<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-10T01:29:17.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@brakebill.me]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Outshape]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/09/outshape/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/09/outshape/</id>
    <published>2015-04-10T01:29:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-10T01:29:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who don’t know, I’ve been spending most of my time since I left ESPN working on a game called <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape" target="_blank" rel="external">Outshape</a>. I’m getting super close to being ready to submit to the App Store. I’m just trying to iterate the design and interaction to as close to perfection as I can get it, while I smooth out some functional edges. It’s the most fun I’ve had in years. And I’m delighted to be able to work hard without having to work all night.</p>
<p>I’ve started a <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/blog" target="_blank" rel="external">blog</a> where I’m going to document the development process of Outshape. From the inspiration, to early mocks, to the stresses of sharing a thing I’m making with the world. I’m sure some of that will come over here, but I’m going to post anything Outshape specific over there.</p>
<p>So go sign up for the email list if you want to get the details on how Outshape came to be!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>For those of you who don’t know, I’ve been spending most of my time since I left ESPN working on a game called <a href="http://onehundred]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Introvert]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/08/introvert/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/08/introvert/</id>
    <published>2015-04-08T23:28:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-08T23:28:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>My thoughts are my thoughts. I share what I choose to, and the rest is mine. Don’t quiz me, demand to know what I’m thinking, tell me I’m meant to share. I have a right to privacy. Don’t assume that because you want to share everything with me, that I should want to share everything with you. Don’t present your view of the world as the only possible option, and that I must be somehow emotionally stunted, wrong, or hiding something.</p>
<p>If I haven’t told you how I feel about something, it’s probably because I haven’t decided how I feel about it. I can’t make decisions without all the information, and I don’t offer solutions without understanding the problem.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want to get into the mind of an introvert, this short piece will get you there.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>My thoughts are my thoughts. I share what I choose to, and the rest is mine. Don’t quiz me, demand to know what I’m thinking]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[iPhone Sixes]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/07/iphone-sixes/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/07/iphone-sixes/</id>
    <published>2015-04-07T20:06:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-07T20:06:37.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been interesting to read <a href="http://www.512pixels.net/blog/2015/4/well-i-switched-to-the-iphone-6-plus" target="_blank" rel="external">Stephen Hackett</a>, <a href="http://www.marco.org/2015/04/06/life-with-the-iphone-6-plus" target="_blank" rel="external">Marco Arment</a> and <a href="http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/04/two-weeks-with-the-iphone-6-plus/" target="_blank" rel="external">Jason Snell</a> talk about their experiences as regular iPhone 6 users who are experimenting with or switching to the iPhone 6 Plus. Particularly since I’ve been a 6 Plus user who is switching to the regular ol’ iPhone 6. </p>
<p>I don’t want to comment on their opinions much, since I don’t have my iPhone 6 yet and I don’t yet know how it works for me. My reason for switching boils down mostly to the fact that the 6 Plus is just too big. I may find that the 6 is too big in day to day usage as well. But I’m most worried about the drop in battery life. I got used to almost never having to think about the battery on my 6 Plus.</p>
<p>I will definitely follow up with my experiences with the iPhone 6 when I receive it.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>It’s been interesting to read <a href="http://www.512pixels.net/blog/2015/4/well-i-switched-to-the-iphone-6-plus" target="_blank" rel="ex]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Introverts as Leaders]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/06/introverts-as-leaders/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/06/introverts-as-leaders/</id>
    <published>2015-04-06T19:20:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-06T19:20:48.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Introverts are professional listeners. Their natural state is to observe and gather data from the world around them as opposed to their extroverts counterparts who enjoying spending their time talking about the state of the world and all the fascinating data in the world… endlessly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All to often, society says that introversion is bad and extroversion is the “proper” or “successful” way to be. This seems to be a more common thought when it comes to leadership. Rands points out that introverts have some pretty huge natural advantages when it comes to good leadership, just as extroverts do. Both most overcome their own weaknesses to make use of their strengths.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Introverts are professional listeners. Their natural state is to observe and gather data from the world around them as oppos]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Pixar]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/03/pixar/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/03/pixar/</id>
    <published>2015-04-03T18:25:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-03T18:25:39.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the process of job hunting for life after ESPN, I managed to land some early interviews with Pixar. While technically it would still be under the umbrella of the same company (Disney), Pixar is sort of <em>that</em> company for me. I love everything they do and want badly to be a part of creating beautifully told stories.</p>
<p>But as we were going through that process my wife and I struggled with the fact that going to Pixar meant moving to California. We’ve been planning on moving to Knoxville for quite a while, and we just weren’t sure San Francisco is where we wanted to live. </p>
<p>Then things changed. We found out we were going to have our first child. I still badly wanted the job with Pixar, but the decision was no longer a struggle. We want to raise children surrounded by family and friends. We weren’t going to move to San Francisco. It hurt badly and it was one of the hardest things I’ve ever had to do, but I had to tell them I wouldn’t be going any further in the interview process. </p>
<p>I had friends say I should have kept going through the process, but that just felt wrong to me. Yes it’s good experience, but in my option it’s selfish to waste the time of hard working people when I know I’m not going to take a job offer. I think it would have shown a lack of respect for the people I was interviewing with.</p>
<p>I’d be lying if I said I didn’t think about it every day and feel a little sad, but I think a lot more every day about that baby and how excited I am to raise him or her around my family and friends.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In the process of job hunting for life after ESPN, I managed to land some early interviews with Pixar. While technically it would still b]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How to take a day off]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/02/how-to-take-a-day-off/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/02/how-to-take-a-day-off/</id>
    <published>2015-04-02T19:25:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-02T19:37:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The biggest difference between that day and a normal weekend day, I realize now, was that I paid little attention to the advance of time. I suspended all aspirations to shaping the future. The only goal was to enjoy the setting and characters of every moment I found myself in, which is refreshingly easy when you’re not trying to get anywhere else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is so incredibly true for me. So often I’m busying my self with the advance of time. Always thinking about how I could be using the upcoming time productively. Or getting frustrated because the time has flown by and I haven’t used it “well”.</p>
<p>Cain provides some great tips on how to take a proper day off. Working some of these into my life will help make me leisure time more enjoyable, and I’m betting will make me a little more fun to be around.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The biggest difference between that day and a normal weekend day, I realize now, was that I paid little attention to the adv]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Munchkin]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/01/pregnant/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/04/01/pregnant/</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T18:53:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-01T18:53:39.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year, when Lauren and I found out we were pregnant I was like 75% scared and 25% excited. We had no plans to have a baby yet. But there we were, expecting one. I’m not sure it’s something you’re ever <em>ready</em> for. But it’s best to at least be planning for it a little bit. (Apparently I married into a fertile family)</p>
<p>When we lost the baby, it was so early in the pregnancy I had a hard time connecting with it. We we’re scared/excited for a couple of weeks. Then just scared shitless for one more. And then just immensely sad. But through all of that, it was hard to feel it was connected to a child. It was more like this roller coaster of expectation changing that Lauren and I went on. One of the most brutal parts about it, was how it affected us differently. How we could be so far apart on the sad to happy spectrum on an hourly basis. </p>
<p>This year we were more ready. Not like <em>planning</em> ready. But it was at least something we had talked about. I think we’d hoped to get settled into Knoxville before Munchkin (that’s what I’m calling him/her) came along, but it wasn’t devastating to have to adjust to new expectations.</p>
<p>Now here we are, less than six months from bringing a human life into the world. Our future nursery is currently the cats’ bedroom, which basically means a room full of unpacked boxes. I’m unemployed and Lauren is just getting started acquiring clients (If you’re in Knoxville and looking for a counselor or someone to talk to, I <strong>highly</strong> recommend <a href="http://www.ebenezercounseling.com/Brakebill.html" target="_blank" rel="external">her</a>). And we don’t even have a dog yet. I thought for sure we’d have to get a dog before we could have a baby.</p>
<p>Yet, despite all those concerns, I can’t help but feel like we’re way more ready for this than we were a year ago. I’m confident that God will provide the right opportunities for us to support this child. I’m trying hard to not be closed off to the job opportunities my family brings me. And speaking of my family, the idea of raising a child is made a million times easier knowing the support we have here in Knoxville.</p>
<p>I guess what I’m saying is my excited to scared ratio is much more balanced this time. So that’s good right?</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Last year, when Lauren and I found out we were pregnant I was like 75% scared and 25% excited. We had no plans to have a baby yet. But th]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tennessee Hires Rick Barnes]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/31/tennessee-hires-rick-barnes/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/31/tennessee-hires-rick-barnes/</id>
    <published>2015-03-31T17:33:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-31T17:33:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>What do you do if you’re Tennessee athletic director Dave Hart and a coach who has won 70 percent of his career games, has made more NCAA Tournament appearances (22) than the Vols have made in their history (20) and has won everywhere he’s been (George Mason, Providence, Clemson, Texas) drops into your lap?</p>
<p>You hire him, that’s what you do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We all love Bruce Pearl, but it’s pretty clear that Rick Barnes has had a much better career. How can you argue with a coach who has more NCAA Tournament appearances than your entire program?</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>What do you do if you’re Tennessee athletic director Dave Hart and a coach who has won 70 percent of his career games, has m]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[No Dickheads!]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/30/no-dickheads/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/30/no-dickheads/</id>
    <published>2015-03-30T17:13:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-30T17:13:49.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>I believe there is a straight line between how the studio feels, how we as designers treat each other, and the innovative impact of the team.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some really great nuggets in here for creating an effective creative workplace. No dickheads is obvious. But many of their guidelines are under appreciated in today’s workplace. Eating and cooking together, reading fiction, sharing your family with your coworkers and your coworkers with your family. These things can turn where you work into more than just that place you go to earn your living. They cultivate a place where you experience joy and growth. Where your work feeds your soul and your soul feeds your work. And that’s how you get shit done.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>I believe there is a straight line between how the studio feels, how we as designers treat each other, and the innovative im]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Two Years of Marriage]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/23/Two-Years-of-Marriage/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/23/Two-Years-of-Marriage/</id>
    <published>2015-03-23T13:30:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-23T13:30:25.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p><p></p><p></p>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/122937125" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>There’s a lot I could say, but I think this video says it well.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p></p><p></p><p></p>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/122937125" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen=]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Decisions, Decisions]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/19/Decisions,-Decisions/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/19/Decisions,-Decisions/</id>
    <published>2015-03-20T02:33:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-20T02:33:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>We are our first users — we’re using the workflows and environment that we set up for ourselves to make good decisions on behalf of ourselves, our families, our clients, and our users. We know the consequences of decision fatigue and poor choices better than most. We’re never going to eliminate decision fatigue from our own lives, or from anyone else’s, but by changing our own habits and lessening our own decision fatigue, we can make better choices more consistently throughout the day, which leads to a better experience for everyone.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’ve been thinking about decision fatigue lately and how it might affect me. I’m trying to get to the more important things as early in the day as possible.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>We are our first users — we’re using the workflows and environment that we set up for ourselves to make good decisions on be]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Why America's Internet Is So Shitty and Slow]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/18/Why-Americas-Internet-Is-So-Shitty-and-Slow/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/18/Why-Americas-Internet-Is-So-Shitty-and-Slow/</id>
    <published>2015-03-19T02:49:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-19T02:49:42.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really great piece on the fundamentals of the internet and why it sucks in the USA.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Really great piece on the fundamentals of the internet and why it sucks in the USA.</p>
]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Inside The Post-Minecraft Billionaire Life Of Gamer God Markus Persson]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/17/Inside-The-Post-Minecraft-Billionaire-Life-Of-Gamer-God-Markus-Persson/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/17/Inside-The-Post-Minecraft-Billionaire-Life-Of-Gamer-God-Markus-Persson/</id>
    <published>2015-03-17T13:42:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-17T13:42:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>It turns out that the most certain thing this windfall bought him was some heavy soul-searching. The only thing he has learned for sure: He was right to walk away from Minecraft. In explaining his recent decisions, he quotes Leonardo da Vinci: “Art is never finished, only abandoned.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seems to be becoming a depressingly common story. Guy or girl creates something cool or popular. Gets an uncomfortable amount of hate over how they manage it. Checks out. Lucky for Persson it netted him well north of a billion dollars. But no amount of money makes that kind of hate feel any better.</p>
<p>As I think about the small possibility of <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape" target="_blank" rel="external">Outshape</a> being really successful, I do get a little terrified. But my ability to ignore the internet has increased greatly in the past couple of years. I won’t mind if it’s a problem I have to deal with.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>It turns out that the most certain thing this windfall bought him was some heavy soul-searching. The only thing he has learn]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Armory of Thought]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/16/The-Armory-of-Thought/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/16/The-Armory-of-Thought/</id>
    <published>2015-03-16T13:20:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-16T13:20:50.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>It isn’t that the man who thinks positively attracts positive circumstances. It’s that a man who thinks positively sees the positive in all circumstances. Whatever circumstances we are faced with, we have the choice between approaching them from a place of blessedness or a place of misery, to view them as an opportunity for enlightenment and growth or as oppression.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great piece on the value of where you place your thinking. It’s difficult to have right action without first having your thoughts focused on what is right.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>It isn’t that the man who thinks positively attracts positive circumstances. It’s that a man who thinks positively sees the ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Astronomers Watch a Supernova and See Reruns]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/13/Astronomers-Watch-a-Supernova-and-See-Reruns/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/13/Astronomers-Watch-a-Supernova-and-See-Reruns/</id>
    <published>2015-03-13T13:11:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-13T13:11:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The star exploded more than nine billion years ago on the other side of the universe, too far for even the Hubble to see without special help from the cosmos. In this case, however, light rays from the star have been bent and magnified by the gravity of an intervening cluster of galaxies so that multiple images of it appear.</p>
<p>Four of them are arranged in a tight formation known as an Einstein Cross surrounding one of the galaxies in the cluster. Since each light ray follows a different path from the star to here, each image in the cross represents a slightly different moment in the supernova explosion.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The way light, gravity, and time work at this scale is absolutely fascinating and mind bending.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The star exploded more than nine billion years ago on the other side of the universe, too far for even the Hubble to see wit]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[What is Bourbon?]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/12/What-is-Bourbon/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/12/What-is-Bourbon/</id>
    <published>2015-03-13T03:20:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-13T03:20:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The Federal Standards of Identity for Distilled Spirits mandate that anything sold as bourbon must be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Made from a grain mixture (the mash) that is at least 51% corn.</li>
<li>Aged in new, charred oak barrels.</li>
<li>Distilled to no more than 160 proof, or 80% alcohol.</li>
<li>Entered into a barrel for aging at no more than 125 proof, or 62.5% alcohol.</li>
<li>Bottled at 80 proof or more, at least 40% alcohol.</li>
<li>Made in the United States.</li>
</ul>
<p>Notice that, although most bourbon is from Kentucky and it’s known as Kentucky’s whiskey, bourbon doesn’t have to be made in Kentucky at all. It can be made anywhere in the United States. Nevertheless, many bourbons made outside of Kentucky choose not to call themselves bourbon, like Jack Daniels. Jack Daniels is, by definition, a bourbon whiskey, but they market themselves as Tennessee Whiskey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I had always thought that bourbon whiskey had to be made in Kentucky.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The Federal Standards of Identity for Distilled Spirits mandate that anything sold as bourbon must be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Made fro]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[A Matter of Priorities]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/11/A-Matter-of-Priorities/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/11/A-Matter-of-Priorities/</id>
    <published>2015-03-12T02:44:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-12T02:44:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Build more roads and you will induce more traffic. Make it faster to get around, things will spread further out, and people will drive more. Zone for isolation, separation, and car dependence and that is the sort of place we will get. Build a pleasant place for people, and a reason to be there, and we will get people. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>I find myself more and more interested in urban design. Having lived most of my life in Knoxville and Orlando, I’m very used to cities built for cars. But there are parts of each city that are becoming more pedestrian friendly. Those parts are really my favorite places to be.</p>
<p>For me it’s a tough balance. I really want to be in those areas, but I also want to live on a nice big chunk of greenery</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Build more roads and you will induce more traffic. Make it faster to get around, things will spread further out, and people ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Life, Love, and Purpose Down on the Farm]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/10/Life,-Love,-and-Purpose-Down-on-the-Farm/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/10/Life,-Love,-and-Purpose-Down-on-the-Farm/</id>
    <published>2015-03-10T21:07:36.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-10T21:07:36.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great story, beautiful location and home. That’s the kind of spot I want to put my home on.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Great story, beautiful location and home. That’s the kind of spot I want to put my home on.</p>
]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Foolish Crowd]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/09/The-Foolish-Crowd/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/09/The-Foolish-Crowd/</id>
    <published>2015-03-09T21:19:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-09T21:19:07.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Are you willing to be foolish in order to do work that matters? Are you willing to fail? To be honest with others? Are you willing to create something even when life is still messy? Are you willing to take risks? Are you willing to put your work out there even when you’re afraid it might not work? Are you willing to try something different than what everyone else is doing because your gut says “why not”? Are you willing to make space in your schedule so you can show up and create something every day?</p>
<p>In our heart, we say, “Yes!” Then we tell ourselves we’ll start tomorrow.</p>
<p>Most of us want to do work that matters. But most of us don’t want to be foolish. At least, not right now. Or, we’re okay with being foolish so long as it’s calculated, planned out, polished, and then distilled down to the lowest common denominator until it’s so insipid it couldn’t possibly be confused as foolishly original.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It was really appropriate that I read this last night, because it really echoes what I’ve been thinking about for the past few weeks. I’ve been mulling over a job offer as we unpack into our new home. What I really want to do is take the risk and spend a couple month’s working full time on <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape" target="_blank" rel="external">Outshape</a>. But it’s a huge risk. Lauren’s income will be limited until she can get more clients.</p>
<p>It’s not just the financial risk that concerns me, it’s what everyone else thinks. I try so hard to only answer to God and my wife. If someone doesn’t like what I’m doing, then that’s their problem. But it’s hard not to hear family constantly saying “but it’s a job” and feel like it’s what I <em>should</em> do. </p>
<p>I may not have another shot to take this risk. The App Store is a tough place to be successful. I have so many doubts and fears, but I badly want to make a run at it. In a few months I may be desperate for a job, and I’m ready to deal with that if we get there. I haven’t <em>quite</em> made a final decision but I will soon. And regardless I will continue to be open to the right job offer if it comes along. For now, I might just be ready to be foolish.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Are you willing to be foolish in order to do work that matters? Are you willing to fail? To be honest with others? Are you w]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Old House at Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/06/The-Old-House-at-Home/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015/03/06/The-Old-House-at-Home/</id>
    <published>2015-03-06T23:14:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T23:14:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fascinating. I love places like this. I just wish they could be visited without be surrounded by other tourists. I was amazed that it existed as described, until I realized it was a story from 1940.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Fascinating. I love places like this. I just wish they could be visited without be surrounded by other tourists. I was amazed that it exi]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>