<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T02:04:55.780Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[We Have Luxurious Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.gedrap.me/blog/2014/02/27/we-have-luxurious-jobs-but-we-are-not-aware-of-it/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/03/our-jobs-are-luxurious/</id>
    <published>2014-03-04T01:59:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-04T01:59:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Posts about annoying, spammy recruiters and just not feeling like working, when working from home, are popular and regular on HackerNews, /r/programming. And I won’t deny, I do often agree on those topics.</p>
<p>The other day, I realised how messed up that is.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sometimes I forget how lucky I am to be in the profession I&#39;m in with the skills I have.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Please Don't Push Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://david-smith.org/blog/2014/02/28/please-dont-push-me/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/03/please-dont-push-me/</id>
    <published>2014-03-04T01:59:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-04T01:59:15.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>I have just sorted through the App Store and settled on trying out your app. I open it up and you immediately ask if you can send me Push Notifications? I have no context about what these are going to be used for or why they might be useful to me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I recently got similar advice about my iPhone game. I&#39;d never really thought twice about asking immediately, but it really is an annoying experience. I&#39;m looking for a better time to ask for this than at launch. Possibly when you make your first move. I might even follow David&#39;s advice and make it something you explicitly enable.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Effective Way to Ask for an App Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2014/02/27/castro-rate-this-app"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/27/the-effective-way-to-ask-for-an-app-review/</id>
    <published>2014-02-28T03:33:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-28T03:33:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Supertop, makers of <a href="http://castro.fm/" target="_blank">Castro</a>, have been experimenting with prompting users to review the app in the release notes. And it&#39;s worked.</p>
<p>I have to admit I&#39;m surprised by this. I&#39;d expect few people see the release notes because of auto updating, and even fewer read them. Maybe it&#39;s more than I expect or maybe a high percentage of those who read them appreciate that prompt and leave a review.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reader Supported]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/shawn-blanc/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/shawn-blanc/</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T22:38:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T22:38:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shawn Blanc is doing is annual membership drive. For just $4/mo you can support his writing and get members only access to his Shawn Today podcast. His writing is <em>absolutely</em> worth supporting and I&#39;m a happy paying member. I don&#39;t know him personally, but I&#39;d like to as he seems like an awesome dude.</p>
<p>If you read him, bump yourself up to membership level. If you don&#39;t, start now and I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll be a member by the next drive.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Roderick On the Line 98: A Mastiff of Spinach]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/roderick-on-the-line-98-a-mastiff-of-spinach/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/roderick-on-the-line-98-a-mastiff-of-spinach/</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T14:19:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T14:19:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Roderick&#39;s account of his trip to a Miley Cyrus concert is both hilarious and interesting.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[After Years Away, Repentant Bruce Pearl Could Be Jewel for Tennessee]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/bruce-pearl/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/bruce-pearl/</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T21:55:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-25T21:55:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gregg Doyel:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If Tennessee has an opening, it should hire Bruce Pearl. Go ahead, Tennessee. He paid his price. You paid yours. Bruce Pearl is a good coach who made a bad mistake and had to be fired -- I was calling for his dismissal months before Tennessee finally did it -- but who served his time and surely, surely learned from his mistake.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I think Bruce Pearl knew, regretted, and learned from his mistake <strong>way</strong> before he was fired. Still, my biggest concern is him lying about something so inconsequential.  I&#39;m terrified that some other larger violation spurred him to cover up the visit to his home.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Here on the outside, the opinion is this: If Tennessee decides [Cuonzo] Martin isn&#39;t the right guy and is looking for a new coach in a month or so, the perfect coach to hire -- not a good coach, but the perfect coach -- still lives in the area and bleeds orange and calls the Volunteers &quot;we.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the end, I 100% agree with this. The weird thing about this is it almost felt inevitable three years ago. And as Bruce has stuck around Knoxville and continued to be so loved in the commmunity, it has felt more and more inevitable. Cuonzo Martin needed to win big to make people forget about Bruce and he hasn&#39;t done that. Three years of teams that have underachieved, played a boring brand of basketball, and lost just enough games to bad teams to keep them out of the dance have made people in Knoxville impatient.</p>
<p>Bruce Pearl should be Tennessee&#39;s basketball coach. Given Cuonzo&#39;s quiet nature, it almost feels like he never left.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Harold Ramis]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/harold-ramis/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/harold-ramis/</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T14:33:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-25T14:33:00.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Harold Ramis <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/25/movies/harold-ramis-who-helped-redefine-what-makes-us-laugh-on-screen-dies-at-69.html?_r=0" target="_blank">passed away</a> yesterday at the age of 69. </p>
<p>Most people will talk about Groundhog Day, Ghostbusters, and Caddyshack, but I will always remember him for <a href="http://youtu.be/xR9HuRUUTbs" target="_blank">Stripes</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Comcast hearts Netflix]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/23/comcast-hearts-netflix/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/23/comcast-hearts-netflix/</id>
    <published>2014-02-23T20:36:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-23T21:00:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Comcast:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Working collaboratively over many months, the companies have established a more direct connection between Netflix and Comcast, similar to other networks, that’s already delivering an even better user experience to consumers, while also allowing for future growth in Netflix traffic. Netflix receives no preferential network treatment under the multi-year agreement, terms of which are not being disclosed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On one hand it just sounds like a sort of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peering" target="_blank">peering agreement</a> between the two companies (if we can trust the bit about &quot;no preferential treatment&quot;), but on the other it sounds sinister and frightening in regards to net neutrality. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s time to say the sky is falling as long as smaller companies can get fair network treatment. But gosh it makes me feel icky. </p>
<p>I think there is something to be said for Netflix being a bit of a special case. It is responsible for a <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57611722-93/netflix-youtube-gobble-up-half-of-internet-traffic/" target="_blank">huge amount</a> of internet traffic.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[A Change]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/22/a-change/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/22/a-change/</id>
    <published>2014-02-23T01:07:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-23T04:04:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve long wanted to do more with this blog. Having it on Tumblr has been fun, but it hasn&#39;t given me the control over my site and data like I want. It also hasn&#39;t lent itself to <strong>really</strong> writing.</p>
<p>So I&#39;ve hit the reset button. I wanted to import all of my Tumblr posts here, but the value I would get out of having old posts wasn&#39;t worth the time I&#39;d have to invest to write up the scripts I needed.</p>
<p>I&#39;ve built my site using the static site generator <a href="http://zespia.tw/hexo/" target="_blank">hexo</a>. I looked at a couple of options, including <a href="http://jekyllrb.com" target="_blank">Jekyll</a> and <a href="http://wintersmith.io" target="_blank">Wintersmith</a>. But hexo gave me the node javascript environment I was looking for with easy deployment to Github pages. It also has a nice plugin framework should I ever need it.</p>
<p>Now I can write in whatever environment feels comfortable, save the markdown file to the proper Dropbox folder, and deploy to the site. I&#39;m hoping this will spur me to write more. About tech. About life. About the things I&#39;m working on. I hope to expand the site to have some places to share the writers I&#39;m reading, the tools I&#39;m using, and more.</p>
<p>All feedback is welcome to my many social networking accounts or, via email, at imchrisbrakebill AT icloud DOT com.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
