<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-18T01:18:17.160Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[NCAA bracket predictions 2014: Choosing the winners by alphabetical order]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sbnation.com/2014/3/17/5517718/ncaa-bracket-predictions-2014-alphabet-picks"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/17/ncaa-bracket-predictions-2014-choosing-the-winners-by-alphabetical-order/</id>
    <published>2014-03-18T01:14:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-18T01:14:18.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Jon Bois:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>(15) American over (2) Wisconsin</p>
<p>This is an easy one. It wouldn&#39;t be appropriate to call this an &quot;upset,&quot; really, since a) the committee that assigned the seeding of this tournament abided by a set of criteria completely unlike mine, and b) it&#39;s rather easy, from the outset, to take a glance at a matchup and immediately determine which ranks higher alphabetically.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[OneNote for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/microsoft-onenote/id784801555?mt=12&affC=QQAJAAAACwAhyZ4GMTFsN2phAAAAAC7HHxM%253D"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/17/onenote-for-mac/</id>
    <published>2014-03-18T01:06:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-18T01:06:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I would have been so excited about this 4 years ago. Now it&#39;s just too little too late. I always preferred the OneNote editor to the Evernote version, but I&#39;m way too invested in Evernote to look back now. It&#39;s where I save everything I want to be able to search for later. I stopped wasting my time labeling emails and being tied to Gmail when I realized I could just save anything I wanted to keep to Evernote and have offline access to it whenever I needed.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Empathy]]></title>
    <link href="http://nshipster.com/empathy/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/17/empathy/</id>
    <published>2014-03-17T15:22:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-18T01:17:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p class="link_author">Mattt Thompson:</p></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We naturally want to help one another, to explain ideas, to be generous and patient. However, on the Internet, human nature seems to drop a few packets. Practicing empathy online becomes a feat of moral athleticism. Lacking many of the faculties to humanize and understand one another (facial expressions, voice tonality, non-verbal cues) we can lose sight of who we&#39;re talking to, and become less human ourselves.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Preach. We could all stand to be a little more empathetic on the internet, myself more than anyone.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Art of the Title: Lego Movie]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.artofthetitle.com/title/the-lego-movie/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/17/art-of-the-title-lego-movie/</id>
    <published>2014-03-17T13:25:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-17T13:25:03.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great look into the awesome ending credits sequence for the Lego Movie. The entire thing was done in stop motion which is mind blowing. I was amazed when I saw it in the theater, and I just assumed it was CGI.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[My Morning Routine]]></title>
    <link href="http://mymorningroutine.com/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/15/my-morning-routine/</id>
    <published>2014-03-15T16:11:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-15T16:11:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;m really loving this site. Really simple. They just ask people a few questions about their morning routine.</p>
<p>Morning is by far my favorite part of the day, so I love learning how other people get their days started.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Telecom Giants Drag Their Feet on Broadband for the Whole Country]]></title>
    <link href="http://mag.newsweek.com/2014/03/21/telecom-giants-drag-feet-broadband-whole-country.html"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/15/telecom-giants-drag-their-feet-on-broadband-for-the-whole-country/</id>
    <published>2014-03-15T15:51:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-15T15:51:06.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>In 2010, the Federal Communications Commission announced the National Broadband Plan, which promised to provide 100 million American households with high-speed cable by 2020. Verizon has been expanding FiOS in major markets, and AT&amp;T has been expanding its U-verse service. And now, instead of spending that war chest digging up streets and laying fiber cable, the cable and telephone companies have invested in a massive and very successful lobbying push. They are persuading state legislatures and regulatory boards to quietly adopt new rules—rules written by the telecoms—to eliminate their legal obligations to provide broadband service nationwide and replace landlines with wireless. This abrupt change in plans will leave vast areas of the country with poor service, slow telecommunications and higher bills.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is just messed up. More bad news for the internet.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[On the Taxation of College Sports]]></title>
    <link href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/post/78566416769"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/10/on-the-taxation-of-college-sports/</id>
    <published>2014-03-10T13:32:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-10T13:32:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sportsgeekonomics tears down another argument against paying college athletes. This time it&#39;s the concern that athletic department income will become taxable and schools might lose their nonprofit status.</p>
<p>You hear that Mr. Andersen? That&#39;s the sound of inevitability.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Internet is Fucked]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/2/25/5431382/the-internet-is-fucked"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/10/the-internet-is-fucked/</id>
    <published>2014-03-10T13:07:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-10T13:07:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nilay Patel: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>What happens in countries where there’s real competition? In the UK, where incumbent provider BT is required to allow competitors to use its wired broadband network, home internet service prices are as low as £2.50 a month, or just over $4. In South Korea, where wireless giants SK Telecom and LG Uplus are locked in a fierce technology battle, customers have access to the fastest mobile networks in the world — up to 300Mbps, compared to a theoretical max of 80Mbps on Verizon that’s actually more like 15 or 20mbps in the real world.</p>
<p>And Americans pay more for these slower wireless speeds than anyone else in the world: in Germany, where customers can freely switch between carriers by swapping SIM cards, T-Mobile customers pay just $1.18 per Mbps of speed. In the US, our mostly incompatible wireless networks lock customers in with expensive handsets they can’t take elsewhere, allowing AT&amp;T and Verizon to charge around $4 per Mbps each and Sprint to clock in at an insane $7.50.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Those two paragraphs are so depressing to me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So there’s the entire problem, expressed in four simple ideas: the internet is a utility, there is zero meaningful competition to provide that utility to Americans, all internet providers should be treated equally, and the FCC is doing a miserably ineffective job. The United States should lead the world in broadband deployment and speeds: we should have the lowest prices, the best service, and the most competition. We should have the freest speech and the loudest voices, the best debate and the soundest policy. We are home to the most innovative technology companies in the world, and we should have the broadband networks to match.</p>
<p>We should stop fucking it up.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want to do something, email the FCC chair at tom.wheeler@fcc.com and call 1-888-225-5322. Calls to your <a href="http://www.house.gov/representatives/find/" target="_blank">representatives</a> and <a href="http://www.senate.gov/general/contact_information/senators_cfm.cfm" target="_blank">senators</a> are always good too.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[P.S. Hoffman (A Tribute)]]></title>
    <link href="http://vimeo.com/87873042"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/05/ps-hoffman-a-tribute/</id>
    <published>2014-03-06T03:54:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-06T03:54:50.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A tribute to Philip Seymour Hoffman. Incredibly well done.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Say Something]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0dYlvdLdK9w"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/04/say-something/</id>
    <published>2014-03-05T04:20:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T04:20:13.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Or stop talking and watch this video.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[CarPlay Powered by Blackberry]]></title>
    <link href="http://bgr.com/2014/03/04/apple-carplay-blackberry-qnx/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/04/carplay-powered-by-blackberry/</id>
    <published>2014-03-05T04:15:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T04:15:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">BGR:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>BlackBerry’s QNX platform is the base on which the BlackBerry 10 operating system is built, but it’s also much more than that. Before it was morphed into smartphone software, QNX was an in-car operating system that powered infotainment systems in a wide range of vehicles. It still is, and as N4BB confirmed on Tuesday, it’s also the foundation for Apple’s new CarPlay product.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Amazing that the value for QNX may not come from Blackberry mobile devices, but from being the go to in-car operating system. Add this onto news that Ford Sync is <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-22/ford-said-to-swap-blackberry-s-qnx-for-microsoft-in-sync-system.html" target="_blank">planning to drop</a> Microsoft for QNX, and it looks like Blackberry is building itself a nice little niche, though I&#39;m not sure how profitable it is.</p>
<p>I never would have believed this a year or so ago, but is it possible that Blackberry could become an acquisition target for Apple?</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[CarPlay]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/ios/carplay/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/04/carplay/</id>
    <published>2014-03-05T04:14:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T04:14:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Apple <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/03/03Apple-Rolls-Out-CarPlay-Giving-Drivers-a-Smarter-Safer-More-Fun-Way-to-Use-iPhone-in-the-Car.html" target="_blank">introduced</a> CarPlay, their solution for connecting your iPhone to your vehicle&#39;s stereo.</p>
<p>My first thought is damn that UI is beautiful. As someone who recently bought an aftermarket stereo, I can say that the makers of these things are stuck in the 90s when it comes to interface design. Even on touch screens the buttons are small, the designs are hideous, and UX is an afterthought. It will be interesting to see if this platform moves beyond built-in stereos.</p>
<p>I&#39;m thrilled that Apple is starting to dip it&#39;s toes into this space. I&#39;ve always been a bit bearish on the phone as the hub for the car stereo, but I&#39;m starting to rethink that.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[We Have Luxurious Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.gedrap.me/blog/2014/02/27/we-have-luxurious-jobs-but-we-are-not-aware-of-it/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/03/our-jobs-are-luxurious/</id>
    <published>2014-03-04T01:59:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T04:09:38.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Gediminas Rapolavicius:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Posts about annoying, spammy recruiters and just not feeling like working, when working from home, are popular and regular on HackerNews, /r/programming. And I won’t deny, I do often agree on those topics.</p>
<p>The other day, I realised how messed up that is.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sometimes I forget how lucky I am to be in the profession I&#39;m in with the skills I have.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Please Don't Push Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://david-smith.org/blog/2014/02/28/please-dont-push-me/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/03/03/please-dont-push-me/</id>
    <published>2014-03-04T01:59:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T04:09:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">David Smith:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I have just sorted through the App Store and settled on trying out your app. I open it up and you immediately ask if you can send me Push Notifications? I have no context about what these are going to be used for or why they might be useful to me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I recently got similar advice about my iPhone game. I&#39;d never really thought twice about asking immediately, but it really is an annoying experience. I&#39;m looking for a better time to ask for this than at launch. Possibly when you make your first move. I might even follow David&#39;s advice and make it something you explicitly enable.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Effective Way to Ask for an App Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.supertop.co/post/77962740329/the-effective-way-to-ask-for-an-app-review"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/27/the-effective-way-to-ask-for-an-app-review/</id>
    <published>2014-02-28T03:33:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-28T03:33:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Supertop, makers of <a href="http://castro.fm/" target="_blank">Castro</a>, have been experimenting with prompting users to review the app in the release notes. And it&#39;s worked.</p>
<p>I have to admit I&#39;m surprised by this. I&#39;d expect few people see the release notes because of auto updating, and even fewer read them. Maybe it&#39;s more than I expect or maybe a high percentage of those who read them appreciate that prompt and leave a review.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reader Supported]]></title>
    <link href="http://shawnblanc.net/2014/02/reader-supported/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/shawn-blanc/</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T22:38:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T22:38:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shawn Blanc is doing is annual membership drive. For just $4/mo you can support his writing and get members only access to his Shawn Today podcast. His writing is <em>absolutely</em> worth supporting and I&#39;m a happy paying member. I don&#39;t know him personally, but I&#39;d like to as he seems like an awesome dude.</p>
<p>If you read him, bump yourself up to membership level. If you don&#39;t, start now and I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll be a member by the next drive.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Roderick On the Line 98: A Mastiff of Spinach]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.merlinmann.com/roderick/ep-98-a-mastiff-of-spinach.html"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/26/roderick-on-the-line-98-a-mastiff-of-spinach/</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T14:19:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T14:19:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Roderick&#39;s account of his trip to a Miley Cyrus concert is both hilarious and interesting.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[After Years Away, Repentant Bruce Pearl Could Be Jewel for Tennessee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cbssports.com/general/writer/gregg-doyel/24456460/after-years-away-repentant-bruce-pearl-could-be-jewel-for-tennessee"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/bruce-pearl/</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T21:55:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-25T21:55:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gregg Doyel:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If Tennessee has an opening, it should hire Bruce Pearl. Go ahead, Tennessee. He paid his price. You paid yours. Bruce Pearl is a good coach who made a bad mistake and had to be fired -- I was calling for his dismissal months before Tennessee finally did it -- but who served his time and surely, surely learned from his mistake.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I think Bruce Pearl knew, regretted, and learned from his mistake <strong>way</strong> before he was fired. Still, my biggest concern is him lying about something so inconsequential.  I&#39;m terrified that some other larger violation spurred him to cover up the visit to his home.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Here on the outside, the opinion is this: If Tennessee decides [Cuonzo] Martin isn&#39;t the right guy and is looking for a new coach in a month or so, the perfect coach to hire -- not a good coach, but the perfect coach -- still lives in the area and bleeds orange and calls the Volunteers &quot;we.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the end, I 100% agree with this. The weird thing about this is it almost felt inevitable three years ago. And as Bruce has stuck around Knoxville and continued to be so loved in the commmunity, it has felt more and more inevitable. Cuonzo Martin needed to win big to make people forget about Bruce and he hasn&#39;t done that. Three years of teams that have underachieved, played a boring brand of basketball, and lost just enough games to bad teams to keep them out of the dance have made people in Knoxville impatient.</p>
<p>Bruce Pearl should be Tennessee&#39;s basketball coach. Given Cuonzo&#39;s quiet nature, it almost feels like he never left.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Harold Ramis]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/harold-ramis/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/harold-ramis/</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T14:33:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-25T14:33:00.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Harold Ramis <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/25/movies/harold-ramis-who-helped-redefine-what-makes-us-laugh-on-screen-dies-at-69.html?_r=0" target="_blank">passed away</a> yesterday at the age of 69. </p>
<p>Most people will talk about Groundhog Day, Ghostbusters, and Caddyshack, but I will always remember him for <a href="http://youtu.be/xR9HuRUUTbs" target="_blank">Stripes</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Comcast hearts Netflix]]></title>
    <link href="http://corporate.comcast.com/news-information/news-feed/comcast-and-netflix"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/23/comcast-hearts-netflix/</id>
    <published>2014-02-23T20:36:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-23T21:00:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Comcast:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Working collaboratively over many months, the companies have established a more direct connection between Netflix and Comcast, similar to other networks, that’s already delivering an even better user experience to consumers, while also allowing for future growth in Netflix traffic. Netflix receives no preferential network treatment under the multi-year agreement, terms of which are not being disclosed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On one hand it just sounds like a sort of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peering" target="_blank">peering agreement</a> between the two companies (if we can trust the bit about &quot;no preferential treatment&quot;), but on the other it sounds sinister and frightening in regards to net neutrality. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s time to say the sky is falling as long as smaller companies can get fair network treatment. But gosh it makes me feel icky. </p>
<p>I think there is something to be said for Netflix being a bit of a special case. It is responsible for a <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57611722-93/netflix-youtube-gobble-up-half-of-internet-traffic/" target="_blank">huge amount</a> of internet traffic.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
