<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T21:01:01.497Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Comcast hearts Netflix]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/23/comcast-hearts-netflix/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/23/comcast-hearts-netflix/</id>
    <published>2014-02-23T20:36:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-23T21:00:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Comcast:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Working collaboratively over many months, the companies have established a more direct connection between Netflix and Comcast, similar to other networks, that’s already delivering an even better user experience to consumers, while also allowing for future growth in Netflix traffic. Netflix receives no preferential network treatment under the multi-year agreement, terms of which are not being disclosed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On one hand it just sounds like a sort of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peering" target="_blank">peering agreement</a> between the two companies (if we can trust the bit about &quot;no preferential treatment&quot;), but on the other it sounds sinister and frightening in regards to net neutrality. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s time to say the sky is falling as long as smaller companies can get fair network treatment. But gosh it makes me feel icky. </p>
<p>I think there is something to be said for Netflix being a bit of a special case. It is responsible for a <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57611722-93/netflix-youtube-gobble-up-half-of-internet-traffic/" target="_blank">huge amount</a> of internet traffic.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[A Change]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/22/a-change/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/22/a-change/</id>
    <published>2014-02-23T01:07:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-23T04:04:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve long wanted to do more with this blog. Having it on Tumblr has been fun, but it hasn&#39;t given me the control over my site and data like I want. It also hasn&#39;t lent itself to <strong>really</strong> writing.</p>
<p>So I&#39;ve hit the reset button. I wanted to import all of my Tumblr posts here, but the value I would get out of having old posts wasn&#39;t worth the time I&#39;d have to invest to write up the scripts I needed.</p>
<p>I&#39;ve built my site using the static site generator <a href="http://zespia.tw/hexo/" target="_blank">hexo</a>. I looked at a couple of options, including <a href="http://jekyllrb.com" target="_blank">Jekyll</a> and <a href="http://wintersmith.io" target="_blank">Wintersmith</a>. But hexo gave me the node javascript environment I was looking for with easy deployment to Github pages. It also has a nice plugin framework should I ever need it.</p>
<p>Now I can write in whatever environment feels comfortable, save the markdown file to the proper Dropbox folder, and deploy to the site. I&#39;m hoping this will spur me to write more. About tech. About life. About the things I&#39;m working on. I hope to expand the site to have some places to share the writers I&#39;m reading, the tools I&#39;m using, and more.</p>
<p>All feedback is welcome to my many social networking accounts or, via email, at imchrisbrakebill AT icloud DOT com.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
