<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2014-11-26:/20141126155001988</id><title>Chris Brakebill</title><updated>2015-05-22T17:06:00.520Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><generator version="0.4.0" uri="https://github.com/jebrosen/pub-atom">pub-atom</generator><subtitle type="text">Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast. Sender of Three Things Weekly.</subtitle><entry><id>961895053</id><title>3+ years of local milk</title><updated>2015-05-07T22:52:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beth Kirby’s blog might be my favorite thing on the internet. I think I come for the recipes and photography, but I stay because it’s like sitting down with an intimate friend for coffee by a fireplace. It’s not about perfection, but comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3054827246</id><title>What College Stars Can Learn From NFL Players Ditching Millions to Retire Early</title><updated>2015-04-21T17:17:56.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For years, I have preached the same message to successful products of the NFL’s farm system: Leave as quickly as you can if there’s a living to be made or even if you’re on the cusp of making one. Playing football for the price of a degree is not a worthwhile trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much truth in here. I’ve spent too much time thinking oh this or that guy could have improved their draft stock by staying in school. But it’s crap. Many of these guys are tremendously under compensated for their skills and sacrifice. Once your skills are at all desired in the NFL, I say go and finish that degree later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly I’m just glad to see that more players are starting to say no to the millions of dollars to focus on life outside of football. Get what you can get. Quit while you’re ahead. Budget wisely. Don’t destroy the rest of your life for a few more years in the spotlight making millions.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>143033039</id><title>Poor Internet for Poor People</title><updated>2015-04-20T18:19:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s how the scheme works. Facebook approaches a telco—in India’s case, Reliance—and offers to pay them the bandwidth costs of serving Facebook site and a small group of other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;So when the poor, who in theory can’t afford a net connection come to the Facebook Zero service confusingly called Internet.org, they’re made to believe they’re on the internet while in reality they’re only on Facebook and a few hand-picked sites.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;And the sites too are picked in secret under some unknown process. For instance, Facebook chose to offer the distant-second search engine Bing instead of industry-leading Google. Why? Is it rivalry with Google? Or because of Microsoft’s stake in Facebook? And then Facebook’s Zero product features a tiny job site like Babajob instead of the industry-leading Naukri. Why? So that the poor have fewer job options? No one knows. Facebook doesn’t feature YouTube—the largest video site in the world and an immense education resource —but allows its own videos in full. It doesn’t really look like charity any more, does it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While zero services are a more extreme case and don’t fit what you will see in the U.S., they are helpful in illustrating how the seemingly good idea of certain companies’ products not counting towards your data caps is actually bad for the internet. You’re no longer choosing between product X and product Y. It’s now product X, which won’t count towards you cap, and product Y, which may be a superior product but can’t afford to pay off your internet provider. Your cell phone company or ISP shouldn’t get to make this decision. They should simply give you uniform access to sites on the internet and charge you according to that usage, no matter where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>397203744</id><title>Life sans iPhone</title><updated>2015-04-15T11:15:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t know, I’d been looking to trade my iPhone 6+ in for an iPhone 6. I was recently able to sell my 6+ on Glyde. Since my last sale fell through, I decided to wait this time until I had the money before buying a new phone. Some crazy slow shipping times, combined with a seller who didn’t seem to want to part with their iPhone 6 left me without a smartphone for about 3 weeks. I feel like the experience of having a phone which was only for calling has been really informative of my habits. (Okay it could text, but have you tried texting without a full keyboard? It’s horrific).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/oldPhone.jpg" alt="My awesome Alcatel temp phone" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became apparent very quickly how habitual looking at my phone was. I would frequently look at my little candy bar for no reason at all. I needed a fix of stimulation that whatever situation I was currently in just couldn’t give me. Or so it seemed. As time went by, I found myself leaving my phone behind even as I went out to do things. I missed the occasional text or call, but for the most part being disconnected was a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I find interesting now is looking at my apps and thinking about how many of them I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; on my phone. I’m pretty sure I can count on one hand the number of times I really needed an iPhone app for something. (One of those times was when I had to print out Google Maps directions and got lost. It felt like 2002 all over again). Most of the time I looked at my phone out of boredom or being stuck in unpleasant social situations (or both).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the most revealing thing has been the past 48 hours of having an iPhone back in my life. I’d been anticipating getting it back for weeks. I think somewhere deep down I thought getting one back would make life so much easier or more pleasant or at least I’ll know the scores of every current SPORTING EVENT. But I’ve become a lot more conscious of my motivations every time I take a peek at it. And I’m finding myself putting it away because I really have nothing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, is this experience going to change my life? Probably not. But at the very least it’s got me being a little bit more intentional about how I use my phone. I’m going to pare down the number of apps I keep on it and try to not feel like I need it everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1780376833</id><title>Decorating with Post-It Notes</title><updated>2015-04-13T17:07:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One day I just got so tired of how sterile and boring our office felt, I thought I should do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic way to bring life to a space affordably and ephemerally.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3529390697</id><title>Outshape</title><updated>2015-04-09T21:29:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know, I’ve been spending most of my time since I left ESPN working on a game called &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt;. I’m getting super close to being ready to submit to the App Store. I’m just trying to iterate the design and interaction to as close to perfection as I can get it, while I smooth out some functional edges. It’s the most fun I’ve had in years. And I’m delighted to be able to work hard without having to work all night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started a &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/blog"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; where I’m going to document the development process of Outshape. From the inspiration, to early mocks, to the stresses of sharing a thing I’m making with the world. I’m sure some of that will come over here, but I’m going to post anything Outshape specific over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So go sign up for the email list if you want to get the details on how Outshape came to be!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3044130376</id><title>Introvert</title><updated>2015-04-08T19:28:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My thoughts are my thoughts. I share what I choose to, and the rest is mine. Don't quiz me, demand to know what I'm thinking, tell me I'm meant to share. I have a right to privacy. Don't assume that because you want to share everything with me, that I should want to share everything with you. Don't present your view of the world as the only possible option, and that I must be somehow emotionally stunted, wrong, or hiding something.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;If I haven't told you how I feel about something, it's probably because I haven't decided how I feel about it. I can't make decisions without all the information, and I don't offer solutions without understanding the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get into the mind of an introvert, this short piece will get you there.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2710528683</id><title>iPhone Sixes</title><updated>2015-04-07T16:06:37.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting to read &lt;a href="http://www.512pixels.net/blog/2015/4/well-i-switched-to-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Stephen Hackett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/2015/04/06/life-with-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/04/two-weeks-with-the-iphone-6-plus/"&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; talk about their experiences as regular iPhone 6 users who are experimenting with or switching to the iPhone 6 Plus. Particularly since I’ve been a 6 Plus user who is switching to the regular ol’ iPhone 6. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to comment on their opinions much, since I don’t have my iPhone 6 yet and I don’t yet know how it works for me. My reason for switching boils down mostly to the fact that the 6 Plus is just too big. I may find that the 6 is too big in day to day usage as well. But I’m most worried about the drop in battery life. I got used to almost never having to think about the battery on my 6 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will definitely follow up with my experiences with the iPhone 6 when I receive it.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2225268362</id><title>Introverts as Leaders</title><updated>2015-04-06T15:20:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Introverts are professional listeners. Their natural state is to observe and gather data from the world around them as opposed to their extroverts counterparts who enjoying spending their time talking about the state of the world and all the fascinating data in the world… endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All to often, society says that introversion is bad and extroversion is the “proper” or “successful” way to be. This seems to be a more common thought when it comes to leadership. Rands points out that introverts have some pretty huge natural advantages when it comes to good leadership, just as extroverts do. Both most overcome their own weaknesses to make use of their strengths.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>872418029</id><title>Pixar</title><updated>2015-04-03T14:25:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the process of job hunting for life after ESPN, I managed to land some early interviews with Pixar. While technically it would still be under the umbrella of the same company (Disney), Pixar is sort of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company for me. I love everything they do and want badly to be a part of creating beautifully told stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we were going through that process my wife and I struggled with the fact that going to Pixar meant moving to California. We’ve been planning on moving to Knoxville for quite a while, and we just weren’t sure San Francisco is where we wanted to live. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then things changed. We found out we were going to have our first child. I still badly wanted the job with Pixar, but the decision was no longer a struggle. We want to raise children surrounded by family and friends. We weren’t going to move to San Francisco. It hurt badly and it was one of the hardest things I’ve ever had to do, but I had to tell them I wouldn’t be going any further in the interview process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had friends say I should have kept going through the process, but that just felt wrong to me. Yes it’s good experience, but in my option it’s selfish to waste the time of hard working people when I know I’m not going to take a job offer. I think it would have shown a lack of respect for the people I was interviewing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be lying if I said I didn’t think about it every day and feel a little sad, but I think a lot more every day about that baby and how excited I am to raise him or her around my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>387157708</id><title>How to take a day off</title><updated>2015-04-02T15:25:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between that day and a normal weekend day, I realize now, was that I paid little attention to the advance of time. I suspended all aspirations to shaping the future. The only goal was to enjoy the setting and characters of every moment I found myself in, which is refreshingly easy when you’re not trying to get anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so incredibly true for me. So often I’m busying my self with the advance of time. Always thinking about how I could be using the upcoming time productively. Or getting frustrated because the time has flown by and I haven’t used it “well”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cain provides some great tips on how to take a proper day off. Working some of these into my life will help make me leisure time more enjoyable, and I’m betting will make me a little more fun to be around.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>53556015</id><title>Munchkin</title><updated>2015-04-01T14:53:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year, when Lauren and I found out we were pregnant I was like 75% scared and 25% excited. We had no plans to have a baby yet. But there we were, expecting one. I’m not sure it’s something you’re ever &lt;em&gt;ready&lt;/em&gt; for. But it’s best to at least be planning for it a little bit. (Apparently I married into a fertile family)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we lost the baby, it was so early in the pregnancy I had a hard time connecting with it. We we’re scared/excited for a couple of weeks. Then just scared shitless for one more. And then just immensely sad. But through all of that, it was hard to feel it was connected to a child. It was more like this roller coaster of expectation changing that Lauren and I went on. One of the most brutal parts about it, was how it affected us differently. How we could be so far apart on the sad to happy spectrum on an hourly basis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we were more ready. Not like &lt;em&gt;planning&lt;/em&gt; ready. But it was at least something we had talked about. I think we’d hoped to get settled into Knoxville before Munchkin (that’s what I’m calling him/her) came along, but it wasn’t devastating to have to adjust to new expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here we are, less than six months from bringing a human life into the world. Our future nursery is currently the cats’ bedroom, which basically means a room full of unpacked boxes. I’m unemployed and Lauren is just getting started acquiring clients (If you’re in Knoxville and looking for a counselor or someone to talk to, I &lt;strong&gt;highly&lt;/strong&gt; recommend &lt;a href="http://www.ebenezercounseling.com/Brakebill.html"&gt;her&lt;/a&gt;). And we don’t even have a dog yet. I thought for sure we’d have to get a dog before we could have a baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite all those concerns, I can’t help but feel like we’re way more ready for this than we were a year ago. I’m confident that God will provide the right opportunities for us to support this child. I’m trying hard to not be closed off to the job opportunities my family brings me. And speaking of my family, the idea of raising a child is made a million times easier knowing the support we have here in Knoxville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m saying is my excited to scared ratio is much more balanced this time. So that’s good right?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3863262990</id><title>Tennessee Hires Rick Barnes</title><updated>2015-03-31T13:33:45.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What do you do if you’re Tennessee athletic director Dave Hart and a coach who has won 70 percent of his career games, has made more NCAA Tournament appearances (22) than the Vols have made in their history (20) and has won everywhere he’s been (George Mason, Providence, Clemson, Texas) drops into your lap?&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;You hire him, that’s what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love Bruce Pearl, but it’s pretty clear that Rick Barnes has had a much better career. How can you argue with a coach who has more NCAA Tournament appearances than your entire program?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1690899809</id><title>No Dickheads!</title><updated>2015-03-30T13:13:49.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe there is a straight line between how the studio feels, how we as designers treat each other, and the innovative impact of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some really great nuggets in here for creating an effective creative workplace. No dickheads is obvious. But many of their guidelines are under appreciated in today’s workplace. Eating and cooking together, reading fiction, sharing your family with your coworkers and your coworkers with your family. These things can turn where you work into more than just that place you go to earn your living. They cultivate a place where you experience joy and growth. Where your work feeds your soul and your soul feeds your work. And that’s how you get shit done.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1205639488</id><title>Two Years of Marriage</title><updated>2015-03-23T09:30:25.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/122937125" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot I could say, but I think this video says it well.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>848606799</id><title>Decisions, Decisions</title><updated>2015-03-19T22:33:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are our first users — we’re using the workflows and environment that we set up for ourselves to make good decisions on behalf of ourselves, our families, our clients, and our users. We know the consequences of decision fatigue and poor choices better than most. We’re never going to eliminate decision fatigue from our own lives, or from anyone else’s, but by changing our own habits and lessening our own decision fatigue, we can make better choices more consistently throughout the day, which leads to a better experience for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about decision fatigue lately and how it might affect me. I’m trying to get to the more important things as early in the day as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2305307246</id><title>Why America's Internet Is So Shitty and Slow</title><updated>2015-03-18T22:49:42.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Really great piece on the fundamentals of the internet and why it sucks in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>186007309</id><title>Inside The Post-Minecraft Billionaire Life Of Gamer God Markus Persson</title><updated>2015-03-17T09:42:58.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It turns out that the most certain thing this windfall bought him was some heavy soul-searching. The only thing he has learned for sure: He was right to walk away from Minecraft. In explaining his recent decisions, he quotes Leonardo da Vinci: “Art is never finished, only abandoned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems to be becoming a depressingly common story. Guy or girl creates something cool or popular. Gets an uncomfortable amount of hate over how they manage it. Checks out. Lucky for Persson it netted him well north of a billion dollars. But no amount of money makes that kind of hate feel any better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I think about the small possibility of &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt; being really successful, I do get a little terrified. But my ability to ignore the internet has increased greatly in the past couple of years. I won’t mind if it’s a problem I have to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1642707756</id><title>The Armory of Thought</title><updated>2015-03-16T09:20:50.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It isn’t that the man who thinks positively attracts positive circumstances. It’s that a man who thinks positively sees the positive in all circumstances. Whatever circumstances we are faced with, we have the choice between approaching them from a place of blessedness or a place of misery, to view them as an opportunity for enlightenment and growth or as oppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great piece on the value of where you place your thinking. It’s difficult to have right action without first having your thoughts focused on what is right.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2173535179</id><title>Astronomers Watch a Supernova and See Reruns</title><updated>2015-03-13T09:11:58.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The star exploded more than nine billion years ago on the other side of the universe, too far for even the Hubble to see without special help from the cosmos. In this case, however, light rays from the star have been bent and magnified by the gravity of an intervening cluster of galaxies so that multiple images of it appear.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Four of them are arranged in a tight formation known as an Einstein Cross surrounding one of the galaxies in the cluster. Since each light ray follows a different path from the star to here, each image in the cross represents a slightly different moment in the supernova explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way light, gravity, and time work at this scale is absolutely fascinating and mind bending.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3630235626</id><title>What is Bourbon?</title><updated>2015-03-12T23:20:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Federal Standards of Identity for Distilled Spirits mandate that anything sold as bourbon must be:
  - Made from a grain mixture (the mash) that is at least 51% corn.
  - Aged in new, charred oak barrels.
  - Distilled to no more than 160 proof, or 80% alcohol.
  - Entered into a barrel for aging at no more than 125 proof, or 62.5% alcohol.
  - Bottled at 80 proof or more, at least 40% alcohol.
  - Made in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Notice that, although most bourbon is from Kentucky and it’s known as Kentucky’s whiskey, bourbon doesn’t have to be made in Kentucky at all. It can be made anywhere in the United States. Nevertheless, many bourbons made outside of Kentucky choose not to call themselves bourbon, like Jack Daniels. Jack Daniels is, by definition, a bourbon whiskey, but they market themselves as Tennessee Whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always thought that bourbon whiskey had to be made in Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1510935689</id><title>A Matter of Priorities</title><updated>2015-03-11T22:44:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Build more roads and you will induce more traffic. Make it faster to get around, things will spread further out, and people will drive more. Zone for isolation, separation, and car dependence and that is the sort of place we will get. Build a pleasant place for people, and a reason to be there, and we will get people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find myself more and more interested in urban design. Having lived most of my life in Knoxville and Orlando, I’m very used to cities built for cars. But there are parts of each city that are becoming more pedestrian friendly. Those parts are really my favorite places to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me it’s a tough balance. I really want to be in those areas, but I also want to live on a nice big chunk of greenery&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2967636136</id><title>Life, Love, and Purpose Down on the Farm</title><updated>2015-03-10T17:07:36.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great story, beautiful location and home. That’s the kind of spot I want to put my home on.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1867567943</id><title>The Foolish Crowd</title><updated>2015-03-09T17:19:07.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Are you willing to be foolish in order to do work that matters? Are you willing to fail? To be honest with others? Are you willing to create something even when life is still messy? Are you willing to take risks? Are you willing to put your work out there even when you’re afraid it might not work? Are you willing to try something different than what everyone else is doing because your gut says “why not”? Are you willing to make space in your schedule so you can show up and create something every day?&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In our heart, we say, “Yes!” Then we tell ourselves we’ll start tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Most of us want to do work that matters. But most of us don’t want to be foolish. At least, not right now. Or, we’re okay with being foolish so long as it’s calculated, planned out, polished, and then distilled down to the lowest common denominator until it’s so insipid it couldn’t possibly be confused as foolishly original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really appropriate that I read this last night, because it really echoes what I’ve been thinking about for the past few weeks. I’ve been mulling over a job offer as we unpack into our new home. What I really want to do is take the risk and spend a couple month’s working full time on &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt;. But it’s a huge risk. Lauren’s income will be limited until she can get more clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just the financial risk that concerns me, it’s what everyone else thinks. I try so hard to only answer to God and my wife. If someone doesn’t like what I’m doing, then that’s their problem. But it’s hard not to hear family constantly saying “but it’s a job” and feel like it’s what I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may not have another shot to take this risk. The App Store is a tough place to be successful. I have so many doubts and fears, but I badly want to make a run at it. In a few months I may be desperate for a job, and I’m ready to deal with that if we get there. I haven’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; made a final decision but I will soon. And regardless I will continue to be open to the right job offer if it comes along. For now, I might just be ready to be foolish.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3324268390</id><title>The Old House at Home</title><updated>2015-03-06T18:14:51.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fascinating. I love places like this. I just wish they could be visited without be surrounded by other tourists. I was amazed that it existed as described, until I realized it was a story from 1940.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2064171598</id><title>On Black History Month and Empathy</title><updated>2015-03-02T16:34:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So today, listen to someone else’s story. Ask good questions. Ask hard questions. Attempt to let go of your own perspective for a moment and get lost in someone else’s life that’s different from your own. Empathize. Be a better human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I married a good one.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1808701167</id><title>Last Day</title><updated>2015-02-25T08:59:42.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My last day at ESPN has finally arrived. It’s been a pretty incredible 3+ years for me. I moved from Knoxville to Seattle to Orlando. I’ve gotten married. I got cats...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we move onto the next season of life and I’m filled with both excitement and terror. I’m excited to be moving home to the city that I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; in Knoxville. But I’m taking a little bit of a plunge as I continue to search for the right job while I work on &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt; and keep sending &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/threethings/"&gt;Three Things Weekly&lt;/a&gt;. It is terrifying. But I believe in myself, I have a wife who believes in me, and I trust God and I can’t wait to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1401572108</id><title>Voluntary Simplicity</title><updated>2015-02-24T08:02:42.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Voluntary simplicity, or simple living, is a way of life that rejects the high-consumption, materialistic lifestyles of consumer cultures and affirms what is often just called ‘the simple life’ or ‘downshifting.’ The rejection of consumerism arises from the recognition that ordinary Western-style consumption habits are degrading the planet; that lives of high consumption are unethical in a world of great human need; and that the meaning of life does not and cannot consist in the consumption or accumulation of material things. Extravagance and acquisitiveness are accordingly considered an unfortunate waste of life, certainly not deserving of the social status and admiration they seem to attract today. The affirmation of simplicity arises from the recognition that very little is needed to live well – that abundance is a state of mind, not a quantity of consumer products or attainable through them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a concept that has been on my mind a lot lately. As we plan our move and I see the amount of crap we accumulate, I can’t help but think we need a better strategy when it comes to the goods we acquire. When I was trying to write out a &lt;a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2012/02/13/how-and-why-to-write-your-own-personal-manifesto/"&gt;personal manifesto&lt;/a&gt; in my journal, one of the things I landed on that was important to me was my use of goods and resources. Here are the bullet points:
- Actively looking for ways to reduce my waste
- Only keep things that are frequently useful, or which I like to look at
- Think more carefully when acquiring new things about sustainability, utility, and aesthetic value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ‘simple living’ doesn’t mean buying cheap stuff. In fact, to me it means the opposite in many cases. I want to acquire &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; stuff, but I want it to be higher quality. I want to buy things that last and that I enjoy seeing in my home.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1146101677</id><title>Mass Production and Mass Media</title><updated>2015-02-23T20:59:01.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Produce for a micro market.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Market to a micro market.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;When someone wants to know how big you can make (your audience, your market share, your volume), it might be worth pointing out that it's better to be important, to be in sync, to be the one that's hard to be replaced. And the only way to be important is to be relevant, focused and specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more it’s possible to be successful in &lt;em&gt;media&lt;/em&gt; without being successful in the mass media. Fame and audiences more niche heavy. Find your &lt;a href="http://kk.org/thetechnium/2008/03/1000-true-fans/"&gt;1,000 true fans&lt;/a&gt; and you can be successful.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3389099978</id><title>The Great SIM Heist - How Spies Stole the Keys to the Encryption Castle</title><updated>2015-02-21T00:24:44.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Depressing news of the day. The NSA hacked a SIM card producer and they’re now easily decrypting your communications. Is there a way to arrest the people responsible for crap like this?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3133629547</id><title>The town without WiFi or cellular service</title><updated>2015-02-19T22:36:22.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what’s more interesting, this town or the fact that it seems so antiquated. Also, that rectangle for the quiet zone seems incredibly large.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2726500488</id><title>Leaving ESPN</title><updated>2015-02-18T21:40:11.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just over three years ago, I was doing a little freelancing and working on an idea for a fantasy football site I had. I’d spent the year applying to jobs, occasionally landing interviews, and always getting turned down. I saw the “We’re Hiring” link on my ESPN Fantasy Football clubhouse, and figured why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month later I was sitting next to Jerry Rice on a bus to get my rental car for my interview. Within a week, I was hired at ESPN as a web developer in the League Manager group. I moved across the country to Seattle and immediately got to work helping to build Fantasy Football for iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ESPN was the first company to actually give me the chance to show what I’m capable of. And I like to think they don’t regret it. I’ve been able to contribute to some incredible projects in my time here, and in the process I’ve learned a &lt;strong&gt;shit ton&lt;/strong&gt; about what it takes to develop a large scale web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the time has come for me to leave ESPN. My wife and I have been looking for a while at moving home to Knoxville, Tennessee and we’re finally able to make that happen. While we’re incredibly excited about it, we’re a bit melancholy about having to leave the company that has given me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so thankful for the opportunity to get to work here. I’m thankful for the incredible and talented group of people I got to work with. I got to experience the other side of the interview table, and I got to experience not being excited about a candidate, only to realize once they were hired how fucking wrong I was (This is why I’m incredibly sympathetic to the many “no’s” I’ve received).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my then fiancée started grad school in Orlando, my manager and superiors were awesome and worked hard to make it possible for me to move and work from Florida while staying in my current role. When I told them I wanted to move to Knoxville, they did everything they could to make it happen but it just wasn’t in the cards. I’m so thankful for all of those efforts and the appreciation they showed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ESPN and Disney are fantastic organizations that appreciate their employees and reward them for good work. I will certainly miss the magic that both provide. More than that I will miss the many people I’ve worked with that make that magic possible. I have no doubt that my team will continue to do awesome work without me. I like to think part of me will stick around there (and not just a few poorly named variables and accidentally committed debugger statements). I’m positive that a part of ESPN and Disney will always be with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only regret is that my coworkers will no longer have someone around to constantly remind them that the SEC is superior to all other forms of sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t yet know what my next thing will be. I’m pondering a few options. I will keep sending my &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/threethings"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to launch &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt; in the coming months. And I'm really dying to get into a little podcasting. If you want to work together on something, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2471030057</id><title>Git Bisect and Why it is Amazing</title><updated>2015-02-17T09:11:38.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was able to wade through 913 commits to find the single commit that caused a bug in a piece of software that spans hundreds of files and over 150,000 lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It took about three minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Git bisect is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don’t use git bisect enough. It’s incredibly powerful for tracking down problems.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3083132742</id><title>The Future of Cinema</title><updated>2015-02-16T13:37:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;M.G. Siegler with a great piece on the future of cinema, and the movie going experience in general. What really resonated with me, and is something that has been on my mind for a while, is the experience of going to movie theaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something very romantic to me about the movie theater. I’m not sure where it comes from, since it’s never been anything like that in my life. I love the idea of the night out at the movie theater. But the fact is that night out revolves around two hours in the dark without talking. The theaters have essentially worked their butts off over the past few decades to figure out how to get you to buy really expensive shit to go along with that experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Siegler hits on that I really want more of is the sort of boutique movie theater...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Probably the best experience I’ve had watching a film in recent years is over here in London. There’s a theater called Electric Cinema in Notting Hill which is fantastic in every way. Massive recliner seats, couches, and even beds and blankets! And lots of good food and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of similar theaters in North Orlando, and I love the experience. Compare it with the dirty, uncomfortably 80s experience of movie theaters today, and you see why I think this is the real future of movie theaters. It’s a dream of mine to open up a sort of boutique theater with a nice bar and an interesting menu...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2827662311</id><title>This is the new ESPN app</title><updated>2015-02-13T10:35:50.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The transformation this app has taken going from ScoreCenter to SportsCenter to ESPN is just fantastic. Personally, I loved putting the SportsCenter brand on the app. It just felt right. Regardless of naming, the teams that have worked on this have built an awesome experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3431403213</id><title>How I use Simple</title><updated>2015-02-11T11:00:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been quite effusive about &lt;a href="http://www.simple.com"&gt;Simple&lt;/a&gt; since I first signed up. There are two particular features of Simple that make it &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; powerful as a financial planning tool: Goals and Safe-to-Spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple allows you to create goals for any expense you’re planning. It works like this. You name your goal, set an amount you’d like to save and then decide whether you want to save it now or save it over time until a specific date. This is where Safe-to-Spend comes in, because any money that is put into that goal is no longer available in your Safe-to-Spend total. If you choose to save over time, Simple will gradually move money from Safe-to-Spend and into the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/simple/createGoalOverTime.png" alt="Creating a goal" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The psychological power of this setup can’t be overstated. I know that I can see my actual balance and I may have plenty of money in my account, but if that Safe-to-Spend total is low then it’s hard to spend anymore. Not only would I feel like I’m spending money I don’t have, but I could see in my goals the things that I’m taking money away from if I spend beyond my Safe-to-Spend. Effectively it’s a digital version of Dave Ramsey’s &lt;a href="http://www.daveramsey.com/article/dave-ramseys-envelope-system/lifeandmoney_budgeting/"&gt;envelope system&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in the Goals section of the website, there’s this fantastic little popover that shows you how much money will be put in Goals until your next paycheck. In my opinion, this information is tremendously underemphasized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/simple/paycheck.png" alt="Nice preview of your status until the next paycheck" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do I use Simple? First off you have to get around one painful fact. Simple doesn’t have recurring goals. You can’t say a goal occurs once a month or year and have a goal automatically created. So let’s break down what different types of goals I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="yearlybills"&gt;Yearly Bills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evernote, Dropbox, Fastmail, and the list goes on. If I can get a cheaper bill by going yearly, I usually do it. Once a year I create a goal for these items. Easy to maintain. And you’re never surprised by a big unexpected expense. You’ve been saving all year, and that big expense is just a blip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="monthlybills"&gt;Monthly Bills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out trying to maintain the monthly things by actually creating a goal each month. But that takes a lot of work and can get a little confusing within a given pay period. So it’s better to handle these yearly as well. Many monthly bills, like rent, cable, internet, or mobile phone, have the same cost every month. With these you can calculate a total for the year and create a goal. Then by the time each bill rolls around, you should have just the right amount to pay it from the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others, like utilities, are variable. For the variable bills it helps if you have a year’s worth of bills to look through, then you can estimate what a year is going to cost and get pretty close. What’s important is that you have a decently close number, and your goal will prevent that monthly bill from making a dent in your Safe-to-Spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="budgeting"&gt;Budgeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another type of goal I create is a yearly budget for certain categories. So I create a goal once a year for things like groceries, gas, tithing, and fun with my wife. Again, you’re looking for solid estimates here, not exact totals. If you have to make some adjustments throughout the year that’s okay. It forces you to really think about your spending on these things and be aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="oneoffexpenses"&gt;One off expenses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create goals for other expected or desired expenses. I have goals for my wife’s birthday, our anniversary, and Christmas. I can save all year for these things and not be caught off guard when they come around. If you are thinking you want to upgrade to a new phone next year, you can start saving now. This is how I make buying phones off contract a reasonable reality. Instead of a sudden major expense, or paying my carrier more every month to make that phone cheaper up front, I pay myself a little every day until iPhone launch day comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="acushion"&gt;A cushion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start really using goals, you end up with a nice chunk of money in them that isn’t in your Safe-to-Spend. What’s nice is it gives you this cushion of immediately available money. If an unexpected expense does come in, you can pull some money out of a few goals and adjust your expectations. Maybe spend less at Christmas. Or cancel/reduce a service. Or just take the money out of the goal and know you’ll be able to compensate gradually. Instead of taking on credit card debt, you take on self debt. It’s so much nicer to know exactly what you’re sacrificing rather than blindly spending out of a single pool of money. &lt;em&gt;(Unless you have an actual pool of money, then you just do you)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple has been a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; boon to my financial management. Bills and large expenses are easy to plan for and track and my stress levels are greatly reduced. I don’t have to plan and save in a spreadsheet, Simple does it for me. One might say it makes managing your finances... Simple?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>593136364</id><title>Please respect my decision not to dance</title><updated>2015-02-10T23:39:33.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And I know I am not alone. There are others like me — you know who you are — leaning against the wall or sitting on the sidelines at weddings and parties. I see your struggle in a way the flesh-shakers simply can’t, and I understand your plight, especially when someone is attempting to cajole you into dancing. We may be few, but we exist, we the lurkers in the shadows, the non-dancers. Please respect who we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important message straight from my soul. Please note, if you give me medium quantities of alcohol this message no longer applies.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1898178191</id><title>The curse of compressing reality</title><updated>2015-02-09T18:26:04.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any creative endeavor is highly non-linear, but the sharing of it almost always skips a lot of the actual work that goes into it. That’s ok; a clear progression makes for a good story that’s easy to tell. But don’t judge your reality against someone else’s compressed work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I needed to be reminded of on a daily basis. I see great writers like John Gruber and Shawn Blanc cranking out awesome stuff. I see devs and designers like Marco Arment and Greg Wohlwend cranking out awesome stuff. And I start comparing myself. I look at my process and see how messy and shitty it is and how it doesn’t compare to their results. People who do great work do a lot of hard messy work first. If you want to do great work, just do work, power through that hard shitty stuff and get better.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3354878638</id><title>Wake Up Excited</title><updated>2015-02-05T09:09:01.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brad Frost tells you to get excited.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>461364297</id><title>The Unreasonable Effectiveness of C</title><updated>2015-02-04T08:24:09.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a huge fan of C. I have no doubt that my C skills aren’t what the used to be, but speed aside there’s something fantastic about how much C lets you get your hands dirty and forces you to know how every little thing works. Sure it’s just another abstraction, but I like to think it’s the perfect amount of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1918064744</id><title>Sleep Advice</title><updated>2015-02-03T08:26:51.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some great advice on how to sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3223106571</id><title>Something Slightly Less Terrible</title><updated>2015-02-02T21:57:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fantastic interview with Loren Brichter. Really love his advice for developers starting out...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remember that nothing is magic. Even though it seems like you’re working at the top of a stack of impenetrable abstractions, they’re made by people (who were probably rushed, or drunk, or both). Learn how they work, then figure out how to minimize your dependence on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>384839722</id><title>Personal Manifesto</title><updated>2015-01-30T16:18:02.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I wanted to do better in 2015 was write in my journal. I’ve been following &lt;a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/01/01/jumpstart-your-journaling-a-31-day-challenge/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; excellent list of prompts from the Art of Manliness. Yesterday’s challenge was to write a personal manifesto and it’s something that really resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many things in life pulling us in a million directions. If you aren’t intentional about what matters to you and what you’re striving to make of your life every day, you can get lost in the sea of crap. Writing a &lt;a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2012/02/13/how-and-why-to-write-your-own-personal-manifesto/"&gt;personal manifesto&lt;/a&gt; can give you a rubric for spending time and making decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The word manifesto traces its roots to the Latin manifestum, which means clear or conspicuous.  A manifesto is defined as a declaration of one’s beliefs, opinions, motives, and intentions. It is simply a document that an organization or person writes that declares what is important to them.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;A manifesto functions as both a statement of principles and a bold, sometimes rebellious, call to action. By causing people to evaluate the gap between those principles and their current reality, the manifesto challenges assumptions, fosters commitment, and provokes change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working out the details, and will be for some time, but I wanted to start by just laying out the areas of my life I want to address in my manifesto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My relationship with God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My relationships with family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My use of goods and resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Care of my body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service to community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible use of technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still sussing out what each of these means. A couple of them are related, so I might try to fold them into each other for simplicity. But these are the areas I landed on that are important to me. That I want to be conscious of every day. One aspect that’s missing is my work. Not because it isn’t important, but because I’m still trying to thoughtfully address it. I want to nail the essence of why my work matters to me and where I pull the meaning from.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>155397061</id><title>Sprinting</title><updated>2015-01-29T22:06:50.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve started using Agile in our team at ESPN, and the experience has made me see just how discombobulated my strategy for working on side projects is. Starting this week, I’m taking some Agile-ish concepts and getting them into my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the problems I have is I’ve got two (well, three, but one has been way on the back burner) projects going on at once and I’m constantly going back and forth on this and that. This context switching from day to day even makes it almost impossible to make real progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I’m doing a little sprint. Each sprint will focus on one project. For now I’m just going to cycle through all three projects week by week. Taking away my ability to just hack on the little thing I want to hack on will help me get shit done. If the nature of deadlines or tasks that need to be done requires it, I will adjust my plan a bit. But I want to make sure I’ve got my weeks’ planned well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pulling my projects and tasks into &lt;a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus/"&gt;Omnifocus&lt;/a&gt; and doing my planning there. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to love Omnifocus, but it feels like the learning curve is so steep. So if you have any tips or workflows for Omnifocus, I’d love to hear them. If it ends up creating too much friction I’ll just move back to &lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com/things/"&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt;, which has been my old standby for years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintaining discipline with a project you work on alone is tough. It’s time to get proactive about my planning.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1612097508</id><title>It's ok</title><updated>2015-01-28T21:26:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s ok to fail. It’s ok to lose. It’s ok to be depressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this one queued up for a while to share. Too long really. If you’re struggling with depression, talk to someone.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>352000716</id><title>Universal Sandwich Theory</title><updated>2015-01-27T17:43:52.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve come up with something I’m calling ”The Universal Sandwich Theory". Follow along with me here: A sandwich made with bad ingredients and poorly made bread will be a horrible sandwich. A sandwich made with good ingredients but poorly made bread will be a bad sandwich. A sandwich made with great ingredients but poorly made bread will be a mediocre sandwich. Conversely, a sandwich made with bad ingredients and great bread will be a mediocre sandwich. A sandwich made with good ingredients and great bread will be a great sandwich. A sandwich made with great ingredients and great bread will be a fantastic sandwich. Bread is the most important ingredient of any sandwich. When making a sandwich, focus on getting the best bread you can. It makes whatever is happening in the middle better. (This also applies to way more than sandwiches.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completely agree. This is why I don’t like standard whole wheat bread. It’s dryness just completely ruins any sandwich for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also definitely applies to burgers. I’ve had a lot of really good burgers (medium rare, with some mayo in case you need to know), but what separates the &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; ones is the buns.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>96530285</id><title>Canadian Passports</title><updated>2015-01-26T09:38:05.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;These Canadian passports are beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3113742990</id><title>From Open (Unlimited) to Minimum Vacation Policy</title><updated>2015-01-22T09:10:35.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think this is a fantastic shift. Open vacation policies can be difficult to navigate and leave you feeling guilty even when you take a minimum time off. It’s hard to track how much time your coworkers are off, but you always tend to fear looking like you aren’t working. Butts in seats != work. I’m a fan of open vacation policies and shorter work weeks. Not just because it makes life a little easier, but I think at the very least, it doesn’t reduce productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2858272559</id><title>Core Curriculum</title><updated>2015-01-20T23:47:37.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And so, why not put together a small notebook that contains highlights and summaries from the books, speeches, articles, sermons, teachings, and other things which have most shaped us? Our own Core Curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great stuff from Shawn Blanc. I’m thinking on this as I debate what to do with my journal once I’m done with the 31 day prompt list I’m following from Art of Manliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what I want to do is in the vein of Shawn’s Core Curriculum. I want to compile a fairly small list of questions that inspect the various important areas of my life. What did you learn about marriage today? How did you experience God? What inspired your work? In the future, what did you learn about fatherhood? How did you fail or succeed financially?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like a list of maybe 10 or so questions to choose from. And each day I’ll pick one from the list. Whatever question lines up with an experience I had. I need to make sure I word the questions so that they’re scoped well and feel answerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely going to stew on this through the end of January...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1676929096</id><title>Poaching lawsuit sounds familiar</title><updated>2015-01-16T17:08:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The thing is, that “they chose this route” defense doesn’t work in antitrust.  The reason we have antitrust laws is because if a firm or group of firms acquires enough market power, they can make that choice a farce, eliminating the aspect of our market economy where firms compete to make the best offer and then we choose among them (whether to buy sometime or to sell something, even our labor). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound like a topic of conversation &lt;a href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/post/13848770602/myth-13-because-a-few-college-athletes-are-good"&gt;somewhere else&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1421458665</id><title>My Analog Life</title><updated>2015-01-15T23:24:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I'm a software developer who uses video games to unwind. Officially, I think, this makes me the kind of person many people imagine would be waiting with bated breath for some kind of ubiquitous, brain implanted computer. I will admit, I do have what I consider a serious addiction to information acquisition -- books were a gateway drug. However, my boundary between digital and analog is extremely definitive. Where most people see digital and analog as opposing forces, and one easily annihilating the other, I always see two different but complementary tools. I wouldn't eat soup with a knife, nor would I cut a steak with a spoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>143704074</id><title>Paid Things</title><updated>2015-01-14T22:57:58.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently shared some of the &lt;a href="/2015/01/01/2014-in-Review/"&gt;things&lt;/a&gt; I’m digging from 2014 going into 2015. I wanted to take some time to share a few more things. Specifically I wanted to share some things I pay for that I could probably get for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fastmailhttpwwwfastmailcomd1040yearperuser"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastmail.com"&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; - $10-40/year per user&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure I could use Gmail or Yahoo Mail or a million other free services, but I prefer to be the customer not the product. Fastmail focuses on &lt;a href="https://www.fastmail.com/help/ourservice/security.html"&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.fastmail.com/about/privacy.html"&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt;. The web app is every bit as good as Gmail but with no pesky ads. They use all the email standards, so you can use whatever desktop and/or mobile client you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond all that you get calendar and contacts syncing, file storage with FTP &amp;amp; WebDAV access, website &amp;amp; photo gallery creation, XMPP chat, etc etc. I don’t think I’ve even taken advantage of everything Fastmail can do in my life. I &lt;em&gt;absolutely&lt;/em&gt; recommend them to everyone. They will be powering my family’s email for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="feedwranglerpodwranglerhttpwwwfeedwranglernetd19year"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.feedwrangler.net"&gt;Feed Wrangler/Pod Wrangler&lt;/a&gt; - $19/year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, the only way to do RSS reading was Google Reader. Then Google decided to shut it down and the race was on for products to replace it. I’ve tried several of them, and I settled on Feed Wrangler. I’m a simple user and don’t use most of the advanced features, but there’s a lot of power in the smart streams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also as a subscriber to Feed Wrangler I get access to Pod Wrangler, a companion podcast syncing service. It’s a lot of simplicity added to my life for less than $2 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="dropboxhttpwwwdropboxcomd99year"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dropbox.com"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; - $99/year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love me some Dropbox. Basically all of my frequently used files are stored, synced, and backed up to Dropbox. All of the photos from my phone are backed up there as well. My only complaint is I wish Dropbox offered a plan somewhere between the free couple of gigabytes and the pro 1 Terabyte plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="evernotehttpwwwevernotecomd45year"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.evernote.com"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; - $45/year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep so much in Evernote. Any email I might need in the future gets emailed into Evernote. All my paper bills and major receipts get scanned in. Most of my transfer bandwidth is used by pictures of beautiful homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend that when it comes to the important web services in your life, you find products you love and are worth paying for. If you take the free and easy option, you likely will be the product not the customer or you won’t have much to complain about when that service gets shut down.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4183200939</id><title>College Football Playoff Championship</title><updated>2015-01-13T21:26:35.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Ohio State won the inaugural College Football Playoff last night. In my imaginary world, they were up for one title, and the won it; defeating B1G rival Michigan State 31-28 in the 12 team playoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 16 team playoff, Michigan State was runner up again losing 35-30 to Ole Miss. Lots of fun and upsets were had along the way. Let’s hope the appetizer that was this 4 team playoff gets expanded to be something more exciting (while still maintaining the importance of the regular season by letting in all conference champs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/12_team_finals.png" alt="12 Team Championship" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/16_team_finals.png" alt="16 Team Championship" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1370961860</id><title>Perpetual Neglect</title><updated>2015-01-12T19:50:22.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Being productive is not what’s ultimately important. I want to do my best creative work and I want to have thriving relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Time management, GTD, focus, diligence — these can help keep me on track. But they are not the end goal in and of themselves. I want to focus first on creativity. What do I need to do my best creative work?&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Have I written today? Have I daydreamed? Have I been contemplative? Have I had an inspiring and encouraging conversation? Have I helped somebody? These acts are far more important than the progress I make against my to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trap I fall into far too frequently is searching for ways to be more productive. Sometimes the best thing to do is to take some time for yourself or for someone else, and you will find yourself with renewed focus and energy for your work.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1115491429</id><title>My favorite feeds and podcasts</title><updated>2015-01-09T10:08:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I shared my full list of feeds and podcasts I read and listen to. I wanted to take a few minutes to share my five favorites in each category. I’m sure by the end of the year these five favorites will look completely different&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="favoritefeeds"&gt;Favorite Feeds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.daringfireball.net"&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;
John Gruber is one of the better writers out there. His writing tends to be complementary of Apple, but that’s almost completely because he believes Apple products are superior products. He’s pretty smart, for a Cowboys fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.remodelista.com"&gt;Remodelista&lt;/a&gt;
Some of the best home design out there. Their style leans strongly in the direction of mine, so I see a lot of stuff I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.grantland.com"&gt;Grantland&lt;/a&gt;
Sports and culture collide into something fantastic. I particularly love anything Holly Anderson and Brian Phillips write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thecramped.com"&gt;The Cramped&lt;/a&gt;
A website about 'analog writing’? Seems a bit absurd, but it is fantastic. As someone who has taken more to writing by hand, I love reading about other people’s tools and tactics for better writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jdbentley.com/journal"&gt;J.D. Bentley&lt;/a&gt;
‘Writings on southern tradition, culture, and bourbon’. The bourbon bit seems, unfortunately, a bit dishonest, but the rest is fantastic. Some of the most thoughtful writing on the internet. He’s somewhat intermittent with posts, but when he does write expect a busy week of reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="favoritepodcasts"&gt;Favorite Podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w"&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt;
I’m forcing myself to only pick one Merlin Mann podcast. Unfortunately for Roderick on the Line, I enjoy Dan Benjamin just a little more than John Roderick. Well today at least. Quality, hilarious, thoughtful talk about so many things in our daily lives. With occasional, long tangents about comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.relay.fm/analogue"&gt;Analog(ue)&lt;/a&gt;
Rather than talking about tech specifically, Casey Liss and Myke Hurley talk about how tech affects our lives. A lot of real stuff here. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/espnradio/podcast/archive?id=10401253"&gt;The Moment with Brian Koppelman&lt;/a&gt;
Some of the best interviews with the most interesting people. Brian Koppelman focuses on a moment in people’s lives that lead them to success. But really he gets so much of their lives beyond that moment and it’s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://justthetip.fm"&gt;Just the Tip&lt;/a&gt;
More of the Gruber family in here. I think this is the funniest podcast on the inter webs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.maximumfun.org/shows/judge-john-hodgman"&gt;Judge John Hodgman&lt;/a&gt;
John Hodgman, also known as the PC from the Apple Mac vs PC commercials, hears the cases of listeners with grievances against each other. Recent cases include debates over Wheel of Time, pizza toppings, and hanging sports team flags. This is one of about five podcasts my wife and I both listen to.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4272677963</id><title>Graphene: Fast, Strong, Cheap, and Impossible to Use</title><updated>2015-01-08T22:35:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A good deep dive into the successes, shortcomings, and potential uses for graphene. Also I love a good born-again Christian scientist.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1434411114</id><title>Less than Zero</title><updated>2015-01-07T21:22:16.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The aim of net neutrality is to preserve the Internet as the crucial open sidewalk for communication that it has become. The reason that the Chinese, Russian and Cuban governments fear an open Internet more than anything else is that it allows users to gather and speak to one another. But users of a walled-garden “zero-rated” Internet can’t even click links that go outside the garden. And they certainly won’t be launching their own apps. Linking and building are the fundamental attributes of the Internet — innovation and speech without permission — that must not be compromised away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the countries who have banned &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero-rating"&gt;zero rating&lt;/a&gt; while the US sits on its thumbs (listening to the carrier lobbyists): Chile, Norway, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, and Japan. Seems like we should be leaders here, not followers.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3610078473</id><title>The Child Is the Father to the Man: 9 Foundational Habits Young Men Should Start Now to Raise Themselves Right</title><updated>2015-01-06T10:32:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A somewhat old post from Art of Manliness, but a really interesting look at the concept of manliness. They quote Roosevelt from his autobiography...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Looking back, a man really has a more objective feeling about himself as a child than he has about his father or mother. He feels as if that child were not the present he, individually, but an ancestor; just as much an ancestor as either of his parents.  The saying that the child is the father to the man may be taken in a sense almost the reverse of that usually given to it. The child is father to the man in the sense that his individuality is separate from the individuality of the grown-up into which he turns. This is perhaps one reason why a man can speak of his childhood and early youth with a sense of detachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year or two, I feel like I’ve been going through that process of fathering the man I’m becoming (that’s probably the weirdest sentence I’ve ever written). Obviously it would be silly to call myself “old” but I’m shedding off my boyhood pretty rapidly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this change has made those &lt;a href="/2015/01/05/What-I-want-to-do-better-in-2015/"&gt;things&lt;/a&gt; I want to get better at this year seem more urgent. The longer I go without those improvements, the more my current ways will become habits for “the man”. AoM continues...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just like one day you’ll need to be intentional about fathering your biological children, right now you need to be intentional about fathering your future self. Will you be an absentee dad who leaves your 30-year-old self feeling lost and adrift? Or will you raise a man who is intelligent, virtuous, and able to tackle life with confidence and vigor? No one can control the kind of biological father they are born with. But every young man can strive to be the best possible father to his future self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author goes on to lay down nine foundational habits for a young man to raise himself right. It’s almost creepy how those habits lineup with the ones I wanted to achieve this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>771811624</id><title>What I want to do better in 2015</title><updated>2015-01-05T09:43:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the new year upon us, I thought I’d share some of the things I’m trying to do better in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="dentalhygiene"&gt;Dental Hygiene&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know. Gross. I’ve always been a little bit lazy with my dental hygiene. I want to hop into bed right away rather than take a couple of minutes from my precious sleep to brush my teeth. And don’t even get me started on flossing... So I’m hoping to brush and floss &lt;em&gt;consistently&lt;/em&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="exercise"&gt;Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not an uncommon story, but I’ve gotten pretty lazy since graduating college. I used to play basketball multiple times a day, and now it seems like I get out for a run a few times a year. I’m hoping to run a couple of 5Ks and a 10K in 2015. Also I want to play basketball and tennis frequently. Conservatively, I want to play one of those sports each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="journaling"&gt;Journaling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m setting a hard goal of one journal entry per day in 2015. An entry doesn’t have to be long. I just want to get myself thinking and writing every day (and practicing my cursive). I’m starting out with &lt;a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/01/01/jumpstart-your-journaling-a-31-day-challenge/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; 31 day prompt challenge from The Art of Manliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="releaseoutshape"&gt;Release Outshape&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on an &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/"&gt;iOS game&lt;/a&gt; for almost a year and a half. It’s tough to spend my free time working when so much of my day is spent staring at code, but I want to get this game in people’s hands and let them play. Every awesome game and iOS update makes life a little harder, but I think 2015 is the year my first game hits the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="minimalism"&gt;Minimalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to cut down on the amount of crap in my life. I spend too much time collecting and organizing stuff around the house. I want to be intentional this year about not keeping things that aren’t very useful or beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="recyclingwastereduction"&gt;Recycling/Waste Reduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lauren and I have gotten super lazy about recycling since we moved to Florida. Sure, we could blame it on the city and our complex for not making it easy for us. But we could get off our butts and take recycling somewhere, we just haven’t made the effort. We need to do better. I want to get our home to produce as little waste as possible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="improvemyrelationshipwithlauren"&gt;Improve my relationship with Lauren&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not a day that goes by where my smart ass, picky, introverted nature doesn’t result in me pushing my wife away just a little. I like to think that we’re good at repairing when that happens. But I want to spend more time being intentional about that push and figure out how I can fight it and help us grow closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gotochurch"&gt;Go to church&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of that relationship, my wife and I have missed a lot of church lately. And that’s definitely had an effect. As I write this, tomorrow is the first Sunday of the year. Is it too much to ask for us to be in church for an hour on 52 days of the year? I don’t think so. (Note: &lt;strong&gt;WE DID IT&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure we waited until the last service of the day, but we did it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="readmybible"&gt;Read. My. Bible.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t do this nearly enough. Not nearly. In the past few years I’ve gone digital with the Youversion apps, but I think maybe it’s time for me to move back to pen and paper for my Bible. Having something physical just feels right to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="readmoreingeneral"&gt;Read more in general&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love books. There are just so many things I’m letting suck my time away that I find it hard to sit down and focus. I want to find a good reading spot and commit to spending some time there reading good books. One thing I learned in 2014 was to be quick about putting a book down if you don’t like it. No sense wasting time and demoralizing yourself with something that doesn’t interest you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fewerscreens"&gt;Fewer Screens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I’ve done well in 2014 that I’d like to continue this year is keeping my phone away from me before bed. I charge my phone across the room in bedroom, so I don’t sit and look at it in bed. It’s been &lt;strong&gt;fantastic&lt;/strong&gt; for my sleep. I’d like to try to push that earlier and not use a phone or computer an hour before bed. I tried no screens after 10 for a while and it was pretty nice. I’d like to make myself sit down and, well, maybe read some for a while before I lay down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="callpeople"&gt;Call people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten more and more introverted over the past 10 years. I only answer my phone when I absolutely have to (or if Lauren tells me to). And I avoid calling people at all costs. I think my friendships have suffered and I want to improve that. I want to be able to talk to the people I care about. Seems basic, but it’s hard for an introvert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="startapodcast"&gt;Start a podcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been vaguely talking about this with a couple of my buddies for a while, but we haven’t gotten intentional about making a time happen. Lets do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay that’s a lot of stuff. It’s just one year, I can’t try to change my &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; life in one year. Baby steps. Let’s see if I can make this stuff happen, then we will move on to bigger things.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>206164462</id><title>What I'm reading and listening to in 2015</title><updated>2015-01-03T00:13:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I thought I'd share the blogs and podcasts I'm going to be following this year. I have to warn you these lists are pretty long. I might try to glean a top 5 or 10 in each category so you can get an idea of the creators I couldn't live without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="blogs"&gt;Blogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://andrewalexanderprice.com/blog.php"&gt;Andrew Alexander Price&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.andrewalexanderprice.com/blog.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thevisualnotes.tumblr.com/"&gt;Visual Notes&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://thevisualnotes.tumblr.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenewsprint.co/"&gt;The Newsprint&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feed.thenewsprint.co/thenewsprint"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.simple.com/engineering-rss.xml"&gt;Quantitative Steezing&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.simple.com/engineering-rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net"&gt;The Pastry Box Project&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/feed/rss2/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rog.ie/"&gt;Rog.ie&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://rog.ie/blog?format=rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://meh.com"&gt;meh.com&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://meh.com/deals.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thesynopsis.co"&gt;The Synopsis&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/synopsis"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.onegoodthingbyjillee.com"&gt;One Good Thing by Jillee&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.onegoodthingbyjillee.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sparkjournal.net/"&gt;The Spark Journal&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/sparkjournal"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livingwellspendingless.com"&gt;Living Well Spending Less&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.livingwellspendingless.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://uxporn.uxpin.com"&gt;User Interface Design Patterns and Wireframe Templates | UXPorn by UXPin&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://uxporn.uxpin.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://owensd.io"&gt;owensd.io - thoughts in and out - Articles&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://owensd.io/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nickbradbury.com"&gt;Nick Bradbury&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://nickbradbury.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://productivityist.com"&gt;Productivityist&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/Productivityistcom"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://minimaldesks.com/"&gt;Minimal Desks - Simple workspaces, interior design&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/minimaldesks"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://itchingpixels.com/"&gt;Mark Szulyovszky&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://itchingpixels.com/rss/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.caseyliss.com"&gt;Liss is More&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.caseyliss.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.listsofnote.com/"&gt;Lists of Note&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.listsofnote.com/feeds/posts/default"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/pulse"&gt;Planet Pulse&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/pulse/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.fastmail.com"&gt;FastMail Weblog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.fastmail.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"&gt;Analog Senses&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.analogsenses.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/"&gt;Letters of Note&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/feeds/posts/default"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.saturdaydownsouth.com"&gt;Saturday Down South&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.saturdaydownsouth.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHCph-_jLba_9atyCZJPLQQ/videos"&gt;How It Should Have Ended&lt;/a&gt;  - &lt;a href="http://gdata.youtube.com/feeds/base/users/HISHEdotcom/uploads?alt=rss&amp;amp;amp;v=2&amp;amp;amp;orderby=published&amp;amp;amp;client=ytapi-youtube-profile"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jessgarner.wordpress.com"&gt;In her eyes... that's where hope lies&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://jessgarner.wordpress.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://awkwardfamilyphotos.com"&gt;AwkwardFamilyPhotos.com AwkwardFamilyPhotos.com&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://awkwardfamilyphotos.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thegreatdiscontent.com"&gt;The Great Discontent&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheGreatDiscontent?format=xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/"&gt;Marco.org&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kegsneggsblog.com"&gt;Kegs 'n Eggs Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://kegsneggsblog.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jumblingsoftheheart.wordpress.com"&gt;jumblings.ofthe.h.e.a.r.t&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://jumblingsoftheheart.wordpress.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.evernote.com/tech"&gt;Evernote Tech Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.evernote.com/tech/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.mengto.com"&gt;Meng To - UI/UX Designer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.mengto.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://freshome.com"&gt;Freshome.com - Interior Design &amp;amp; Architecture Magazine&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://freshome.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.remodelista.com/"&gt;Remodelista&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.remodelista.com/contents/index.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://shawnblanc.net"&gt;Shawn Blanc&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://shawnblanc.net/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.getrichslowly.org/blog"&gt;Get Rich Slowly - Personal Finance That Makes Sense.&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.getrichslowly.org/blog/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://code.tutsplus.com"&gt;Tuts+ Code&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thewirecutter.com"&gt;The Wirecutter&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheWirecutter"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com/things/blog"&gt;Cultured Code Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com/things/blog/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://awesomepeoplehangingouttogether.tumblr.com/"&gt;awesome people hanging out together&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://awesomepeoplehangingouttogether.tumblr.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://verynicewebsite.net"&gt;John Moltz's Very Nice Web Site&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://verynicewebsite.net/feed/atom/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grilledcheesesocial.com"&gt;GRILLED CHEESE SOCIAL&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.grilledcheesesocial.com/feeds/posts/default?alt=rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://stratechery.com"&gt;Feed:  » stratechery by Ben Thompson &lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://stratechery.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://useyourloaf.com"&gt;Use Your Loaf&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://useyourloaf.com/blog/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com"&gt;Both Sides of the Table&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.feld.com"&gt;Feld Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/FeldThoughts"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/"&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/index.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.everydayshouldbesaturday.com/"&gt;Every Day Should Be Saturday -  All Posts&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.everydayshouldbesaturday.com/rss/current"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/"&gt;Sportsgeekonomics&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rockytoptalk.com/"&gt;Rocky Top Talk -  All Posts&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.rockytoptalk.com/rss/current"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grantland.com"&gt;Grantland » Features&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.grantland.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://toolsandtoys.net"&gt;Tools and Toys&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kickingbear.com/blog"&gt;kickingbear&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://kickingbear.com/blog/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.manton.org"&gt;Manton Reece&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.manton.org/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thebrief.io"&gt;The Brief&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://thebrief.io/links/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdixon.org"&gt;cdixon blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://cdixon.org/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://davidwalsh.name"&gt;David Walsh Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://davidwalsh.name/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com"&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nathanbarry.com"&gt;Nathan Barry&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/NathanBarry"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bhorowitz.com"&gt;ben's blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://bhorowitz.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ignorethecode.net"&gt;ignorethecode.net&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://ignorethecode.net/blog/rss/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://inessential.com/"&gt;inessential.com&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/xml/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://massivegreatness.com"&gt;massive greatness&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/massivegreatness"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com"&gt;Rands in Repose&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.randsinrepose.com/index.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cameronmoll.tumblr.com/"&gt;Cameron Moll / Designer, Speaker, Author&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://cameronmoll.tumblr.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://the-pastry-box-project.net"&gt;The Pastry Box Project&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://the-pastry-box-project.net/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://david-smith.org/"&gt;David Smith&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://david-smith.org/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.appleoutsider.com"&gt;Apple Outsider&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.appleoutsider.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blog"&gt;The GitHub Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/blog/all.atom"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.neglectedpotential.com"&gt;Neglected Potential&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.neglectedpotential.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/"&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ninjasandrobots.com"&gt;Ninjas and Robots&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://ninjasandrobots.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mattgemmell.com/"&gt;Matt Gemmell&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mattgemmell.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://avc.com"&gt;AVC&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/avc"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.512pixels.net/"&gt;512 Pixels&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://512pixels.net/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://robottuxedo.net"&gt;Robot Tuxedo&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://robottuxedo.net/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/"&gt;BrettTerpstra.com&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://csswizardry.com/"&gt;CSS Wizardry&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/csswizardrycom"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com"&gt;Joel on Software&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://littlebigdetails.com/"&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://littlebigdetails.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.smashingmagazine.com"&gt;Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://rss1.smashingmagazine.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kylesteed.com"&gt;KyleSteed&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/KyleSteed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thriftyandthriving.com"&gt;Thrifty and Thriving&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.thriftyandthriving.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://audaciousfox.com/"&gt;Audacious Fox&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://audaciousfox.com/feed.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sixcolors.com/"&gt;Six Colors&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://sixcolors.com/feed.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.betterment.com"&gt;Betterment&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.betterment.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trashisfortossers.com/"&gt;Trash is for Tossers&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.trashisfortossers.com/feeds/posts/default"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zerowastehome.com/"&gt;Zero Waste Home&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.zerowastehome.com/feeds/posts/default"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grantland.com"&gt;Grantland » Contributors » Holly Anderson&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://grantland.com/contributors/holly-anderson/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://austinkleon.com"&gt;Austin Kleon&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds2.feedburner.com/austinkleon"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gardenista.com/"&gt;Gardenista&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.gardenista.com/contents/index.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.remodelaholic.com"&gt;Remodelaholic&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.remodelaholic.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.teehanlax.com/blog"&gt;Teehan+Lax&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/teehanlax"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://localmilkblog.com"&gt;Local Milk&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://localmilkblog.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.matthewbischoff.com"&gt;Matthew Bischoff&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.matthewbischoff.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://metalbyexample.com"&gt;Metal By Example&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://metalbyexample.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.monumentvalleygame.com/"&gt;Monument Valley by ustwo games&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.monumentvalleygame.com/blog?format=rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/backchannel"&gt;Backchannel — Medium&lt;/a&gt;  - &lt;a href="https://medium.com/feed/backchannel"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sbnation.com/"&gt;SBNation.com: All Posts by Jon Bois&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.sbnation.com/authors/jon-bois/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://betterelevation.com"&gt;Better Elevation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://betterelevation.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sketchnotearmy.com/blog/atom.xml"&gt;Sketchnote Army&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://sketchnotearmy.com/blog/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal"&gt;chrisbowler.com&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thesweetsetup.com"&gt;The Sweet Setup&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://thesweetsetup.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chambersdaily.com/"&gt;Chambers Daily&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/chambersdaily"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bradfrost.com"&gt;Brad Frost&lt;/a&gt;  - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/brad-frosts-blog"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com"&gt;Short of the Week Best 3D Animation Short Films&lt;/a&gt;  - &lt;a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/category/style/3d-animation/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://meteorhacks.com"&gt;MeteorHacks&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://meteorhacks.com/blog/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.feedwrangler.net/rss.rss"&gt;Feed Wrangler News&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.feedwrangler.net/rss.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"&gt;Chris Brakebill&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pxlnv.com"&gt;Pixel Envy&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://pxlnv.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://subjc.com/"&gt;Subjective-C&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://subjc.com/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thecramped.com"&gt;The Cramped&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.thecramped.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://brooksreview.net"&gt;The Brooks Review&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://brooksreview.net/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://patrickrhone.com"&gt;patrickrhone / journal&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://patrickrhone.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tipsaholic.com"&gt;Tipsaholic&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://tipsaholic.com/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://what-if.xkcd.com/feed.atom"&gt;What If?&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://what-if.xkcd.com/feed.atom"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oleb.net/blog/"&gt;Ole Begemann&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://oleb.net/blog/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wholeandpart.com/"&gt;Whole &amp;amp; Part&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.wholeandpart.com/now?format=rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nshipster.com"&gt;NSHipster&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://nshipster.com/feed.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hypercritical.co/"&gt;Hypercritical&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://hypercritical.co/feeds/main"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeascraft.com"&gt;Code as Craft - Code as Craft&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://codeascraft.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/swift-programming"&gt;Swift Programming — Medium&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://medium.com/feed/swift-programming"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://emmas.blogg.se"&gt;emmas designblogg&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://emmas.blogg.se/index.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mymorningroutine.com"&gt;My Morning Routine&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mymorningroutine.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://justinjackson.ca"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://justinjackson.ca/feed/atom/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hexo.io/"&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://hexo.io/atom.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jdbentley.com//journal"&gt;Writings on Southern Tradition, Culture, and Bourbon. – J.D. Bentley | Journal&lt;/a&gt;  - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/jdbentley"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://developer.apple.com/swift/blog/"&gt;Swift Blog - Apple Developer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/swift/blog/news.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gardenista.com"&gt;Gardenista&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.gardenista.com/list/outbuildings/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/"&gt;Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/codinghorror"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://minimalmac.com/"&gt;Minimal Mac&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://minimalmac.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.idonethis.com"&gt;iDoneThis Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://blog.idonethis.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://unsplash.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DESCRIPTIVE - &lt;a href="http://feed.descriptive.audio"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working Out - &lt;a href="http://simplecast.fm/podcasts/128/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Meteor Podcast - &lt;a href="http://www.meteorpodcast.com/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;seanwes podcast  - &lt;a href="http://seanwes.com/feed/podcast"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grit with After Dark Post-Shows - &lt;a href="http://feeds.5by5.tv/quit-afterdark"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tim Ferriss Show - &lt;a href="http://timferriss.libsyn.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judge John Hodgman - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/todayinthepast"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Core Intuition - &lt;a href="http://www.coreint.org/podcast.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serial - &lt;a href="http://feeds.serialpodcast.org/serialpodcast"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Record - &lt;a href="http://goodstuff.fm/ftr/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen - &lt;a href="http://goodstuff.fm/fullscreen/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lost and Lemon - &lt;a href="http://goodstuff.fm/ll/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuff You Should Know - &lt;a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/podcasts/stuff-you-should-know.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuff You Missed in History Class - &lt;a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/podcasts/stuff-you-missed-in-history-class.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPR: TED Radio Hour Podcast - &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510298"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99% Invisible - &lt;a href="http://feeds.99percentinvisible.org/99percentinvisible"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just The Tip - &lt;a href="http://justthetip.fm/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Truth - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/thetruthapm"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pod5 Podcast - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Pod5Podcast"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Margin of Error Tennis Podcast - &lt;a href="http://tennisabstract.com/marginoferror/moe.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accidental Tech Podcast - &lt;a href="http://atp.fm/episodes?format=rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shawn Today - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/shawntoday"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing Perspective - &lt;a href="http://developingperspective.com/feed/podcast/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/debugshow"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSBrief - &lt;a href="http://feeds.nsbrief.com/nsbrief"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vector - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/vectorshow"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dorm Room Tycoon - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/DormRoomTycoon"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electric Shadow - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/electricshadow"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exponent - &lt;a href="http://exponent.fm/feed/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roderick on the Line - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/RoderickOnTheLine"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Record - &lt;a href="http://therecord.co/xml/rss.xml"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JavaScript Jabber - &lt;a href="http://javascriptjabber.com/podcast.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterate - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Iterate"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I Were You - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/soundcloud/mudw"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girl on Guy with Aisha Tyler - &lt;a href="http://girlonguy.libsyn.com/rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5by5 at the Movies - &lt;a href="http://feeds.5by5.tv/movies"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/adhocshow"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B-Sides - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/b-sides/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/upgrade/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/virtual/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BONANZA! - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/bonanza/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematic - &lt;a href="http://feeds.5by5.tv/systematic"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unprofessional - &lt;a href="http://feeds.muleradio.net/unprofessional"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connected - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/connected/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inquisitive - &lt;a href="Http://relay.fm/inquisitive/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analog(ue) - &lt;a href="http://relay.fm/analogue/feed"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back to Work - &lt;a href="http://feeds.5by5.tv/b2w"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brooks Review - Podcast - &lt;a href="http://feedpress.me/TBRpodcast"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Incomparable's Greatest Hits - &lt;a href="http://feeds.theincomparable.com/holiday"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Rebound - &lt;a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:113784502/sounds.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Incomparable Radio Network - Feeds - &lt;a href="http://www.theincomparable.com/feeds/"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clockwise - &lt;a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:58576571/sounds.rss"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac Power Users with After Dark Post-Shows - &lt;a href="http://feeds.5by5.tv/mpu-afterdark"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grantland Sports - &lt;a href="http://sports.espn.go.com/espnradio/podcast/feeds/itunes/podCast?id=6907276"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grantland Pop Culture - &lt;a href="http://sports.espn.go.com/espnradio/podcast/feeds/itunes/podCast?id=9179868"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alton Browncast - &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/libsyn/zihs"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Talk Show With John Gruber - &lt;a href="http://feeds.muleradio.net/thetalkshow"&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3044431311</id><title>College Football Semifinals</title><updated>2015-01-02T10:19:15.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;College football started it’s playoff last night, and that means it’s time for me to simulate my semifinal matchups. They came very close to being in line with an Ohio State v. Michigan State rematch semifinal. Since we got to see Ohio State v. Bama last night, I decided to just plug that final in. Here are the results...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/12_team_semifinals.png" alt="12 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/16_team_semifinals.png" alt="16 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next weekend we will find out if Michigan State can sweep the playoffs, or if Ole Miss can get some redemption for that &lt;em&gt;ugly&lt;/em&gt; bowl performance.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2381831821</id><title>2014 in Review</title><updated>2015-01-01T12:07:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2014 has been an interesting year in the Brakebill household our biggest high and low probably came around the same time with Lauren’s graduation and our &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/"&gt;miscarriage&lt;/a&gt;. Those events have been rippling through our year as we plan for our future and cope with the loss of an expected child. It’s been another beautiful, fun, hard, and humbling year. I’d like to share some of the things I’ve liked this year. In the spirit of my &lt;a href="threethings"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, a “thing” can be just about anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thingsiveliked"&gt;Things I’ve liked&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="prorasoshavesoaphttpwwwitalianbarbercomprorasoshavecream150gtubmentholandeucalyptusnewformula"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.italianbarber.com/proraso-shave-cream-150g-tub-menthol-and-eucalyptus-new-formula"&gt;Proraso Shave Soap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a new convert to this stuff but I already love it. I’ve been doing most of my shaving this year with a safety razor and some soap I bought on Etsy. I could never get a good lather with it. This stuff lathers fantastically and feels great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="merlinmann"&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w"&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.merlinmann.com/roderick/"&gt;Roderick on the Line&lt;/a&gt; are two of my favorite podcasts of the year. Merlin (and John and Dan) are equal parts helpful, hilarious, and... real humans. I love finding people with absurdly different yet awesome view points and experiences from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="coconutoil"&gt;Coconut Oil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff has so many great uses. My wife frequently uses it as cooking oil. You can add it to your &lt;a href="2014/12/17/Oil-and-Coffee/"&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt;. You can use it as a pre shave oil. I’m sure if you search the internet you’ll find more interesting and uncomfortable uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="penandpaper"&gt;Pen and Paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve become a bit of a &lt;a href="http://bulletjournal.com"&gt;Bullet Journal&lt;/a&gt; convert this year. I don’t write down as much as I should and I’m still trying to reach a happy medium between paper tasks and keeping track long term in &lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com/things/"&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="threeshttpsitunesapplecomusappthreesid779157948mt8andmonumentvalleyhttpsitunesapplecomusappmonumentvalleyid728293409mt8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threes!/id779157948?mt=8"&gt;Threes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/monument-valley/id728293409?mt=8"&gt;Monument Valley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two best games of the year by far. Monument Valley is short but it’s just an incredible experience that made me say “whoa” many times. Threes is &lt;strong&gt;infinitely&lt;/strong&gt; playable. I think I’ve played it every single day since it came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="themartianhttpwwwamazoncomthemartiannovelandyweirebookdpb00emxbdma"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Martian-Novel-Andy-Weir-ebook/dp/B00EMXBDMA"&gt;The Martian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite book of the year by far. One of those ones you read in a day or two because it’s just that good. Can’t wait for the &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3659388/"&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="simplehttpwwwsimplecom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.simple.com"&gt;Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve raved about them before. They’ve had a rough year as they made some major technical changes and the transition hasn’t been particularly smooth. But even with these issue, the product is still the best thing out there. I wouldn’t be able to manage our budget without it. And their customer support is second to none, which is hard to find in a bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jdbentleyhttpjdbentleycom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://jdbentley.com"&gt;J.D. Bentley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite writers I’ve found this year. His writing is so thoughtful, concise, and easy to read. If I didn’t contain myself, I would end up sharing every single post he makes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="trippelbeers"&gt;Trippel Beers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long been a fan of New Belgium’s Trippel, but I’ve found that as a style the dubbel and trippel are my favorites. High alcohol content. Thick and wheaty. Not super hoppy. Everything I want in a beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="tomasinospizzahttpwwwtomasinospizzacom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tomasinospizza.com"&gt;Tomasino’s Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our local pizza joint and it’s quickly become one of my favorites. We still order frequently from Papa John’s, but Tomasino’s pizza is fantastic and it’s topped only by their garlic cheesy knots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="feedwranglerhttpfeedwranglernetpodwranglerhttpsitunesapplecomusapppodwranglerpodcastsmadeid692068382mt8"&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedwrangler.net"&gt;Feed Wrangler&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pod-wrangler-podcasts-made/id692068382?mt=8"&gt;Pod Wrangler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two products I use on a daily basis for consuming RSS feeds and podcasts. If you are big on these things, the $19 per year is a steal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="houzzhttpwwwhouzzcom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.houzz.com"&gt;Houzz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my most visited websites. Lauren and I are frequently talking about owning/building/renovating a home in the near future and Houzz is filled with education and inspiration. I’m just not someone who can accept “cookie cutter”, so I need more. Maybe not more. Probably less. But a less that is high quality. Houzz is an awesome way to find that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="elizabethevelynkirbyhttplocalmilkblogcom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://localmilkblog.com"&gt;Elizabeth Evelyn Kirby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I talk about her I just refer to her as local milk. Her blog and instagram have been fantastic to follow. Beautiful homes and sights. Tasty recipes. And a style that is just... comforting and attractive. And she’s a fellow Tennessean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later today or this weekend I’m going to share the podcasts/blogs I’m following heading into the new year. And I’m also going to talk about the shit I want to do or do better this year. Happy New Year y’all.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3838532268</id><title>What Horrible Things Did We Do To Our Penises Last Year</title><updated>2014-12-31T12:49:31.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the most entertaining horrifying things Deadspin does. What terrible things happened to penises this year. Be more careful y’all.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>996671811</id><title>Rooms and Mazes - A Procedural Dungeon Generator</title><updated>2014-12-30T18:17:09.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some fun nerdy reading for you. If you enjoyed the original Legend of Zelda, you’ll enjoy this piece on creating dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2453372258</id><title>The Oatmeal - 6 things I learned from riding in a Google Self-driving Car</title><updated>2014-12-29T22:46:58.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can’t decide if I’m terrified of these things or impatiently waiting for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the self driving car is awesome. Eventually they will be safer and they will make road trips way more bearable. But we will need to be incredibly thoughtful when designing a system of self driving cars. You can’t have some sort of large scale hack giving away control of a large number of cars.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1193275466</id><title>How the sun sees you</title><updated>2014-12-24T16:44:42.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pretty good argument for wearing sunscreen more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>937805035</id><title>Christmas or Bust - The Untold Story of National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation</title><updated>2014-12-23T20:24:23.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some great quotes from the people who made a holiday classic. I love this nugget...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For the dog and squirrel chase, we hired an animal trainer who trained them everyday for months to run through the set. When it came time to finally shoot what we've been planning, I got out of my car and saw everyone standing in a huddle shaking their heads and I knew something was terribly wrong. I asked them what was going on and they said, "We have a problem." Okay, what? "The squirrel's dead." I said, "Holy fuck, we're shooting that today!" And the animal trainer turned and said, "Ya know, they don't live that long." We still had to shoot the scene, so we used an untrained squirrel. It was just total chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>530675976</id><title>The Enemy, Real or Imagined</title><updated>2014-12-22T22:20:36.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Outrage—especially when coupled with a false sense of urgency and injustice—leads us away from the nuances of particular situations, away from actually having to weigh all sides of the argument, away from the humanity of the so-called opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More fantastic insight and writing from J.D. Bentley.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>275205545</id><title>College Playoff Round 2</title><updated>2014-12-20T11:25:41.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="/2014/12/12/Georgia-Southern-has-it’s-day/"&gt;Round 1&lt;/a&gt; of my college football playoff(s), Georgia Southern produced a couple major upsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Round 2 there were wildly different results between the 12-Team and 16-Team playoffs. In our 12-Team playoff, there’s something mostly resembling the committee’s selected final four, with Michigan State replacing Oregon. In the 16-Team playoff, Ohio State is the only final four team that made the committee’s list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the brackets...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="12team"&gt;12-Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/12_team_round2.png" alt="12 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="16team"&gt;16-Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/16_team_round2.png" alt="16 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next round is where things will get a little less accurate, as the &lt;a href="http://www.ncaagamesim.com/fb_GameSimulator.asp"&gt;simulator&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t allow for neutral site games. But this is for fun not accuracy, so I’ll just assume the games are closer to the higher seed and make them the home team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, the playoff takes a holiday break until new years. So I’ll simulate the semifinals on the same day as the actual semifinals&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4259996110</id><title>Oil and Coffee</title><updated>2014-12-17T21:57:25.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw a coffee with coconut oil recipe in a recent &lt;a href="http://tipsaholic.com/10-delightful-hot-drink-recipes-cold-nights/"&gt;tipsaholic&lt;/a&gt; post, and I’d heard of &lt;a href="http://nextshark.com/5-reasons-why-everyone-is-putting-butter-in-their-coffee/"&gt;Bulletproof Coffee&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/195"&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt; not too long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something like that crosses my path a few times, I figure it might be worth a try. So this morning I put a tablespoon of coconut oil in with my milk as I steamed it to go in my coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result? Delicious. I can’t speak much for the health benefits, but I enjoyed the coffee. I definitely felt pretty full this morning, but any immediately benefits I felt can probably be attributed to the placebo effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I feel like crap tonight but I think that’s me getting sick rather than the coconut oil. I’m going to keep trying this in my coffee and see if I notice any significant changes.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4004525679</id><title>Sobriety</title><updated>2014-12-16T09:09:08.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People are stuck inside the giant spider web that is the consumer society, which is built upon the idea of accumulating stuff, and they don’t even realize it. But let’s go to the beginning. When you buy something, make no mistake, the money is an instrument that you’re using to pay for it. But what you’re actually paying with is the time of your life that you had to spend in order to earn that money. So whenever you spend on something, what you’re really giving away is time, the time of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy is fantastic. Exactly what government representatives should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this piece, which almost feels like several pieces, Álvaro Serrano talks about the resource of time, geeks and their toys, the two week test, and buying stuff that lasts. Absolutely worth spending some time on.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3597396620</id><title>Playing With My Son</title><updated>2014-12-15T20:00:33.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andy Baio had his son play through twenty five years of video game history in about four years. Just fantastic. My favorite bit...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eliot’s early exposure to games with limited graphics inoculated him from the flashy, hyper-realistic graphics found in today’s AAA games. He can appreciate retro graphics on its own terms, and focus on the gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;My hope is that this experiment instilled a life-long appreciation for smaller, weirder, more intimate games in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m worried that my child won’t understand how simple and yet how difficult games used to be before they were so... realistic. There’s something so magical about a game where you can see the pixels.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3341926189</id><title>Georgia Southern has it’s day</title><updated>2014-12-12T18:03:01.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I thought I would go through and simulate my playoffs as they would happen. I'm using &lt;a href="http://www.ncaagamesim.com/fb_GameSimulator.asp"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; fun little tool to simulate all of the games. I thought about simulating them multiple times to get a more accurate look at how the game would go, but what is college sports without the fun of how random it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up this week, we have round 1 of my two playoff versions. Let’s look at what happened...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="12team"&gt;12 Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/12_team_round1.png" alt="12 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 12 team bracket ended up with mostly chalk, but Georgia Southern pulled off a huge upset of Baylor in double OT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="16team"&gt;16 Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/16_team_round1.png" alt="16 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 16 team bracket also saw Georgia Southern pulling off an overtime upset, this time against #1 Alabama. I like this playoff idea a little more every day.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2212236610</id><title>Marco Arment on himself</title><updated>2014-12-11T22:27:08.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It seems ridiculous that reviewing a bunch of headphones would bring this degree of controversy, but that wasn’t really the cause. I often speak and write with arrogance, absolutes, and generalizations that I don’t intend, and often don’t even realize I’ve done unless someone points it out. It’s probably the biggest flaw in my writing and personality, and while I’ve been trying to write (and think) with more qualifiers, fewer absolutes, and more consideration and inclusion of other viewpoints, I still have a long way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this sitting in my queue for a while, but this is some fantastic and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; self evaluation. I will fully admit to being annoyed my Marco’s ‘arrogance’ and ‘absolutes’ frequently. Despite the fact that we surely disagree on many things, I’ve always respected him and this just makes me respect him &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (myself as much as anyone) could all use more open, honest looks at ourselves. And we would do well to share what we see with the people around us, because they’ve likely seen it and been affected by it.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1956766179</id><title>Just One Thing</title><updated>2014-12-10T15:51:35.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My little girl, Beatrix, has many unique and endearing qualities. But, one of my favorites is this: With almost everyone she meets, she will notice and pick out one thing she likes and then tell them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only we could all be a little more like Patrick Rhone’s daughter. We might be a lot more civil.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2560507081</id><title>UAB Can Afford Football, So Why Is It Choosing Otherwise?</title><updated>2014-12-09T09:53:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do the math and UAB appears to be overestimating the supposed $7.25 million cost of having a football team in 2018-19. In fact, it looks like UAB football is a break-even and/or slightly profitable proposition, without even considering merchandise sales or other, hidden sources of revenue. (For instance, one recent FBS entrant has a $2 million-a-year concession deal with Pepsi, yet credits those revenues to university food services.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, Andy Schwarz is spot on. Read the whole thing to find out how schools use bad accounting in relation to their athletic departments.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4017207528</id><title>The Real College Football Playoff</title><updated>2014-12-08T11:53:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The good news is we get our first college football playoff this year. The bad news is it’s still a bit imperfect. I can’t seem to find my playoff plan on the internet anymore so I’ll give a quick summary here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think college basketball has it mostly right. Conference champions deserve a shot, no matter the conference. In general, if you’re a conference champion you’re a winner. Previously I’ve been a support of 16 teams, but with the total number of conferences down to 10, I’m open to a 12 team playoff. I’m going to frame out what both scenarios would look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="conferencechampions"&gt;Conference Champions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, let’s look at who is getting the automatic bids into our tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AAC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Memphis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;ACC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;FSU&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Big XII&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Baylor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Big Ten&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ohio State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Conference USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Marshall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;MAC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Northern Illinois&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mountain West&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Boise State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pac 12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Oregon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SEC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alabama&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sun Belt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Georgia Southern&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id="atlargespots"&gt;At Large Spots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ve got 10 conference champions that leaves us 2 or 6 at large spots, depending on the playoff format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top At-Large Teams&lt;/strong&gt;
TCU, Michigan State, Kansas State, Mississippi State, Georgia Tech, Wisconsin, Missouri, Arizona, Mississippi, Georgia, UCLA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s just rank the top teams here. There’s a lot of debate to be made here, and my goal isn’t to determine the absolute best field but to show off the format. So forgive me if you think my at large picks are dumb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TCU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kansas State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mississippi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mississippi State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCU and Michigan State are easy. Both teams’ only losses are to teams already in the field. Honestly think Mississippi State had a better season than Ole Miss, but that head to head gives Ole Miss the edge. Both had great seasons in a tough conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kansas State might be the best three loss team in the country. Two losses to top Big XII teams in the field and a close home loss to Auburn. I’m putting them third, partly because they deserve it and partly for better 16 team match ups. Arizona sneaks in despite the rough showing in the Pac 12 title game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="rankingthefield"&gt;Ranking the Field&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that gives us our field of 12 to 16 teams. Let’s rank all 16 top to bottom. (again these are my rankings and I’m sure &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; will disagree)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;16 Team&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;12 Team&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1. Alabama&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1. Alabama&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2. Oregon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2. Oregon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3. Florida State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3. Florida State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;4. Ohio State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4. Ohio State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5. Baylor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;5. Baylor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;6. TCU&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;6. TCU&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7. Michigan State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;7. Michigan State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8. Kansas State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;8. Boise State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9. Mississippi&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;9. Marshall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10. Mississippi State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;10. Northern Illinois&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11. Arizona&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;11. Memphis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12. Boise State&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12. Georgia Southern&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;13. Marshall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;14. Northern Illinois&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15. Memphis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;16. Georgia Southern&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thebrackets"&gt;The Brackets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/real-college-football-playoff/16_team.png" alt="16 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/real-college-football-playoff/12_team.png" alt="12 Team" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the number of conferences down to 10, I think I'm changing my tune a little this year. I'd really prefer the 12 team playoff. I imagine we won't see any new FBS conferences anytime soon so it's a safe bet for the future. And I think it creates more competitive first round matchups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both formats it would likely mean a reduction in the number of regular season games. I think at least one game would have to be dropped off, but maybe two. Frankly this is my biggest concern, because losing those games could be tough financiallly on a lot of teams. Hopefully a profit share of the playoff games could compensate for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you dropped off a game, then you would play two rounds at school sites before Christmas and two rounds at neutral site after New Years. There are a lot of logisitics to work out, but rewarding the conference champions will make for a fantastic playoff.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1027282059</id><title>Three Things - December 7, 2014</title><updated>2014-12-07T16:15:47.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Betterment, Orion, and Die Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/threethings/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2483982506</id><title>Beginning Minimalism</title><updated>2014-12-05T11:53:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Once you begin the process of slowly shedding unnecessary possessions, it becomes intoxicating. Your living space slowly becomes simpler and less cluttered, which has the unexpected effect of de-cluttering your head. It becomes a lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been feeling this sort of tugging at my soul for the past couple of months. I have too much stuff. Too much clutter. And that stuff tends to begat more stuff. I need to replace that stuff. Upgrade it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to evaluate the things in our home. To look for things that I don’t love to look at or need. I’m going to try to share some of my struggle as I attempt to reduce my stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1332260429</id><title>Exodus</title><updated>2014-12-04T17:11:29.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think there is a strong humanitarian argument for making life multi-planetary in order to safeguard the existence of humanity in the event that something catastrophic were to happen, in which case being poor or having a disease would be irrelevant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk is an incredibly fascinating and brilliant guy. If anyone can make this happen, you have to believe it’s him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a related note, the &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/orion/"&gt;Orion program&lt;/a&gt; has me really excited about the future of human space travel. I can’t wait to see what comes of the first test launch tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2788960876</id><title>NaNoWriMo Update</title><updated>2014-12-03T23:22:13.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it’s hard to call my attempt at NaNoWriMo anything but a failure. I wrote about 6 super short chapters of my “novel” and inertia plus the holidays stopped me in my tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem I found each day was my fear before even getting started. I felt like I had already written a bunch of shit and all I could muster up was more of it. I also had this crippling fear of writing myself into a corner. Sticking myself in a position where my story was screwed. The point of NaNoWriMo is to power through this and if you don’t like your plot at the end, you can edit it. But I couldn’t fight off the fear that I was going to write something dumb (this not doing something for the fear that I’ll do it poorly is an all too common story in my life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking about keeping the writing going throughout the year and maybe trying to add to the novel once a week. Nothing to ambitious. Just consistently sticking to the habit, if for nothing else but the habit’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4094002703</id><title>Untitled</title><updated>2014-11-09T10:52:44.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things that is driving me crazy about my iPhone is websites in Safari auto redirecting to their native app. This is the kind of thing that seems great in theory, but it results in a really shitty experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary culprit for me is Pinterest. If I open a link to a board or user or pin on Pinterest, that tab redirects me to the app. Okay cool. I’m logged in in the app. I can check out whatever I was looking at. But if I don’t immediately go close that tab I’m in for trouble the next time I open Safari. The tab will have been purged from memory so it’s reloaded and I’m immediately forced back into the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the solution? To me there are two options. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Close the tab. If you’re directing me out of Safari, then I probably want that context to be closed as I move into another. I’m not sure if devs can do this, but if they can’t Apple should do it. The site is taking me to their app, close that Safari tab. This is the simplest solution, but I think there are marginally decent arguments to be made that you don’t want that tab closed in every situation. I think?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provide developers the ability to show a native extension-like popover view that gives some context. For Pinterest it might be some basic board or information with a small photo. Not the stupid little, “Hey we have an app. Go view it” functionality that Apple provides, but a fully native, developer provided view that lets users decide if they want to load the app. No forcing a user out of the browser and into the app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1255735854</id><title>Here's Why Public WiFi is a Public Health Hazard</title><updated>2014-10-22T08:42:28.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We visit yet another cafe. My last request to Slotboom is to show me what he would do if he wanted to really harm me. He asks me to go to Live.com (the Microsoft email site) and enter a random username and password. A few seconds later, the information I just typed appears on his screen. “Now I have the login details of your email account,” Slotboom says. “The first thing I would do is change the password of your account and indicate to other services you use that I have forgotten my password. Most people use the same email account for all services. And those new passwords will then be sent to your mailbox, which means I will have them at my disposal as well.” We do the same for Facebook: Slotboom is able to intercept the login name and password I entered with relative ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why you should think twice about connecting to public WiFi. If you’re going to use an untrusted network, you really should use a secured VPN like &lt;a href="https://www.getcloak.com"&gt;Cloak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3579468225</id><title>Machine Setup</title><updated>2014-10-16T23:34:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Developers like control. We like things to be just how we like. It tends to take some time to get things that way. This becomes a bit of a problem when you need to do a clean OS install or move to a new machine. How do you restore shell settings? Install node packages? Install your favorite apps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of solutions out there for automating system setups like &lt;a href="https://www.vagrantup.com"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://boxen.github.com"&gt;Boxen&lt;/a&gt; but those seem a little heavy for a personal setup (though I’m open to suggestions otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I had the chance to take a sort of git crash course from Github’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/matthewmccull"&gt;Matthew McCullough&lt;/a&gt; and encountered his system setup &lt;a href="https://github.com/matthewmccullough/dotfiles"&gt;process&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been using the zsh aliases and oh-my-zsh for a long while with some minor tweaks, but after a recent clean install I decided to really make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://brew.sh"&gt;Brew&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic tool for installing packages that you want. But the real game changer for me was &lt;a href="http://caskroom.io"&gt;Cask&lt;/a&gt;. It installs Mac applications automatically right from the script. You’re limited to apps that have been added by the community and you can’t install the apps you’ve bought on the Mac App Store, but it’s a great start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when I load up a fresh OS X install all I have to do is install Dropbox and let it sync, go into my dotfiles folder and run &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;_setupdotfiles.zsh&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m set. I’m sure I’ll find improvements along the way. But I thought I’d share &lt;a href="https://github.com/braker1nine/dotfiles"&gt;my setup&lt;/a&gt; so it might benefit someone else.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>741201376</id><title>Sleeping Without Phones</title><updated>2014-10-16T07:55:20.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back, Dan Benjamin and Merlin Mann discussed how blue light affects our sleep on &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/160"&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt;. It was a really fantastic discussion and it resonated with my own experiences. I tended to sit up late at night, staring at my phone and wondering why I wasn’t sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They link &lt;a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-light-affects-our-sleep/#axzz2uMAnScJH"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where Mark Sisson dives into the science of why blue light keeps us awake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Blue light regulates our secretion of melatonin, the sleep hormone. Exposed to blue light, we limit the production of melatonin, and we stay alert and awake; in the absence of blue light, melatonin production ramps up, and we get sleepy. This system worked quite well for a long time. Reddish light from fire (our formerly primary source of nighttime illumination) has little to no effect on melatonin production, so sleep wasn’t disrupted when we relied on fire. These days, though, we’re subject to a steady barrage of blue light. During the day, blue light (natural or unnatural) isn’t much of a problem because we’re supposed to be awake, but at night, when we’re “supposed” to be getting ready to sleep, we tend to sit in front of blue light-emanating appliances, and our sleep suffers for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m generally a skeptical guy, but this felt anecdotally right to me. I already had &lt;a href="https://justgetflux.com"&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt; installed on my MacBook and felt at night as if &lt;em&gt;it was making me&lt;/em&gt; tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I moved my phone charger to the office and left it there at night. Not having it next to me has taken away the temptation to look at it. That is a temptation I cannot resist. &lt;strong&gt;IT’S SO CLOSE. I CAN REACH IT INDY.&lt;/strong&gt; Since my Fitbit broke, I’ve moved my phone back into the bedroom for alarm purposes, but I keep it across the room. It’s actually fantastic because it keeps me from staring at the phone at night and forces me to get up in the morning to shut it off. The only time I keep my phone on the nightstand anymore is when I’m on call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was frequently laying in bed, unable to fall asleep, and then finally getting up to go downstairs and read myself into a coma (Kindle FTW), but I haven’t done that in months it seems. I still have some nights where I struggle to sleep, but that’s usually due to shoulder pain and having another human taking up space in the bed. I like to really spread my elbows out, and they can do damage. &lt;strong&gt;(MARRIAGE TIP: Use separate blankets. Thank me later).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3776071880</id><title>The Song of the Introvert</title><updated>2014-09-17T10:35:04.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are a threat.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It’s a strong word. I don’t mean that you intend pain, injury, or damage. But I’m an introvert and you – as a new unknown human – are a threat to me. I don’t know what you want and you most definitely want something and until I figure that out, you’re a threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand me and other introverts better…&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3520601449</id><title>The Shocking Truth About Yourself</title><updated>2014-09-03T22:30:40.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The greatest evil is this: pride, avarice, lust, envy, gluttony, anger, and sloth. Avoid those and you’ll arrive at their polar opposites, which are the greatest good: humility, charity, chastity, kindness, temperance, patience, and diligence.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;If you lack purpose, if your life is a mess, then you are surely practicing, in some measure, the evils and failing to practice the good. There’s no easy fix for that. There’s no expert for that. There are no “12-steps” or “30-days” that can turn that around for you. It’s a choice made daily and fought for by the minute. It’s exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But it’s the only thing that works. Anything else is snake oil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JD Bentley has one of my favorite websites to read. So many things I read fast and carelessly. But I know when he puts something out there it's worth the time to slowly take in.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2242846858</id><title>Pleasing a person who is not in the room</title><updated>2014-09-02T22:15:44.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It's the boss's job to continually ask, "is this the most daring vision of your work?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how easy it is to prevent stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1987376427</id><title>Fantasy Football Fantasy</title><updated>2014-08-25T22:35:31.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Mannings. Always gold.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2547825228</id><title>Good at the Beginning</title><updated>2014-08-20T21:06:46.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every rejection is a gift. A chance to learn and to do it better next time. An opportunity to figure out how to bounce, not break. Don't waste them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2292354797</id><title>The Slow Web</title><updated>2014-08-20T20:30:58.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;History will probably laugh at our time’s attempt to impose a mentality of industrial production upon creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really love the 'mantra' put forth by iDoneThis. If you're not following their blog you're missing out.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1014600206</id><title>You're 16. You're a Pedophile. You Don't Want to Hurt Anyone. What Do You Do Now?</title><updated>2014-08-15T17:38:45.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow. It's hard to do, but it lends a bit of humanity to a group of people we have a hard time seeing as human.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2517214980</id><title>Lets Build A Traditional City</title><updated>2014-08-15T09:39:47.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An old post that resurfaced this week. I find this really fascinating, particularly the move to a more European style of city construction. Our sprawling cities with wide roads and huge parking lots suck.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2261744549</id><title>Empathy</title><updated>2014-08-08T12:14:08.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A friend of mine told me that, when dealing with people, it’s best to assume positive intent. You can view it as a shortcut (since, truthfully, the vast majority of people do have positive intent), but more importantly it’s a conscious choice that makes the world a better place for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some excellent advice from Matt Gemmell.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>209775554</id><title>Why I am leaving the best job I ever had</title><updated>2014-08-08T12:08:34.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Friends and colleagues often ask my wife how she balances her job and motherhood. Somehow, the same people don’t ask me.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I decided the only way to balance was by stepping back from my job. MongoDB is a special company. In my nearly 4 years at the company, we have raised $220 million, grown the team 15x and grown sales 30x. We have amazing customers, a great product which gets better with every release, the strongest team I have ever worked with, and incredible momentum in the market. The future is bright and MongoDB deserves a leader who can be “all-in” and make the most of the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I cannot be that leader given the geography of the majority of the company in New York and my family in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says a lot about our society that men aren't asked these same questions. Fatherhood is &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt;. Kudos to Max Schireson.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3420950118</id><title>SEC Network: Tennessee</title><updated>2014-08-07T19:48:13.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/NhsEqOdx8Tk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4249272419</id><title>Being Wrong</title><updated>2014-08-04T21:08:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;once you accept the beauty and utility of being wrong, “putting something out there” quickly becomes one important step on the path to being right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much good here from Casey and &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2014/07/31/how_to_be_wrong_on_the_internet"&gt;Brent&lt;/a&gt;. I need to think about this more and worry less about being wrong. I think I stay away from technical stuff for fear of being wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3842143360</id><title>App Disillusionment</title><updated>2014-08-04T21:07:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Commoditizing apps and tightly controlling the market for apps on iPhones benefits Apple, and many of its users, in the short run. But in the long run, an unhealthy software ecosystem can’t be good for Apple, for its users, or for the developers who write apps for Apple’s platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple obviously doesn't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to do anything right now. They're making a lot of money selling iPhones. But their store is flawed. It inhibits a lot of applications and prevents talented developers from being able to make a living selling apps. It may not be hurting now, but it will at some point. The point is Apple could do more to make building great apps a viable business venture, and doing so would directly benefit Apple.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1301650181</id><title>The Moment: Tim Ferriss</title><updated>2014-07-31T18:58:23.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fantastic interview from Brian Koppelman. I've been meaning to read the &lt;a href="http://fourhourworkweek.com"&gt;4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt; for years...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3586672929</id><title>We Really Can't Have Nice Things</title><updated>2014-07-31T18:57:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Seriously, Apple launched the App Store with no mechanism for Trials and Upgrades and we all just though “Meh, that’s fine.” Turns out, we screwed over everything by accepting that.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I love iOS and all these apps, but once we lose the good developers, we’ll lose the good apps. And then we’ll lose the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a bunch of crap about this, but didn't feel like I had a coherent thought. Thankfully Ben Brooks took care of it for me. I'm not convinced the top lists are a positive or a negative. But these other failures are a huge negative.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1967489870</id><title>Insulated Perspectives</title><updated>2014-07-24T13:04:38.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;David Smith talked on his podcast today about &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threes!/id779157948?mt=8"&gt;Threes!&lt;/a&gt; and 2048. In particular he was talking about an acquaintance playing 2048, and how he perceived this acquaintance's experience. You'll have to &lt;a href="http://developingperspective.com/2014/07/24/0/"&gt;listen&lt;/a&gt; to hear the nuances of his point, but essentially his deduction was that 2048 made the acquaintance feel smart and that's why he valued it versus Threes!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really missed the mark for me. I think by design Threes! gives users the exact same feeling. It's more difficult for sure, but it provides the exact same satisfaction. What you take pride in achieving is really based on what your friends achieve. If he feels smart, it's because he's doing better than his average friend. While he might take pride in beating 2048, he would take the same pride in getting the 768 block in Threes! if his friends were struggling to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This user wasn't playing 2048 because it made him feel smart and Threes! couldn't. He was playing because 2048 was free. Free games are easier to pick up. You can try them without risking your money. They copied the simple mechanics that made Threes! enjoyable to play and put them out for free. What this story tells me is that this guy, like a lot of App Store consumers, values his $5 (or whatever Threes! costs nowadays).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David's larger point was to understand what it is your potential customers value, which I think was good. We know that a lot of customers (nay, users; if they don't pay they aren't customers) will deal with a lot of crap from a product if it's gives them some utility they don't have to pay for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly developers should be thinking about how they can generate value for customers. 2048 has done that by providing a ton of eyeballs to the customers who pay for ads. The best products, &lt;em&gt;in my opinion&lt;/em&gt;, are the ones that can generate enough value to convince users pay for them. Products like David's own Feed Wrangler/Pod Wrangler and especially apps with delightful and fun experiences like Threes!. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1712019439</id><title>This is Your Brain on Mobile</title><updated>2014-07-24T08:40:55.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some great thoughts on the effects of being chained to your mobile device, and what you can do to break free. I've been doing some similar things myself, which I'm hoping to write about soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>885370478</id><title>BBQ</title><updated>2014-07-23T09:20:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/barbecue/pulled_pork.jpg" alt="Pulled Pork" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shawn Blanc likes to say that those who work with their minds, rest with their hands. It's something I absolutely believe in. Even throughout the day on a micro level, I take brief work rests to clean the kitchen, vacuum the living room, or sift through the horror that is the litter box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shawn likes to do woodworking when he is resting. It's a hobby I would love to get into one day, but right now I don't have the money, space, or tools to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have discovered a different but applicable hobby in barbecue. Not only do I enjoy the labor I put into it, but the fruits (well, meats) I get out of it are quite delicious. In the past month, I've spent two of my Saturdays seasoning meat, soaking wood chips, and keeping my smoker at a consistent low heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/barbecue/raw_pork.jpg" alt="Pork Butt" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the beauties of barbecue is it gives you a lot of time to relax. You have to pay attention to your smoker and the temperature, but it's a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; process and there's a lot of waiting time. You can read a book, drink a beer, finally beat that level on TwoDots, write a letter to your representative, relax in the sun, etc etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/barbecue/outside_thermometer.jpg" alt="Drinking Coffee and waiting..." title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great thing about barbecue is there's a lot of freedom and creativity. You can spice it up however you want. Want to make it sweet? You can do that. Want to put sriracha on it? You can do that. Want to soak your ribs in Dr. Pepper? You can do that. There are so many ways to achieve different flavors. It's almost an art form (but really it's science).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love hacking away, I'm really excited to have a fun hobby that doesn't involve me staring at my computer. There's something so relaxing about spending my Saturday working in the sun. I'm already planning on doing a rack of ribs for my next smoke...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/barbecue/smoking_grill.jpg" alt="" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2268543567</id><title>Stickers</title><updated>2014-07-22T16:52:22.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nifty. Love seeing the old rainbow logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I would never &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; put stickers on my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>222770988</id><title>UI.registerHelper</title><updated>2014-07-22T07:52:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in Meteor you need to use the same helper across templates. For example, if you have several views with admin controls, you might want a helper to help you control who sees those. It would be a pain to add that function to each template. Luckily, Meteor provides the ability to create a new global helper via UI.registerHelper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UI.registerHelper takes two parameters: the name of the helper as a string, and the function to be called. So to add my admin helper I might do something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=" javascript"&gt;    UI.registerHelper('admin', function() {
        return userIsAdmin();
    });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UI.registerHelper is an excellent tool to prevent repeating code and to centralize global template functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1605944077</id><title>Eternity</title><updated>2014-07-21T10:07:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be made for eternity and forced to dwell in time is for mankind a tragedy of huge proportions. All within us cries for life and permanence, and everything around us reminds us of mortality and change. Yet that God has made us of the stuff of eternity is both a glory and a prophecy, a glory yet to be realized and a prophecy yet to be fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thought is a major comfort when I'm overwhelmed with a desire for permanence and an aversion to death or change.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2210298858</id><title>The Kids Menu</title><updated>2014-07-15T22:51:09.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of course, chicken fingers are just a symptom. If we want to insulate ourselves from new experiences, ensure that we never eat something we don't like, never engage with someone we disagree with, never have to hold two opposing ideas in our head at the same time—chicken fingers are a great way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a huge problem for me, for many reasons. The new means the unfamiliar. It means something I might not feel like I'm already competent at. And heaven forbid I do something I'm not already good at...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3593471947</id><title>On the Shutdown of Lavabit</title><updated>2014-07-15T22:49:56.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we allow our government to continue operating in secret, it is only a matter of time before you or a loved one find yourself in a position like I did – standing in a secret courtroom, alone, and without any of the meaningful protections that were always supposed to be the people's defense against an abuse of the state's power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slow to post this, but it's all kinds of terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4083279008</id><title>Full Time: Fading Images of the World Cup</title><updated>2014-07-14T17:34:07.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fantastic&lt;/em&gt; writing from Brian Phillips. I'll be honest I watched a maximum of 30 minutes of non-US soccer during the World Cup. Even then, I didn't watch the Belgium game. Soccer isn't my game, but I'll do just about anything that let's me drink and be patriotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, this is a fantastic commentary of the significance of sport. Or really the significance of how we watch them. Here's the opening, no way you can read this and not read the article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Watching sports is, among other things, a special way of experiencing time. Sport is like music or fiction or film in that, for a predetermined duration, it asks you to give it control over your emotions, to feel what it makes you feel. Unlike (most) forms of art, though, a game has no foreordained plan or plot or intention. The rules of a game impose a certain kind of order, but it’s different from the order of an artwork. A movie knows where it wants to take you; no one can say in advance where a game will go. All of its beauty, ugliness, boredom, and excitement, all of its rage and sadness emerge spontaneously out of the players’ competing desires to win. For however long the clock runs, your feelings are at the mercy of chance. This happens and then this happens and then this happens. You’re experiencing, in a contained and intensified way, something like the everyday movement of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1547699368</id><title>ESPN Fantasy Football</title><updated>2014-07-14T14:53:40.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Get the new hotness. Positive reviews are welcome. If you want to be negative at least help us make it better. Among the new things to enjoy...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FREE Alerts. You don't have to be an Insider anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a team or league right in the app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretty things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2930872457</id><title>JavaScript Fun</title><updated>2014-07-14T09:14:51.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to create a decently designed JavaScript function that, when passed a function, returns (you guessed it) a function that runs some authentication code before trying to execute the passed in function. So the return function would look something like this...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=" javascript"&gt;function createAuthedFunction() {
    return function(variable, numberOf, params) {
        if(checkAuth()) {
            callPassedInFunction(variable, numberOf, params);
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I could just call checkAuth in every function that requires it, but that seems very non-&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_repeat_yourself"&gt;DRY&lt;/a&gt; to me. What I've ended up going with is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=" javascript"&gt;function checkAuthFunction(func, error) {
  return function() {
        if (checkAuth()) {
            func.apply(this, arguments);
        } else {
            error = error || 'You must be an admin to do that.';
            console.log(error)
        }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when an object or function wants to create a method that requires authentication to run, it calls checkAuthFunction and passes in a function (and an optional error message) and this returns a function that checks for proper authentication, and either runs the function or outputs an error message, depending on authentication status. Function.apply allows me to call the passed in function with the current this value and the passed in arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's working for now, but I'm still not in love with it syntactically.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1904331622</id><title>CBTextFieldView</title><updated>2014-07-10T18:36:46.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a simple little view I created for textfield/label selection on OSX. Poorly documented, but available.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3287504711</id><title>iPhone, phone home</title><updated>2014-07-10T18:13:06.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tremendously cool concept to allow the return of lost iPhones to their owners.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3289178051</id><title>The Great Discontent: Rogie King</title><updated>2014-07-10T18:11:28.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes. This is over two years old. Yes. I have a huge man crush on Rogie King.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1964249671</id><title>Facebook's Explanation: We Wanted to Make Sure You Weren't Turned Off By Facebook</title><updated>2014-07-09T22:04:34.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ben Brooks nails pretty much everything I wanted to say about this. My favorite bit from the Facebook explanation...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nobody’s posts were “hidden,” they just didn’t show up on some loads of Feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2179066543</id><title>How Are Apps Made</title><updated>2014-07-09T20:57:11.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How are apps made? Painfully with deliberation or effortlessly without thought. Blind inspiration. Eight hours over a lazy weekend. Fifty grand a day. A million dollars a syllable. Do not look for the sense in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1693806222</id><title>The Other Side of Empathy</title><updated>2014-07-08T15:12:01.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As designers and product builders, we are told to empathize with our users in order to create awesome experiences for the web and beyond. I propose we take a look at the other side of empathy, and make an effort to empathize with the creators behind the products, features, or designs triggering those rage-tweet reactions seen across many a timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I've become a lot more aware of in the past couple of years. Working on a product that is used by millions of people, I know what it's like to see people bashing what you've built. It sucks. I do my best to think before I tweet critically and angrily about a piece of software I'm using.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1516467053</id><title>Persona</title><updated>2014-07-07T17:54:29.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I was younger, it was easy to put people I looked up to on a pedestal. Bosses at work, pastors at church, my favourite bands. That is easy to do from afar, but the closer you get to people, the more you see the real person; the flaws, the hurting, and the mess as much as the good things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great stuff from Chris Bowler. We're all just messy people.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1031206732</id><title>Jonathan Haidt can explain the liberal Hobby Lobby freak out</title><updated>2014-07-05T20:47:25.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lot to absorb here, but it's something that I do feel like resonates with my experiences. Definitely worth a read. The end though is a bit disturbing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet seeing the grotesque animosity towards people like me from liberals over the small-beer Hobby Lobby decision compels me to face up to the fact that the only political force standing between me, my church, and my community, and a State dominated by people who think we traditional church people are cretins who deserve to be pushed around, is Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3503994923</id><title>The Gunfighter</title><updated>2014-06-28T09:36:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great short film. Nick Offerman narrates and is hilarious as usual.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3018734602</id><title>Universal Studios Interactive Wands</title><updated>2014-06-27T15:46:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dang. So cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>500065728</id><title>The Martian: A Novel</title><updated>2014-06-27T12:17:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just spent a couple of days reading this on vacation. Really fantastic book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short, an astronaut gets stranded on Mars. He engineers and potato farms to survive while NASA and his fellow astronauts try to figure out how to get him home.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2841395433</id><title>Fighting to Stay Creative</title><updated>2014-06-26T08:02:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shawn Blanc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We mustn’t be afraid of failing nor of being rejected, and we must place more value on the act of creating so we can find joy in the journey and develop a lifetime of experience in making things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shawn has some &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; advice on creativity. I can feel every one of the stiflers of creativity that he mentions getting a foothold in my work. I'm going to try to be more intentional about keeping those things at bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Gemmell &lt;a href="http://mattgemmell.com/staying-creative/"&gt;adds&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Creative people, in my experience, are plagued with doubt. This is awful! they all think, definitely including myself. It’s a very personal thing, and it’s insidious because you’re the only one who gets to see the first drafts, and the refinements, and whole, messy stop and start and double-back of producing something worthwhile. It’s hard to keep in mind that the first version of everything is garbage, and the final version of everything is still garbage to the person who made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely struggle with this every single day.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2356135112</id><title>Programming Sucks</title><updated>2014-06-25T15:02:07.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So no, I'm not required to be able to lift objects weighing up to fifty pounds. I traded that for the opportunity to trim Satan's pubic hair while he dines out of my open skull so a few bits of the internet will continue to work for a few more days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hilarious. Depressing. Accurate.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3198027687</id><title>Starting Anew</title><updated>2014-06-24T11:01:03.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My father used to always say, “Ask questions, don’t make assumptions." Questions invite conversations, stimulate thinking, break down barriers, create positive energy and show your willingness to understand and learn. Questions show humility, acknowledgement and respect for the past, and give you greater insights into both the business and individuals. And don’t be afraid to ask personal questions or share a few of your personal details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some great advice that I could follow more often.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2712767366</id><title>On Losing a Life, Grief, and Honor</title><updated>2014-06-24T08:41:09.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife wrote a wonderful post on &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/"&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>759129775</id><title>Code as Craft: Opsweekly</title><updated>2014-06-23T15:45:33.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Really cool stuff from Etsy. Quantizing on-call experience and effectiveness is not something you hear about from many companies.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3468166892</id><title>Miscarriage</title><updated>2014-06-20T23:43:40.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had originally planned to call this post "Surprise", because that's exactly what it was when Lauren and I found out we were going to have our first child. But as we neared our 6th week, and our first ultrasound, our excitement was turning into fear. Blood was coming when it shouldn't have been. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week and three ultrasounds later, our baby was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotions of going from "oh crap we're having a baby" to "I can't wait to have this child" to "I don't know what's happening" and finally to "Your baby isn't there anymore" are brutal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first found out Lauren was pregnant, we had to allow ourselves some time to grieve. Not to grieve the new life we created, but to grieve the loss of our plans for the next couple of years. This wasn't supposed to happen yet. I wanted to get a dog first. But that very quickly changed to excitement (and then quickly back and forth between fear and excitement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctors told us that this isn't uncommon, and happens more than 20% of the time. Usually it happens because of severe genetic defects, and the body stops the pregnancy before it gets going. I have to marvel at the wonder of God's creation. That He makes our bodies stop these things when He has to, to prevent pain and grief down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, I have to think about the babies born with various defects and disease. We may question why God would put those babies and families through that. But God keeps those babies going because he knows they are strong enough and their purpose important enough to bring them into this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are so thankful to the close friends and family who were around to love and share this with us. While we're heartbroken, we're glad to have the opportunity to talk about something that just isn't talked about enough, failed pregnancy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was driven a bit mad even in the few shorts weeks we had that I couldn't tell people. I found the idea of waiting until you're far in and complication free absurd. And now, after this experience, I find it even more ridiculous. You're denying yourself the support and love of people around you. Is it uncomfortable telling people you lost your baby not long after you told them you were pregnant? Absolutely. But I'd take that every time over dealing with this fear and pain alone. Having to tell my parents, "oh by the way, we were going to have a baby, but we had a miscarriage" was way worse than if they had been there through the whole experience. I'm SO thankful for the people close to us in Orlando who we told and were there to support us through every scary moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This child was created in passion, when... certain precautions weren't taken (ew.. sex.. right?). Before the miscarriage, I'd had a dream that we had a girl, and that's as good as anything to go on, right? We wanted to memorialize her, so we named her Emma. One of Lauren's supervisors at school said that she must be a full and passionate woman with God now. That is a thrilling thing to think about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't wait to meet you one day, Emma.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>556372685</id><title>Game of Thrones Cover</title><updated>2014-06-17T18:32:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Incredible cover of the Game of Thrones theme.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1934941870</id><title>To Teachers</title><updated>2014-06-17T10:39:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes to everything here. My sister is a teacher and I'm incredibly proud of her. Teachers are overworked and underpaid.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3318114959</id><title>Filling a Notebook</title><updated>2014-06-16T08:55:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been using the &lt;a href="http://bulletjournal.com"&gt;Bullet Journal&lt;/a&gt; method for managing my tasks and notes. As much as I &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; a digital, cloud based task manager to be my go to, there's just something about putting a pen to paper that sticks better with me. I suspect it has to do with growing up in a world where I had to write something down to record it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to use it more to record thoughts, so that I could write more and better. I often find that the little nugget that was in my head disappears so quickly into an abyss of thoughts and memories.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>498127976</id><title>Do More of This Stuff</title><updated>2014-06-16T08:51:59.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A good list of things to do more of, and some things to do less of.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1881301065</id><title>Reading With Intention</title><updated>2014-06-10T08:44:40.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chris Bowler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Take time to read, re-read, and meditate on this piece of human thought you've chosen to ingest. Truly ingest it; if it resonates with you, allow it to change you. This is what I want to do with Scripture, but also any topic that I enjoy; web design, typography, woodworking … you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great stuff in regards to scripture reading and all other reading.  With both I tend to find myself reading to get it done. I don't take time and really think about what I'm reading. I just want to quickly absorb the facts. It translates straight into my writing here as well. I see a thing I want to share and I just share it without any thoughtful commentary.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2626578561</id><title>Judge John Hodgman Ep. 161: Cold Case</title><updated>2014-06-10T08:35:46.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you aren't listening to John Hodgman's podcast, you're really missing out. Basically he acts as judge in an argument between couples, friends, and families. They present their cases and he rules. Hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this particularly hilarious episode, a couple debates whether they need to add air conditioning to their apartment in Berlin. We learn about Germans' fear of drafts and the wonder that is the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tropical_Islands_Resort"&gt;Tropical Islands Resort&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3259870250</id><title>Listen</title><updated>2014-06-05T23:25:19.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Defending ourselves is always easier than listening to difficult truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurate. It's the natural reaction and it's so incredibly destructive.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>450911202</id><title>The Alton Browncast: Andrew Zimmern</title><updated>2014-06-05T23:22:01.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just an incredible listen. I've always loved &lt;a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/bizarre-foods"&gt;Bizarre Foods&lt;/a&gt;, but I never knew Andrew Zimmern's story. I can't remember the exact quote, but he said something like "I'll never start a business venture without a charitable component". A fantastic way to do things.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>348076043</id><title>John Oliver on 'Preventing Cable Company F&amp;%kery'</title><updated>2014-06-04T07:39:08.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brilliant. Hilarious. It would be funnier if it weren't so true...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>192160740</id><title>Servant Leadership</title><updated>2014-05-30T18:22:22.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chris Bowler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the truth is, you (and I) can adopt a servant leader mentality no matter what position we're in. Doing everything you can to ensure your coworkers succeed is the best habit we can all adopt. You may not be setting the vision for your company or assigning work, but you can put energy into making your teammates the best they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some great advice on leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1575333829</id><title>The Pastry Box</title><updated>2014-05-30T18:21:35.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whenever I fret and flail (frequently) while trying to create thing, I say to myself “Someone has to be the shittiest writer in the world but while there are people who still get paid to make up horoscopes, it won’t be me.” Then I write. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>466895661</id><title>Reeder 2 for Mac</title><updated>2014-05-29T11:23:14.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm tempted to be cheap and whine about having to pay more since I bought Reeder (this is what the App Store economy has done to us). This is the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; RSS app for Mac and I use it on a daily basis. Silvio Rizzi has put in the work to create a &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; application, which is not easy to do on the Mac. He deserves to get paid. Honestly he could charge twice as much and I'd still happily pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4276602636</id><title>The Right Way To Copy</title><updated>2014-05-24T07:21:11.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;David Smith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good copying learns from another’s innovation and then applies it in a novel way to a new context in a way that doesn’t diminish the source invention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good stuff. This is something that has been on my mind as I've been working on an iOS game in my spare time. It's inspired by some of my favorite games, but it's also unique. Sometimes it's hard not to feel like people will look at it and say he just ripped this or that off another game. He is invalid. David Smith explains how you can take cues without 'ripping off'.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>244595297</id><title>Chained Wimbledon: The Joys and Perils of Prison Tennis</title><updated>2014-05-21T08:54:46.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The class perception of tennis is both fascinating and depressing. There are a large number of great athletes that miss out on tennis because of that perception.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3228637935</id><title>If Internet Providers Ran Public Services</title><updated>2014-05-16T09:54:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Funny and depressing.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2743377614</id><title>The Competitive-Balance Argument Against Paying Atheletes is Bullshit</title><updated>2014-05-15T15:10:43.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As expected, a rigorous statistical analysis confirms what every fan of any powerhouse team already knew: Teams with recruiting success tend to remain successful year after year and teams without much success tend to remain unsuccessful. Fixing the price of a year of a college athlete's service to be comparable across all schools does not result in anything like competitive balance, and statistically, the level of imbalance has been growing over the last six years. It's time to stop using that as an excuse why college football should be allowed to collude its way out of paying market rates for talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the powerhouse schools are successful because they spend so much more money on recruiting and facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But how would things look under a pay-for-play model? Would the imbalance actually get worse?&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe not. If anything, the economics of price competition argue that as you let schools use money directly as a tool in attracting talent, you may empower mid-level schools to splurge on a would-be starter who might otherwise accept an offer at a top-tier school and end up riding the bench. When stars and benchwarmers all get the same compensation package, there's no way for a smaller school to show they really want a player much more than the big school, which is free to stockpile talent. Both schools can claim they want the player, both can send 700 letters in one day, etc. The best way to show you mean business and that the other school is just engaging in what economists call "cheap talk" is price competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Andy Schwarz being insightful and on point. Remember this stuff next time someone argues that paying players would be unfair or that if players get paid, they all have to get the same stipend.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1791824041</id><title>Johnny Express</title><updated>2014-05-12T17:43:22.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short of the Week is one of my new favorite sites. Definitely worth checking out to if you like video shorts (I only subscribe to the &lt;a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/category/style/3d-animation/"&gt;3D Animated feed&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is hilariously terrifying. I've got the worst attention span, so when a video makes me stop checking the time to see when it ends, I know it's captured me.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1306563720</id><title>How Athletic Departments (And The Media) Fudge The Cost Of Scholarships</title><updated>2014-05-09T20:35:16.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The usual brilliance from Andy Schwarz.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>258599019</id><title>'Authors Should Just Write' - Or, Maybe They Shouldn't</title><updated>2014-05-08T11:34:13.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rhone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A reminder that, in order to be better writers, we must be better observers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I need to keep better in the front of my mind. It always feels like my writing is directly correlated with my reading. And my reading tends to be impatient and sometimes thoughtless.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4068305994</id><title>Kevin Durant Wins NBA MVP</title><updated>2014-05-07T08:21:45.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As if I didn't already have a huge man crush on Kevin Durant, this MVP speech is unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1485856805</id><title>B.S. Report - Chuck Klosterman 5/1/14</title><updated>2014-05-02T12:50:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Really thoughtful conversation between Bill Simmons and Chuck Klosterman. Near the end they really hit on what is SCARY about this situation. The ability for an internet mob to mobilize.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1000596484</id><title>Help Preserve Net Neutrality</title><updated>2014-04-27T20:11:51.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href="https://petitions.whitehouse.gov/petition/maintain-true-net-neutrality-protect-freedom-information-united-states/9sxxdBgy"&gt;White House petition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.savetheinternet.com/sti-home"&gt;petition&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by the Free Press.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>14474346</id><title>Pen and Paper</title><updated>2014-04-27T20:08:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love this post from Chris Bowler. In the past 6-ish months, I've found myself in a similar mode. I've always wanted my task list to be digital. I've wanted it available on all of my various platforms synced through the cloud. For a while, I was an avid &lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com"&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt; user. I've also experimented with &lt;a href="http://trello.com"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; (I still use it as sort of a long term "issue tracker").&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But late last year, when I discovered the &lt;a href="http://bulletjournal.com"&gt;Bullet Journal&lt;/a&gt; system, I decided to dive in. There's just something about picking up a pen and writing physically that connects with my brain more. I more like I know what I have to do, and I feel more accomplished when I can check something off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't subscribe religiously to every little bit, but I think you have to find what works for you. I'd like to put more notes and events in to log myself. I've also been playing a bit with the Omnifocus 2 beta for keeping track of longer term tasks. But for managing my day to day, having a pen and a notebook has been fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1397647435</id><title>The FCC Continues to Suck</title><updated>2014-04-23T19:36:19.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The original story is &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/technology/fcc-new-net-neutrality-rules.html?_r=1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Linking to Gruber because he links to an Obama quote. This was one thing I thought Obama would nail, and this administration has &lt;strong&gt;completely&lt;/strong&gt; failed us. The FCC is trying to destroy the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2924344039</id><title>Vox: Why the government should provide internet access</title><updated>2014-04-23T09:58:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm far from a supporter of too much government, but the internet is one of those world changing things that requires an exception.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3646842152</id><title>Wish I Was Here</title><updated>2014-04-21T18:06:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Can't wait for this movie. I contributed to the &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869987317/wish-i-was-here-1"&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; in a heartbeat.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>735047945</id><title>The Foodroom</title><updated>2014-04-16T10:56:31.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fantastic. Man I love me some Josh Charles.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3081194990</id><title>Grand Budapest Hotel</title><updated>2014-04-16T10:54:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cool look at how the hotel set was constructed.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>169400783</id><title>The "Like" Drug</title><updated>2014-04-14T10:02:45.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've listened to this podcast and then watched the video. It was so good I had to hear it twice. I'd never heard most of these guys before, but I immediately went and followed them on Twitter and on their blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do yourself a favor. Take an hour and watch.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2418595500</id><title>Mozilla's Gay-Marriage Litmus Test Violates Liberal Values</title><updated>2014-04-11T12:21:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Good gosh this whole article. Especially love this bit...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I've had many occasions to observe that an individual's position on the policy question turns out to be a flawed proxy for his or her attitude toward gays and lesbians. Gay-marriage supporters may have been more likely to be tolerant of gays. But I encountered people who'd say things like, "Look, I don't want gays looking at me in the shower at the gym, but why should I care if they want to marry each other?" And I also encountered gay-marriage opponents who were, apart from opposing marriage equality, model parents to gay sons or daughters, exceptionally supportive to gay friends, and wonderful bosses to gay subordinates. This will seem perfectly rational to some readers and weirdly inconsistent to others. (For the latter, note that people are often weirdly inconsistent.)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3801768589</id><title>Jon Stewart on the NCAA</title><updated>2014-04-11T10:05:52.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just watch the clips and enjoy Jon Stewart make Mark Emmert look like a child who doesn't want to share.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1033435490</id><title>Patrick Stewart and Ian McKellen Are New York's Best Tourists</title><updated>2014-04-08T09:13:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Where is the reality show where we just follow these two guys around.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2416608579</id><title>Patents Suck</title><updated>2014-04-08T09:13:07.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marco Arment: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The idea of the patent system is sold to gullible people as a necessary protector of small inventors — which is a nice fairy tale, and nothing more — and it reinforces the destructive but all-too-common fallacy that great ideas are rare, novel, unique, and immediately so valuable that simply having a great idea will suddenly cause somebody, somewhere, somehow to make you rich and you’ll never have any problems again.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;We therefore value ideas above their execution, and that’s exactly how the patent system is designed, despite history showing that good execution is far more important and provides far more value to society in almost every instance regardless of who filed the first patent on the underlying idea. (Not to mention the value to society of a vibrant market of diverse, competing alternatives.)&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Like most laws and policies that chiefly benefit lawyers and big business, our voters, lobbyists, and politicians will keep supporting the patent fairy tale indefinitely as the rest of us get taxed, shaken down, or bankrupted by its reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1308170411</id><title>Monument Valley</title><updated>2014-04-04T20:40:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beautiful game. Beautiful sound. Incredibly inventive gameplay. It doesn't take long to beat, but I can't tell you how many times I said "WOW THAT'S SO COOL" while playing. Absolutely worth the small price.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>822910090</id><title>The Hounding of a Heretic</title><updated>2014-04-04T20:37:57.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andrew Sullivan has pretty much &lt;a href="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/04/03/the-hounding-of-brendan-eich/"&gt;nailed&lt;/a&gt; what &lt;a href="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/04/03/the-hounding-of-a-heretic-ctd/"&gt;bothers&lt;/a&gt; me about &lt;a href="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/04/04/dissents-of-the-day-63/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; whole Brendan Eich firestorm.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>645570921</id><title>Beautiful Death</title><updated>2014-04-04T20:36:10.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cool way to countdown to the Game of Thrones premiere.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>160310600</id><title>Banned For Life</title><updated>2014-04-04T20:07:25.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sounds like my experience selling on Amazon. A shipping mishap (USPS paid on my insurance because they lost the item) and an unappeasable customer left me banned forever.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>79923759</id><title>How presidential elections are impacted by a 100 million year old coastline</title><updated>2014-03-28T16:36:53.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm no scientist, but this is fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3889630734</id><title>Chris Coyier one on one with his hacker</title><updated>2014-03-25T19:19:42.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Really fascinating. Kudos to Chris Coyier for having the patience to sit down and have this conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's really terrifying what people can do to you on the internet, and how frequently the weaknesses come from people at the companies you trust your information to. It's &lt;strong&gt;ridiculous&lt;/strong&gt; that someone can call in, say the right piece of software's name, and get your social security number. There have to be more thorough security measures for these companies spreading this information, even from one employee to another.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2208625518</id><title>The Moment with Brian Koppelman: Chris Fowler</title><updated>2014-03-25T18:53:44.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was really thrilled when I saw Chris was appearing on The Moment. Firstly, because it has become one of my favorite podcasts. Brian Koppelman talks to people through the lens of some moment in their lives. Some make or break point in time that really changes their path. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, because Chris Fowler is one of my favorite people on TV with the most incredible job. He gets to travel to the best football games and follow the great tennis players around the world. And covers them all so well.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3712291565</id><title>Sweet 16</title><updated>2014-03-25T18:47:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've got several links and a few things to say about the Vols advancing to the Sweet 16. First off, I'm &lt;strong&gt;pumped&lt;/strong&gt;. These players have all worked hard and deserve it. I loved seeing the energy we saw from Cuonzo Martin. I feel like we know him a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's a bit from an &lt;a href="http://www.footballtime.com/2014/03/24/open-letter-cuonzo-martin/"&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; to Cuonzo Martin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We were blind to the type of leader you are. We were blind to the love your players have for you. We ignored the quiet work you do in the community—work you do because you care, not because you want to draw attention to yourself. We were blind to your growth as a coach and to your potential.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Yet, here you are in the Sweet 16 leading a team that might be the best story of the tournament. Here you are leading a group of young men who blocked out all our chatter, backed you, and embraced your coaching. You deserve a tremendous amount of credit for keeping this team together. Many coaches would have lost them when the criticism reached deafening levels, but not you. Instead, you got them playing together at just the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great stuff and it's absolutely true. I was someone who was salivating over the idea of &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/02/25/bruce-pearl/"&gt;Bruce Pearl coming back&lt;/a&gt;. It wasn't really fair to Cuonzo Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some thoughts from &lt;a href="http://www.tnsportsradio.com/2014/03/24/vol-nation-united-stand/"&gt;Tennessee Sports Radio&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Before this season, Martin had never led the Vols to the NCAA Tournament. That’s a fail, folks, and one need look no further than to Bruce Pearl’s six-year tenure as the Vols’ head coach for confirmation of such. A stretch during which the Tennessee Volunteers punched their ticket to the dance every single season. Three times they danced all the way to the Sweet 16, one of those tangos evolving into the program’s first and only Elite 8 appearance ever. Thanks to Bruce Pearl, NCAA Tournament appearances are now expected in Knoxville. And rightly so.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Which is why Cuonzo Martin came under ever increasing scrutiny this season. For he entered it 0-2 in the only stat that mattered. NCAA Tournament berths...&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Therefore, many in Vol Nation believed Cuonzo Martin was a horrible coach. Bruce Pearl was a great one whose show-cause was just about to end. So 36,000 members of Vol Nation signed on the dotted virtual line and made it official. Time for the great coach to replace the horrible one.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The only problem with that is that Cuonzo Martin isn’t a horrible coach. Don’t get me wrong. He certainly hadn’t proven he was a great one. Not by any stretch. A great coach doesn’t put forth a team which underachieves as often as Martin’s team did this year. But calling Martin a horrible coach isn’t accurate, either. A horrible coach doesn’t win 60-plus games in three seasons. A horrible coach doesn’t land five-star recruits like Robert Hubbs III. A horrible coach doesn’t keep a team together when 36,000 fans have officially called for his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team looked &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different a month ago. There wasn't much they'd done to give us reason to expect they would play like this. Not consistently. I don't think at that time you were wrong to think, maybe it's time for a change back to Bruce Pearl. But this is why you wait until the &lt;em&gt;end&lt;/em&gt; of the season to make decisions like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have confess to being swayed by the show that is Bruce Pearl. He's enthusiastic. He paints his chest. He makes jokes about bacon. He promises to kick Florida's ass, and delivers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuonzo is a quiet guy. He doesn't say more than he needs to. And I absolutely faulted him for that which is unfair. You don't have to make a show of yourself to be a great coach (see: pretty much every other great coach). And we've always known he's a great man. That's why we followed up a coach who made questionable decisions with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuonzo still has a lot to prove. But he's at the very least proven he can make a sweet 16. He's got a good chance to do more than that. He's going to have a challenge ahead next year, but he's earned the security to show us what else he has up his sleeve. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3227031244</id><title>NCAA Mascot Tournament</title><updated>2014-03-20T10:20:59.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While most will be filling out their bracket the old fashioned way, closing your eyes and pointing a finger. But, I like to make my decisions based on mascots. Now this isn't your run of the mill &lt;em&gt;Which mascot would win in a fight&lt;/em&gt; contest. I will, in a 100% subjective manner, decide which mascot is cooler. Let's not dally any longer...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="firstround"&gt;First Round&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="south"&gt;South&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Florida Gators v. (16) Albany Great Danes&lt;/strong&gt; - I give a lot of respect to straying from the typical dog breed. The only better breed Albany could have chosen was the Saint Bernard. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Albany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(8) Colorado Buffaloes v. (9) Pittsburgh Panthers&lt;/strong&gt; - No one is winning &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; games with a mascot like "Panthers". Unless they're playing another team with the same mascot and I like them better than that team. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Colorado&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5) VCU Rams v. (12) Stephen F. Austin Lumberjacks&lt;/strong&gt; - Come on. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: SF Austin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(4) UCLA Bruins v. (13) Tulsa Golden Hurricane&lt;/strong&gt; - UCLA gets credit for being Bears without actually calling themselves bears. Plus Bears are to be &lt;a href="http://www.colbertnation.com/the-colbert-report-videos/210979/december-01-2008/exclusive---godless-killing-machines-mash-up"&gt;feared&lt;/a&gt;. And there's nothing cool about hurricanes. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: UCLA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(6) Ohio State Buckeyes v. (11) Dayton Flyers&lt;/strong&gt; - When I hear the Flyers nickname, all I can think of is the Sandlot. And that's a win. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Dayton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3) Syracuse Orange v. (14) Western Michigan Broncos&lt;/strong&gt; - There's nothing cool about Broncos right now. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Syracuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(7) New Mexico Lobos v. (10) Stanford Cardinal&lt;/strong&gt; - I don't know what a Lobo is, but Cardinal? Singular? And the tree? &lt;strong&gt;Winner: New Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) Kansas Jayhawks v. (15) E. Kentucky Colonels&lt;/strong&gt; - Military mascots are cool. Birds are not. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: EKU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="east"&gt;East&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Virgina Cavaliers v. (16) Coastal Carolina Chanticleers&lt;/strong&gt; - Yeah. This goes against previous logic, but I can't stop saying Chanticleer. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Coastal Carolina&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(8) Memphis Tigers v. (9) George Washington Colonials&lt;/strong&gt; - Tigers don't win. Plus, Memphis. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: George Washington&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5) Cincinnati Bearcats v. (12) Harvard Crimson&lt;/strong&gt; - I have a soft spot in my heart for things that are half bear and half cat. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Cincinnati&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(4) Michigan State Spartans v. (13) Delaware Fightin' Blue Hens&lt;/strong&gt; - Maybe if they were regular hens. But Blue hens? No. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Michigan State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(6) North Carolina Tar Heels v. (11) Providence Friars&lt;/strong&gt; - You just don't mess with God. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Providence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3) Iowa State Cyclones v. (14) NC Central Eagles&lt;/strong&gt; - Fly Eagles Fly. Also, once again, weather patterns aren't cutting it. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: NC Central&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(7) Connecticut Huskies v. (10) St. Joe's Hawks&lt;/strong&gt; - Weak first round matchup. I wish I could pick neither. But I really do like actual huskies. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Connecticut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) Villanova Wildcats v. (15) Milwaukee Panthers&lt;/strong&gt; - Another bad first round matchup. I'm picking based on my desire for this bracket to not suck. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Villanova&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="west"&gt;West&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Arizona Wildcats v. (16) Weber State Wildcats&lt;/strong&gt; - One of two all wildcat match ups. What a bummer. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Arizona&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(8) Gonzaga Bulldogs v. (9) Oklahoma State Cowboys&lt;/strong&gt; - I hate the &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/82637574"&gt;Cowboys&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Gonzaga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5) Oklahoma Sooners v. (12) ND State Bison&lt;/strong&gt; - There's just something cool about Bison. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: ND State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(4) San Diego State Aztecs v. (13) New Mexico State Aggies&lt;/strong&gt; - There are too many Aggies and not enough Aztecs in college sports. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: San Diego State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5) Baylor Bears v. (12) Nebraska Cornhuskers&lt;/strong&gt; - See previous matchup with a bear related mascot. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Baylor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3) Creighton Blue Jays v. (14) LA-Lafayette Ragin' Cajuns&lt;/strong&gt; - This one isn't even close. Cajuns, when they're a-ragin' can't be beat. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: LA-Lafayette&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(7) Oregon Ducks v. (10) BYU Cougars&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5uIfRUV_XV0"&gt;Puddles&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Oregon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) Wisconsin Badgers v. (15) American Eagles&lt;/strong&gt; - I'm tempted not to give American a pass. Their full name sounds a bit... douchey. But... Eagles. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: American&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="midwest"&gt;Midwest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Wichita State Shockers v. (16) Cal Poly Mustangs&lt;/strong&gt; - Their mascot is the SHOCKERS. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Wichita State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(8) Kentucky Wildcats v. (9) Kansas State Wildcats&lt;/strong&gt; - Another crummy wildcat matchup. I'll never pick John Calipari. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Kansas State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5) St. Louis Bilikens v. (12) NC State Wolfpack&lt;/strong&gt; - I'm concerned about the repercussions of picking against the Biliken. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: St. Louis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(4) Louisville Cardinals v. (13) Manhattan Jaspers&lt;/strong&gt; - I don't know what a Jasper is, but it has to beat a Cardinal. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Manhattan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(6) UMass Minutemen v. (11) Tennessee Volunteers&lt;/strong&gt; - It's hard to pick against the Minutemen. But... Volunteers? They do it for free. I'm COMPLETELY objective here. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Tennessee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3) Duke Blue Devils v. (14) Mercer Bears&lt;/strong&gt; - THERE ARE A LOT OF BEARS IN THIS TOURNAMENT. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Mercer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(7) Texas Longhorns v. (10) Arizona State Sun Devils&lt;/strong&gt; - Not a fan of the longhorns, but I can't pick devils. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Texas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) Michigan Wolverines v. (15) Wofford Terriers&lt;/strong&gt; - This is an example of picking an alternate dog, and going the wrong way. &lt;strong&gt;Winner: Michigan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2327131555</id><title>The NCAA-Killing Lawsuit Might Finally Be Here</title><updated>2014-03-19T20:48:36.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sports labor attorney Jeffrey Kessler has filed suit against the NCAA and five power conferences, alleging that capping player compensation at the cost of a scholarship is an antitrust violation. Unlike previous suits, this one does not seek damages. It wants to tear down the NCAA. "We're looking to change the system," Kessler said. "That's the main goal."&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Kessler is the biggest hitter yet in the war against amateurism. He's partially responsible for bringing free agency to the NFL, and has served as outside counsel for both MLB and NBA players in labor battles against their respective leagues. He's joined in this suit by Tim Nevius, once the NCAA's associate director of enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One step closer to a new age in college sports.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1841871234</id><title>The Walking Dead trades cheap scares for a brutal, gut-wrenching shock</title><updated>2014-03-18T10:45:19.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This episode of Walking Dead might have been the best hour of television I've watched this year, which is an accomplishment considering... True Detective. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING: POSSIBLE SPOILER AHEAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It's brutal, and TWD neither flinches from it nor sensationalizes it. It is just a stark, gut-wrenching moment that offers no visceral entertainment, just a horrible feeling in the pit in your stomach that forces you to wonder how this awfulness could have been avoided, and whether it could be at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was &lt;em&gt;brutal&lt;/em&gt;, but you felt like it had to be done, which is such an unsettling feeling. It's a feeling that The Walking Dead really assaults you with. You're constantly torn between the morality you know and the new morality of the world the characters inhabit. No one has had to shift their morality more than Carol, and it's been almost chilling to see how pragmatically she's gone about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So let's take one moment to add Chad Coleman and Melissa McBride to The Walking Dead actors who are knocking it out of the goddamn park the second half of this season. Carol's tough exterior cracks and breaks down as Lizzie gets more and more fucked up; and the scene where Tyreese forgives Carol is, by itself, as good as any performance on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This this this. Mika's death and the subsequent dispatching of Lizzie were brutal, but that scene between Carol and Tyreese was unbelievable. That's what almost brought me to tears. The grace Tyreese showed her was just... damn.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3179814470</id><title>NCAA bracket predictions 2014: Choosing the winners by alphabetical order</title><updated>2014-03-17T21:14:18.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Jon Bois:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(15) American over (2) Wisconsin&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;This is an easy one. It wouldn't be appropriate to call this an "upset," really, since a) the committee that assigned the seeding of this tournament abided by a set of criteria completely unlike mine, and b) it's rather easy, from the outset, to take a glance at a matchup and immediately determine which ranks higher alphabetically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2597270760</id><title>OneNote for Mac</title><updated>2014-03-17T21:06:44.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I would have been so excited about this 4 years ago. Now it's just too little too late. I always preferred the OneNote editor to the Evernote version, but I'm way too invested in Evernote to look back now. It's where I save everything I want to be able to search for later. I stopped wasting my time labeling emails and being tied to Gmail when I realized I could just save anything I wanted to keep to Evernote and have offline access to it whenever I needed.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2758350628</id><title>Art of the Title: Lego Movie</title><updated>2014-03-17T09:25:03.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great look into the awesome ending credits sequence for the Lego Movie. The entire thing was done in stop motion which is mind blowing. I was amazed when I saw it in the theater, and I just assumed it was CGI.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3980443849</id><title>My Morning Routine</title><updated>2014-03-15T12:11:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm really loving this site. Really simple. They just ask people a few questions about their morning routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morning is by far my favorite part of the day, so I love learning how other people get their days started.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1064045738</id><title>Telecom Giants Drag Their Feet on Broadband for the Whole Country</title><updated>2014-03-15T11:51:06.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2010, the Federal Communications Commission announced the National Broadband Plan, which promised to provide 100 million American households with high-speed cable by 2020. Verizon has been expanding FiOS in major markets, and AT&amp;amp;T has been expanding its U-verse service. And now, instead of spending that war chest digging up streets and laying fiber cable, the cable and telephone companies have invested in a massive and very successful lobbying push. They are persuading state legislatures and regulatory boards to quietly adopt new rules—rules written by the telecoms—to eliminate their legal obligations to provide broadband service nationwide and replace landlines with wireless. This abrupt change in plans will leave vast areas of the country with poor service, slow telecommunications and higher bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just messed up. More bad news for the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2447218827</id><title>On the Taxation of College Sports</title><updated>2014-03-10T09:32:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sportsgeekonomics tears down another argument against paying college athletes. This time it's the concern that athletic department income will become taxable and schools might lose their nonprofit status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You hear that Mr. Andersen? That's the sound of inevitability.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1369024108</id><title>The Internet is Fucked</title><updated>2014-03-10T09:07:28.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nilay Patel: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What happens in countries where there’s real competition? In the UK, where incumbent provider BT is required to allow competitors to use its wired broadband network, home internet service prices are as low as £2.50 a month, or just over $4. In South Korea, where wireless giants SK Telecom and LG Uplus are locked in a fierce technology battle, customers have access to the fastest mobile networks in the world — up to 300Mbps, compared to a theoretical max of 80Mbps on Verizon that’s actually more like 15 or 20mbps in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;And Americans pay more for these slower wireless speeds than anyone else in the world: in Germany, where customers can freely switch between carriers by swapping SIM cards, T-Mobile customers pay just $1.18 per Mbps of speed. In the US, our mostly incompatible wireless networks lock customers in with expensive handsets they can’t take elsewhere, allowing AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon to charge around $4 per Mbps each and Sprint to clock in at an insane $7.50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those two paragraphs are so depressing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So there’s the entire problem, expressed in four simple ideas: the internet is a utility, there is zero meaningful competition to provide that utility to Americans, all internet providers should be treated equally, and the FCC is doing a miserably ineffective job. The United States should lead the world in broadband deployment and speeds: we should have the lowest prices, the best service, and the most competition. We should have the freest speech and the loudest voices, the best debate and the soundest policy. We are home to the most innovative technology companies in the world, and we should have the broadband networks to match.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;We should stop fucking it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do something, email the FCC chair at tom.wheeler@fcc.com and call 1-888-225-5322. Calls to your &lt;a href="http://www.house.gov/representatives/find/"&gt;representatives&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.senate.gov/general/contact_information/senators_cfm.cfm"&gt;senators&lt;/a&gt; are always good too.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2752197197</id><title>P.S. Hoffman (A Tribute)</title><updated>2014-03-05T22:54:50.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A tribute to Philip Seymour Hoffman. Incredibly well done.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>4130766382</id><title>Say Something</title><updated>2014-03-04T23:20:13.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or stop talking and watch this video.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1218972175</id><title>CarPlay Powered by Blackberry</title><updated>2014-03-04T23:15:46.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;BGR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BlackBerry’s QNX platform is the base on which the BlackBerry 10 operating system is built, but it’s also much more than that. Before it was morphed into smartphone software, QNX was an in-car operating system that powered infotainment systems in a wide range of vehicles. It still is, and as N4BB confirmed on Tuesday, it’s also the foundation for Apple’s new CarPlay product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing that the value for QNX may not come from Blackberry mobile devices, but from being the go to in-car operating system. Add this onto news that Ford Sync is &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-22/ford-said-to-swap-blackberry-s-qnx-for-microsoft-in-sync-system.html"&gt;planning to drop&lt;/a&gt; Microsoft for QNX, and it looks like Blackberry is building itself a nice little niche, though I'm not sure how profitable it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never would have believed this a year or so ago, but is it possible that Blackberry could become an acquisition target for Apple?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3616231904</id><title>CarPlay</title><updated>2014-03-04T23:14:40.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Apple &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/03/03Apple-Rolls-Out-CarPlay-Giving-Drivers-a-Smarter-Safer-More-Fun-Way-to-Use-iPhone-in-the-Car.html"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; CarPlay, their solution for connecting your iPhone to your vehicle's stereo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought is damn that UI is beautiful. As someone who recently bought an aftermarket stereo, I can say that the makers of these things are stuck in the 90s when it comes to interface design. Even on touch screens the buttons are small, the designs are hideous, and UX is an afterthought. It will be interesting to see if this platform moves beyond built-in stereos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled that Apple is starting to dip it's toes into this space. I've always been a bit bearish on the phone as the hub for the car stereo, but I'm starting to rethink that.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>704437697</id><title>We Have Luxurious Jobs</title><updated>2014-03-03T20:59:27.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Gediminas Rapolavicius:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Posts about annoying, spammy recruiters and just not feeling like working, when working from home, are popular and regular on HackerNews, /r/programming. And I won’t deny, I do often agree on those topics.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The other day, I realised how messed up that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I forget how lucky I am to be in the profession I'm in with the skills I have.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3890966825</id><title>Please Don't Push Me</title><updated>2014-03-03T20:59:15.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;David Smith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have just sorted through the App Store and settled on trying out your app. I open it up and you immediately ask if you can send me Push Notifications? I have no context about what these are going to be used for or why they might be useful to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently got similar advice about my iPhone game. I'd never really thought twice about asking immediately, but it really is an annoying experience. I'm looking for a better time to ask for this than at launch. Possibly when you make your first move. I might even follow David's advice and make it something you explicitly enable.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>3405706504</id><title>The Effective Way to Ask for an App Review</title><updated>2014-02-27T22:33:16.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Supertop, makers of &lt;a href="http://castro.fm/"&gt;Castro&lt;/a&gt;, have been experimenting with prompting users to review the app in the release notes. And it's worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit I'm surprised by this. I'd expect few people see the release notes because of auto updating, and even fewer read them. Maybe it's more than I expect or maybe a high percentage of those who read them appreciate that prompt and leave a review.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2357741803</id><title>Reader Supported</title><updated>2014-02-26T17:38:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shawn Blanc is doing is annual membership drive. For just $4/mo you can support his writing and get members only access to his Shawn Today podcast. His writing is &lt;em&gt;absolutely&lt;/em&gt; worth supporting and I'm a happy paying member. I don't know him personally, but I'd like to as he seems like an awesome dude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read him, bump yourself up to membership level. If you don't, start now and I'm sure you'll be a member by the next drive.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>751925071</id><title>Roderick On the Line 98: A Mastiff of Spinach</title><updated>2014-02-26T09:19:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;John Roderick's account of his trip to a Miley Cyrus concert is both hilarious and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1872481482</id><title>After Years Away, Repentant Bruce Pearl Could Be Jewel for Tennessee</title><updated>2014-02-25T16:55:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gregg Doyel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If Tennessee has an opening, it should hire Bruce Pearl. Go ahead, Tennessee. He paid his price. You paid yours. Bruce Pearl is a good coach who made a bad mistake and had to be fired -- I was calling for his dismissal months before Tennessee finally did it -- but who served his time and surely, surely learned from his mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Bruce Pearl knew, regretted, and learned from his mistake &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; before he was fired. Still, my biggest concern is him lying about something so inconsequential.  I'm terrified that some other larger violation spurred him to cover up the visit to his home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here on the outside, the opinion is this: If Tennessee decides [Cuonzo] Martin isn't the right guy and is looking for a new coach in a month or so, the perfect coach to hire -- not a good coach, but the perfect coach -- still lives in the area and bleeds orange and calls the Volunteers "we."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I 100% agree with this. The weird thing about this is it almost felt inevitable three years ago. And as Bruce has stuck around Knoxville and continued to be so loved in the commmunity, it has felt more and more inevitable. Cuonzo Martin needed to win big to make people forget about Bruce and he hasn't done that. Three years of teams that have underachieved, played a boring brand of basketball, and lost just enough games to bad teams to keep them out of the dance have made people in Knoxville impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Pearl should be Tennessee's basketball coach. Given Cuonzo's quiet nature, it almost feels like he never left.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2662720173</id><title>Harold Ramis</title><updated>2014-02-25T09:33:00.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Harold Ramis &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/25/movies/harold-ramis-who-helped-redefine-what-makes-us-laugh-on-screen-dies-at-69.html?_r=0"&gt;passed away&lt;/a&gt; yesterday at the age of 69. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people will talk about Groundhog Day, Ghostbusters, and Caddyshack, but I will always remember him for &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/xR9HuRUUTbs"&gt;Stripes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>2177459852</id><title>Comcast hearts Netflix</title><updated>2014-02-23T15:36:02.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Comcast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Working collaboratively over many months, the companies have established a more direct connection between Netflix and Comcast, similar to other networks, that’s already delivering an even better user experience to consumers, while also allowing for future growth in Netflix traffic. Netflix receives no preferential network treatment under the multi-year agreement, terms of which are not being disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one hand it just sounds like a sort of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peering"&gt;peering agreement&lt;/a&gt; between the two companies (if we can trust the bit about "no preferential treatment"), but on the other it sounds sinister and frightening in regards to net neutrality. I don't think it's time to say the sky is falling as long as smaller companies can get fair network treatment. But gosh it makes me feel icky. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is something to be said for Netflix being a bit of a special case. It is responsible for a &lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57611722-93/netflix-youtube-gobble-up-half-of-internet-traffic/"&gt;huge amount&lt;/a&gt; of internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>1129495151</id><title>A Change</title><updated>2014-02-22T20:07:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've long wanted to do more with this blog. Having it on Tumblr has been fun, but it hasn't given me the control over my site and data like I want. It also hasn't lent itself to &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I've hit the reset button. I wanted to import all of my Tumblr posts here, but the value I would get out of having old posts wasn't worth the time I'd have to invest to write up the scripts I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've built my site using the static site generator &lt;a href="http://zespia.tw/hexo/"&gt;hexo&lt;/a&gt;. I looked at a couple of options, including &lt;a href="http://jekyllrb.com"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://wintersmith.io"&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;. But hexo gave me the node javascript environment I was looking for with easy deployment to Github pages. It also has a nice plugin framework should I ever need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I can write in whatever environment feels comfortable, save the markdown file to the proper Dropbox folder, and deploy to the site. I'm hoping this will spur me to write more. About tech. About life. About the things I'm working on. I hope to expand the site to have some places to share the writers I'm reading, the tools I'm using, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All feedback is welcome to my many social networking accounts or, via email, at imchrisbrakebill AT icloud DOT com.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>