<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-16T13:57:36.143Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[If Internet Providers Ran Public Services]]></title>
    <link href="http://theweek.com/cartoons/index/261623/editorial-cartoon-net-neutrality"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/16/if-internet-providers-ran-public-services/</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T13:54:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T13:54:39.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Funny and depressing.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Competitive-Balance Argument Against Paying Atheletes is Bullshit]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/the-competitive-balance-argument-against-paying-athlete-1576638830"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/15/the-competitivebalance-argument-against-paying-atheletes-is-bullshit/</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T19:10:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-15T19:10:43.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>As expected, a rigorous statistical analysis confirms what every fan of any powerhouse team already knew: Teams with recruiting success tend to remain successful year after year and teams without much success tend to remain unsuccessful. Fixing the price of a year of a college athlete’s service to be comparable across all schools does not result in anything like competitive balance, and statistically, the level of imbalance has been growing over the last six years. It’s time to stop using that as an excuse why college football should be allowed to collude its way out of paying market rates for talent.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It turns out the powerhouse schools are successful because they spend so much more money on recruiting and facilities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But how would things look under a pay-for-play model? Would the imbalance actually get worse?</p>
<p>Maybe not. If anything, the economics of price competition argue that as you let schools use money directly as a tool in attracting talent, you may empower mid-level schools to splurge on a would-be starter who might otherwise accept an offer at a top-tier school and end up riding the bench. When stars and benchwarmers all get the same compensation package, there’s no way for a smaller school to show they really want a player much more than the big school, which is free to stockpile talent. Both schools can claim they want the player, both can send 700 letters in one day, etc. The best way to show you mean business and that the other school is just engaging in what economists call “cheap talk” is price competition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>More Andy Schwarz being insightful and on point. Remember this stuff next time someone argues that paying players would be unfair or that if players get paid, they all have to get the same stipend.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Johnny Express]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/2014/05/12/johnnyexpress/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/12/johnny-express/</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T21:43:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T21:43:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Short of the Week is one of my new favorite sites. Definitely worth checking out to if you like video shorts (I only subscribe to the <a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/category/style/3d-animation/" target="_blank">3D Animated feed</a>).</p>
<p>This one is hilariously terrifying. I’ve got the worst attention span, so when a video makes me stop checking the time to see when it ends, I know it’s captured me.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How Athletic Departments (And The Media) Fudge The Cost Of Scholarships]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-1570827027"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/09/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-of-scholarships/</id>
    <published>2014-05-10T00:35:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-10T00:35:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The usual brilliance from Andy Schwarz.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA['Authors Should Just Write' - Or, Maybe They Shouldn't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecramped.com/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt-james-shelley/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/08/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt/</id>
    <published>2014-05-08T15:34:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-08T15:34:13.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Patrick Rhone:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A reminder that, in order to be better writers, we must be better observers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is something I need to keep better in the front of my mind. It always feels like my writing is directly correlated with my reading. And my reading tends to be impatient and sometimes thoughtless.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Kevin Durant Wins NBA MVP]]></title>
    <link href="http://espn.go.com/video/clip?id=10893208&ex_cid=sportscenter"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/07/kevin-durant-wins-nba-mvp/</id>
    <published>2014-05-07T12:21:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-07T12:21:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As if I didn’t already have a huge man crush on Kevin Durant, this MVP speech is unbelievable.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[B.S. Report - Chuck Klosterman 5/1/14]]></title>
    <link href="http://espn.go.com/espnradio/play?id=10870177"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/02/bs-report-chuck-klosterman-5114/</id>
    <published>2014-05-02T16:50:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-02T16:50:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really thoughtful conversation between Bill Simmons and Chuck Klosterman. Near the end they really hit on what is SCARY about this situation. The ability for an internet mob to mobilize.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Help Preserve Net Neutrality]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/help-preserve-net-neutrality/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/help-preserve-net-neutrality/</id>
    <published>2014-04-28T00:11:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-28T00:11:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a <a href="https://petitions.whitehouse.gov/petition/maintain-true-net-neutrality-protect-freedom-information-united-states/9sxxdBgy" target="_blank">White House petition</a> and <a href="http://www.savetheinternet.com/sti-home" target="_blank">petition</a> sponsored by the Free Press.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Pen and Paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/pen-and-paper"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/pen-and-paper/</id>
    <published>2014-04-28T00:08:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-28T00:08:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this post from Chris Bowler. In the past 6-ish months, I’ve found myself in a similar mode. I’ve always wanted my task list to be digital. I’ve wanted it available on all of my various platforms synced through the cloud. For a while, I was an avid <a href="http://culturedcode.com" target="_blank">Things</a> user. I’ve also experimented with <a href="http://trello.com" target="_blank">Trello</a> (I still use it as sort of a long term “issue tracker”).</p>
<p>But late last year, when I discovered the <a href="http://bulletjournal.com" target="_blank">Bullet Journal</a> system, I decided to dive in. There’s just something about picking up a pen and writing physically that connects with my brain more. I more like I know what I have to do, and I feel more accomplished when I can check something off. </p>
<p>I don’t subscribe religiously to every little bit, but I think you have to find what works for you. I’d like to put more notes and events in to log myself. I’ve also been playing a bit with the Omnifocus 2 beta for keeping track of longer term tasks. But for managing my day to day, having a pen and a notebook has been fantastic.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The FCC Continues to Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2014/04/23/fcc-net-neutrality"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/23/the-fcc-continues-to-suck/</id>
    <published>2014-04-23T23:36:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-23T23:36:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The original story is <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/technology/fcc-new-net-neutrality-rules.html?_r=1" target="_blank">here</a>. Linking to Gruber because he links to an Obama quote. This was one thing I thought Obama would nail, and this administration has <strong>completely</strong> failed us. The FCC is trying to destroy the internet.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Vox: Why the government should provide internet access]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.vox.com/2014/4/6/5587138/susan-crawford-internet-public-option"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/23/vox_why_the_government_should_provide_internet_access/</id>
    <published>2014-04-23T13:58:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-23T13:58:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m far from a supporter of too much government, but the internet is one of those world changing things that requires an exception.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Wish I Was Here]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kw8VCDx399I&feature=youtu.be"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/21/wish-i-was-here/</id>
    <published>2014-04-21T22:06:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-21T22:06:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Can’t wait for this movie. I contributed to the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869987317/wish-i-was-here-1" target="_blank">Kickstarter</a> in a heartbeat.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Foodroom]]></title>
    <link href="http://gawker.com/amy-schumers-fast-food-aaron-sorkin-parody-is-spot-on-1563433408"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/16/the-foodroom/</id>
    <published>2014-04-16T14:56:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-16T14:56:31.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fantastic. Man I love me some Josh Charles.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Grand Budapest Hotel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.foxsearchlight.com/post/3943/the-grand-budapest-hotel-featurette-creating-a-hotel/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/16/grand-budapest-hotel/</id>
    <published>2014-04-16T14:54:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-16T14:54:48.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cool look at how the hotel set was constructed.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The "Like" Drug]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanwes.com/podcast/065-the-like-drug/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/14/the-like-drug/</id>
    <published>2014-04-14T14:02:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-14T14:02:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve listened to this podcast and then watched the video. It was so good I had to hear it twice. I’d never heard most of these guys before, but I immediately went and followed them on Twitter and on their blogs.</p>
<p>Do yourself a favor. Take an hour and watch.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Mozilla's Gay-Marriage Litmus Test Violates Liberal Values]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/04/mozillas-gay-marriage-litmus-test-violates-liberal-values/360156/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/11/mozillas-gaymarriage-litmus-test-violates-liberal-values/</id>
    <published>2014-04-11T16:21:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-11T16:21:21.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good gosh this whole article. Especially love this bit…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’ve had many occasions to observe that an individual’s position on the policy question turns out to be a flawed proxy for his or her attitude toward gays and lesbians. Gay-marriage supporters may have been more likely to be tolerant of gays. But I encountered people who’d say things like, “Look, I don’t want gays looking at me in the shower at the gym, but why should I care if they want to marry each other?” And I also encountered gay-marriage opponents who were, apart from opposing marriage equality, model parents to gay sons or daughters, exceptionally supportive to gay friends, and wonderful bosses to gay subordinates. This will seem perfectly rational to some readers and weirdly inconsistent to others. (For the latter, note that people are often weirdly inconsistent.)  </p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Jon Stewart on the NCAA]]></title>
    <link href="deadspin.com/the-daily-show-takes-down-the-ncaa-1562165262"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/11/jon-stewart-on-the-ncaa/</id>
    <published>2014-04-11T14:05:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-11T14:05:52.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just watch the clips and enjoy Jon Stewart make Mark Emmert look like a child who doesn’t want to share.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Patrick Stewart and Ian McKellen Are New York's Best Tourists]]></title>
    <link href="http://ift.tt/1hy11bT"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/08/patrick_stewart_and_ian_mckellen_are_new_york_s_best_tourists/</id>
    <published>2014-04-08T13:13:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-08T13:13:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seriously. Where is the reality show where we just follow these two guys around.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Patents Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.marco.org/2014/04/07/foss-patents-holy-war"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/08/Patents/</id>
    <published>2014-04-08T13:13:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-08T13:13:07.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>The idea of the patent system is sold to gullible people as a necessary protector of small inventors — which is a nice fairy tale, and nothing more — and it reinforces the destructive but all-too-common fallacy that great ideas are rare, novel, unique, and immediately so valuable that simply having a great idea will suddenly cause somebody, somewhere, somehow to make you rich and you’ll never have any problems again.</p>
<p>We therefore value ideas above their execution, and that’s exactly how the patent system is designed, despite history showing that good execution is far more important and provides far more value to society in almost every instance regardless of who filed the first patent on the underlying idea. (Not to mention the value to society of a vibrant market of diverse, competing alternatives.)</p>
<p>Like most laws and policies that chiefly benefit lawyers and big business, our voters, lobbyists, and politicians will keep supporting the patent fairy tale indefinitely as the rest of us get taxed, shaken down, or bankrupted by its reality.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Monument Valley]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.monumentvalleygame.com"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/04/monument-valley/</id>
    <published>2014-04-05T00:40:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-05T00:40:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful game. Beautiful sound. Incredibly inventive gameplay. It doesn’t take long to beat, but I can’t tell you how many times I said “WOW THAT’S SO COOL” while playing. Absolutely worth the small price.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
