<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-16T02:51:36.463Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Kids Menu]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/06/the-childrens-menu.html"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/15/the-kids-menu/</id>
    <published>2014-07-16T02:51:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-16T02:51:09.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seth Godin:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Of course, chicken fingers are just a symptom. If we want to insulate ourselves from new experiences, ensure that we never eat something we don’t like, never engage with someone we disagree with, never have to hold two opposing ideas in our head at the same time—chicken fingers are a great way to start.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a huge problem for me, for many reasons. The new means the unfamiliar. It means something I might not feel like I’m already competent at. And heaven forbid I do something I’m not already good at…</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/15/the-kids-menu/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[On the Shutdown of Lavabit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/may/20/why-did-lavabit-shut-down-snowden-email"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/15/lavabit/</id>
    <published>2014-07-16T02:49:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-16T02:49:56.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ladar Levison:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p> If we allow our government to continue operating in secret, it is only a matter of time before you or a loved one find yourself in a position like I did – standing in a secret courtroom, alone, and without any of the meaningful protections that were always supposed to be the people’s defense against an abuse of the state’s power.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Slow to post this, but it’s all kinds of terrifying.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/15/lavabit/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Full Time: Fading Images of the World Cup]]></title>
    <link href="http://grantland.com/the-triangle/full-time-fading-images-of-the-world-cup/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/full-time-fading-images-of-the-world-cup/</id>
    <published>2014-07-14T21:34:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T21:35:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Fantastic</em> writing from Brian Phillips. I’ll be honest I watched a maximum of 30 minutes of non-US soccer during the World Cup. Even then, I didn’t watch the Belgium game. Soccer isn’t my game, but I’ll do just about anything that let’s me drink and be patriotic.</p>
<p>That said, this is a fantastic commentary of the significance of sport. Or really the significance of how we watch them. Here’s the opening, no way you can read this and not read the article.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Watching sports is, among other things, a special way of experiencing time. Sport is like music or fiction or film in that, for a predetermined duration, it asks you to give it control over your emotions, to feel what it makes you feel. Unlike (most) forms of art, though, a game has no foreordained plan or plot or intention. The rules of a game impose a certain kind of order, but it’s different from the order of an artwork. A movie knows where it wants to take you; no one can say in advance where a game will go. All of its beauty, ugliness, boredom, and excitement, all of its rage and sadness emerge spontaneously out of the players’ competing desires to win. For however long the clock runs, your feelings are at the mercy of chance. This happens and then this happens and then this happens. You’re experiencing, in a contained and intensified way, something like the everyday movement of life.</p>
</blockquote>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/full-time-fading-images-of-the-world-cup/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[ESPN Fantasy Football]]></title>
    <link href="https://appsto.re/us/ifMgH.i"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/espn-fantasy-football/</id>
    <published>2014-07-14T18:53:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T18:53:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Get the new hotness. Positive reviews are welcome. If you want to be negative at least help us make it better. Among the new things to enjoy…</p>
<ul>
<li>FREE Alerts. You don’t have to be an Insider anymore.</li>
<li>Create a team or league right in the app</li>
<li>Pretty things</li>
</ul>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/espn-fantasy-football/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[JavaScript Fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/javascript-fun/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/14/javascript-fun/</id>
    <published>2014-07-14T13:14:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T13:14:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m trying to create a decently designed JavaScript function that, when passed a function, returns (you guessed it) a function that runs some authentication code before trying to execute the passed in function. So the return function would look something like this…</p>
<figure class="highlight javascript"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre>1
2
3
4
5
6
7
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span> <span class="title">createAuthedFunction</span><span class="params">()</span> {</span>
	<span class="keyword">return</span> <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span><span class="params">(variable, numberOf, params)</span> {</span>
		<span class="keyword">if</span>(checkAuth()) {
			callPassedInFunction(variable, numberOf, params);
		}
	}
}
</pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>Obviously I could just call checkAuth in every function that requires it, but that seems very non-<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don&#39;t_repeat_yourself" target="_blank">DRY</a> to me. What I’ve ended up going with is this:</p>
<figure class="highlight javascript"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre>1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span> <span class="title">checkAuthFunction</span><span class="params">(func, error)</span> {</span>
  <span class="keyword">return</span> <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span><span class="params">()</span> {</span>
		<span class="keyword">if</span> (checkAuth()) {
			func.apply(<span class="keyword">this</span>, <span class="built_in">arguments</span>);
		} <span class="keyword">else</span> {
			error = error || <span class="string">'You must be an admin to do that.'</span>;
			console.log(error)
		}
  }
}
</pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>Now when an object or function wants to create a method that requires authentication to run, it calls checkAuthFunction and passes in a function (and an optional error message) and this returns a function that checks for proper authentication, and either runs the function or outputs an error message, depending on authentication status. Function.apply allows me to call the passed in function with the current this value and the passed in arguments.</p>
<p>It’s working for now, but I’m still not in love with it syntactically.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[CBTextFieldView]]></title>
    <link href="https://github.com/braker1nine/CBTextFieldView"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/cbtextfieldview/</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T22:36:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T22:36:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a simple little view I created for textfield/label selection on OSX. Poorly documented, but available.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/cbtextfieldview/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[iPhone, phone home]]></title>
    <link href="https://medium.com/@saycreative/iphone-phone-home-cc3bcff73069"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/iphone-phone-home/</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T22:13:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T22:13:06.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tremendously cool concept to allow the return of lost iPhones to their owners.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/iphone-phone-home/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Great Discontent: Rogie King]]></title>
    <link href="http://thegreatdiscontent.com/rogie-king"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/the-great-discontent-rogie-king/</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T22:11:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T22:11:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes. This is over two years old. Yes. I have a huge man crush on Rogie King.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/10/the-great-discontent-rogie-king/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Facebook's Explanation: We Wanted to Make Sure You Weren't Turned Off By Facebook]]></title>
    <link href="https://brooksreview.net/2014/06/facebooks-explanation-we-wanted-to-make-sure-you-werent-turned-off-by-facebook/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/09/facebook-experiment/</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T02:04:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T02:04:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ben Brooks nails pretty much everything I wanted to say about this. My favorite bit from the Facebook explanation…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Nobody’s posts were “hidden,” they just didn’t show up on some loads of Feed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Oh. Okay.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/09/facebook-experiment/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How Are Apps Made]]></title>
    <link href="https://medium.com/message/how-are-apps-made-e9fe65448670"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/09/how-are-apps-made/</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T00:57:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T00:57:11.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Craig Mod:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>How are apps made? Painfully with deliberation or effortlessly without thought. Blind inspiration. Eight hours over a lazy weekend. Fifty grand a day. A million dollars a syllable. Do not look for the sense in it.</p>
</blockquote>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/09/how-are-apps-made/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Other Side of Empathy]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/nick-hehr/2014-july-5"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/08/the-other-side-of-empathy/</id>
    <published>2014-07-08T19:12:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-08T19:12:55.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nick Hehr:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>As designers and product builders, we are told to empathize with our users in order to create awesome experiences for the web and beyond. I propose we take a look at the other side of empathy, and make an effort to empathize with the creators behind the products, features, or designs triggering those rage-tweet reactions seen across many a timeline.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is something I’ve become a lot more aware of in the past couple of years. Working on a product that is used by millions of people, I know what it’s like to see people bashing what you’ve built. It sucks. I do my best to think before I tweet critically and angrily about a piece of software I’m using.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/08/the-other-side-of-empathy/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Persona]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/persona"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/07/persona/</id>
    <published>2014-07-07T21:54:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-07T21:54:29.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>When I was younger, it was easy to put people I looked up to on a pedestal. Bosses at work, pastors at church, my favourite bands. That is easy to do from afar, but the closer you get to people, the more you see the real person; the flaws, the hurting, and the mess as much as the good things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great stuff from Chris Bowler. We’re all just messy people.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/07/persona/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Jonathan Haidt can explain the liberal Hobby Lobby freak out]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.theamericanconservative.com/dreher/jonathan-haidt-can-explain-the-liberal-hobby-lobby-freakout/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/05/hobby-lobby/</id>
    <published>2014-07-06T00:47:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-06T00:48:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot to absorb here, but it’s something that I do feel like resonates with my experiences. Definitely worth a read. The end though is a bit disturbing:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet seeing the grotesque animosity towards people like me from liberals over the small-beer Hobby Lobby decision compels me to face up to the fact that the only political force standing between me, my church, and my community, and a State dominated by people who think we traditional church people are cretins who deserve to be pushed around, is Republicans.</p>
</blockquote>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/05/hobby-lobby/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Gunfighter]]></title>
    <link href="https://vimeo.com/79306807"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/28/the-gunfighter/</id>
    <published>2014-06-28T13:36:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-28T13:36:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great short film. Nick Offerman narrates and is hilarious as usual.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/28/the-gunfighter/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Universal Studios Interactive Wands]]></title>
    <link href="http://gizmodo.com/live-your-hogwarts-fantasies-with-universal-studios-int-1592078675"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/universal-studios-interactive-wands/</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T19:46:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T19:46:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dang. So cool.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/universal-studios-interactive-wands/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Martian: A Novel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00EMXBDMA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00EMXBDMA&linkCode=as2&tag=braonenin-20&linkId=ZIEJGBTQ4ROOEDNR"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/the-martian/</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T16:17:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T16:20:14.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just spent a couple of days reading this on vacation. Really fantastic book.</p>
<p>Long story short, an astronaut gets stranded on Mars. He engineers and potato farms to survive while NASA and his fellow astronauts try to figure out how to get him home.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/the-martian/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Fighting to Stay Creative]]></title>
    <link href="http://shawnblanc.net/2014/05/fighting-to-stay-creative/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/26/fighting-to-stay-creative/</id>
    <published>2014-06-26T12:02:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-26T12:02:21.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shawn Blanc:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We mustn’t be afraid of failing nor of being rejected, and we must place more value on the act of creating so we can find joy in the journey and develop a lifetime of experience in making things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Shawn has some <strong>great</strong> advice on creativity. I can feel every one of the stiflers of creativity that he mentions getting a foothold in my work. I’m going to try to be more intentional about keeping those things at bay.</p>
<p>Matt Gemmell <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/staying-creative/" target="_blank">adds</a>…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Creative people, in my experience, are plagued with doubt. This is awful! they all think, definitely including myself. It’s a very personal thing, and it’s insidious because you’re the only one who gets to see the first drafts, and the refinements, and whole, messy stop and start and double-back of producing something worthwhile. It’s hard to keep in mind that the first version of everything is garbage, and the final version of everything is still garbage to the person who made it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I absolutely struggle with this every single day.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/26/fighting-to-stay-creative/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Programming Sucks]]></title>
    <link href="http://stilldrinking.org/programming-sucks"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/25/programming-sucks/</id>
    <published>2014-06-25T19:02:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-25T19:11:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Peter Welch:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>So no, I’m not required to be able to lift objects weighing up to fifty pounds. I traded that for the opportunity to trim Satan’s pubic hair while he dines out of my open skull so a few bits of the internet will continue to work for a few more days.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hilarious. Depressing. Accurate.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/25/programming-sucks/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Starting Anew]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20140623211315-269697626-starting-anew"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/starting-anew/</id>
    <published>2014-06-24T15:01:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-24T15:01:03.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Angela Ahrendts:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>My father used to always say, “Ask questions, don’t make assumptions.” Questions invite conversations, stimulate thinking, break down barriers, create positive energy and show your willingness to understand and learn. Questions show humility, acknowledgement and respect for the past, and give you greater insights into both the business and individuals. And don’t be afraid to ask personal questions or share a few of your personal details. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some great advice that I could follow more often.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/starting-anew/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[On Losing a Life, Grief, and Honor]]></title>
    <link href="http://apensievenameddesire.com/post/89364387805/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor/</id>
    <published>2014-06-24T12:41:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-24T12:41:09.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife wrote a wonderful post on <a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/">Emma</a> as well.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
