<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2014-11-26:/20141126155001988</id><title>Chris Brakebill</title><updated>2015-06-17T22:04:14.982Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><generator version="0.4.0" uri="https://github.com/jebrosen/pub-atom">pub-atom</generator><subtitle type="text">Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast. Sender of Three Things Weekly.</subtitle><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-17:http://luckypeach.com/1-dad/</id><title>#1 Dad</title><updated>2015-06-17T22:04:13.953Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wonderful piece by Ben Shewry about being a chef and a dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-16:http://jdbentley.com/journal/the-cost-of-a-15-dollar-minimum-wage</id><title>The Cost of a $15 Minimum Wage</title><updated>2015-06-16T12:33:39.818Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The minimum wage is one of those things that sounds great in theory and always gets people excited, but has a lot of problems. J.D. Bentley covers some of these issues, including fewer jobs for unskilled workers, fewer opportunities for development, and a climate the pushes more jobs under the table and into the hands of illegal immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-15:/soylent/</id><title>Soylent</title><updated>2015-06-15T12:27:46.918Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Soylent is being talked about more and more, particularly in the tech world. The New York Times &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/25/technology/in-busy-silicon-valley-protein-powder-is-in-demand.html?_r=0"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about engineers who are ditching lunch so they can get more work in…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boom times in Silicon Valley call for hard work, and hard work — at least in technology land — means that coders, engineers and venture capitalists are turning to liquid meals with names like Schmoylent, Soylent, Schmilk and People Chow. The protein-packed products that come in powder form are inexpensive and quick and easy to make — just shake with water, or in the case of Schmilk, milk. While athletes and dieters have been drinking their dinner for years, Silicon Valley’s workers are now increasingly chugging their meals, too, so they can more quickly get back to their computer work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the kind of ridiculous attitude about something that comes from Silicon Valley. Hustle. Grind. Drink lunch at your desk so you can &lt;em&gt;keep on working&lt;/em&gt;.  Give me a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find soylent incredibly interesting, but not so I can spend more time at my desk working. Something more like &lt;a href="http://www.insignificant.info/blog-native/2015/5/21/soylent"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best meals to replace with Soylent are the meals you aren’t excited about. I’m talking about boring sandwiches, generic lunches near the office, hasty breakfasts, or even “I just need to eat something” dinners. Those aren’t fun eating experiences. They don’t bring delight to your life. They probably cost more than they should, waste time, and are often unhealthy. If you are on a diet, these are the meals where you are likely to cheat and then regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often don’t eat breakfast or I eat crap for lunch because I don’t have the time, energy, or materials to make something proper and decent for me. I see Soylent as a good solution to that. It’s an easily made and balanced meal to replace all that junk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like that I don’t have to worry about the conditions soylent ingredients were raised in. Unlike the bacon and eggs I had for breakfast or the burger I’m having for lunch, the ingredients to soylent don’t require massive slaughterhouses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to stop eating food I enjoy. I can still go out to dinner with family and friends. Or I can have the occasional bacon and eggs in the morning. I just want to replace some of the crap I waste time on with something healthier and easy to make. I think Soylent provides that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-12:/manifesto-update/</id><title>Manifesto Update</title><updated>2015-06-12T13:11:04.432Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this year I worked on my own &lt;a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/personal-manifesto/"&gt;personal manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, a sort guide for how I live my life and what I prioritize. Now that we’re halfway through the year, I wanted to take a look back at it and see what I’m doing well and where I could do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="relationships-with-family"&gt;Relationships with family&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/p/2wgvYYpLx4/"&gt;Charleston&lt;/a&gt; on the way, my relationship with Lauren is better than ever, and we’re working hard to prepare for the challenge ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could definitely do better with my family. I’m not good about picking up the phone and calling my siblings (or anyone for that matter). If I don’t have a specific reason to call, I usually don’t. I’d really like to change that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="responsible-use-of-goods-and-resources"&gt;Responsible use of goods and resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve definitely been able to make some strides here. Having a decent waste &amp;amp; recycling company is a big reason why. I don’t even put the trash out every week because it frequently has one or no bags in it. That said, I would still like to find ways to waste less through composting and buying fewer unrecyclable products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently adjusted how I take showers. I generally keep them on the luke warm to cool side. I never turn the handle more than halfway. Not only does it use less energy heating water, but I don’t feel the need to just stand in the shower so I take shorter, more efficient showers. I’ve also switched to using a homemade toothpaste so hopefully I’m creating a little less waste there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working hard to reduce the amount of stuff in our home, but I’ve got a long way to go there. I’m slowly tossing or giving away things that I don’t need. But I’m still clinging to a large number of old Eagles jerseys…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="care-of-my-body"&gt;Care of my body&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has largely been a failure this year. I’ve gotten very little exercise. I’ve not played much basketball or tennis like I wanted to. I’m trying to pay attention to what I eat, but I’ve mostly been passive. I tend to rely on Lauren to plan healthy meals, which she does very well. The good news is she usually does the grocery trips, so I’m not able to pick up a bunch of junk food. I don’t drink much soda anymore. I haven’t been to the doctor, which I desperately need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not all bad news. Things are on the uptick with my fitness. I got back to scheduling my days (which is absolutely crucial to my productivity, more on that soon). And I’ve run every single day this week. I’m keeping my goals simple, but consistent. I want to run one mile every single day for a month. It’s quick and (mostly) easy, but it’s building a habit that should help me stay consistent. One of the things I’m looking at doing is using &lt;a href="https://diy.soylent.com"&gt;Soylent&lt;/a&gt; to replace some of the times in the week where I would eat crappy meals, or no meal at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="serve-participate-in-community"&gt;Serve &amp;amp; Participate in Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost nothing but failure. There are only a couple of small positives I can think of. I went to a local monthly Cocoa Heads meetup, but unfortunately I’ve missed the two since that one. I’ve also started following the RSS feed for the &lt;a href="http://knoxvillecitytn.iqm2.com/Citizens/Default.aspx"&gt;Knoxville City Council minutes&lt;/a&gt;. It’s small, but it helps me keep a little bit up to date on what’s going on in the city. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is Lauren and I have found a church we really enjoy, but we need to get plugged into the community there. We have plenty of friends in Knoxville, many that we &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;, but we don’t really feel like we have a community. That’s something we want to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="use-electronics-responsibly"&gt;Use electronics responsibly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not even sure what to say on this one. I don’t think I sussed it out well enough to properly evaluate myself. My rule of no electronics after 10 PM has not been a success. I’ve barely even thought about it. I’m going to work on making that an actual part of my day. I have a feeling it will be a little easier once Charleston comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="relationship-with-god"&gt;Relationship with God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ve done a pretty crummy job here. I haven’t done anything to serve God in the community. I haven’t been regularly praying (other than at meals) or reading the bible. I haven’t talked about God with other communities outside of church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think now that I’m back to intentionally scheduling my day, I’ll get in the habit of scheduling some time for God. Some prayer and bible reading time every day would be good. I also have been thinking about getting back to having a physical bible. If anyone has any recommendations they would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s where I am. If I can find some time soon, I might try to refine my manifesto and put the full version on the internet. What’s the point of having a guiding document if you can’t be held accountable? As I mentioned earlier, I’m doing more intentional planning of my daily work. I’d like to write about exactly what that looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-11:http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths blog/2015/06/name-calling.html</id><title>Name Calling</title><updated>2015-06-11T12:39:48.026Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Seth Godin:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we call someone misogynist or racist or sexist or a capitalist, a socialist or an abstract expressionist, what are we hoping for? Every one of us is on the &amp;#39;ist&amp;#39; spectrum, so the label becomes meaningless. Meaningless labels are noise, noise that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that person stopped acting like a &lt;strong&gt;_&lt;/strong&gt;ist, what would change? Because if there&amp;#39;s nothing we want to change, the labeling is useless. And if there&amp;#39;s a change that needs to be made, let&amp;#39;s talk about what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that absolutely drives me nuts about our sort of shock culture. Someone does or says something, we label them, and as Seth Godin also says…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best reason to brand someone with a pejorative label is to push them away, to forestall useful conversation, to turn them into the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It divides our culture all over the place. We want to find the racists, and the sexists, and whatever else-ists, label them and cast them out rather than looking at them as people, digging into the issues, and trying to figure out how we can help them and ourselves. Applying such vitriolic labels is tremendously oversimplifying people who are much more complex. Yes someone made a sexist or racist remark, and lets deal with that and talk about it. But let’s not reduce them as a person down to that comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathy is needed all around. Empathy for other groups of people. Empathy for those with a poor understanding of other groups. Just general empathy for people who are different.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-10:http://shawnblanc.net/2015/06/there-is-no-finally/</id><title>There is no “finally”</title><updated>2015-06-10T12:42:56.499Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Shawn Blanc:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distractions, excuses, and challenges will always be right at your doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait for the fear to go away, because it won’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait for the risk to disappear, because there will always be risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show up every day when it’s frightful. When it’s risky. When it’s tense. When it hurts. Because it will always be that way — the “finally” moment never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is such an easy trap to slip into. I feel the pull of it every day. Once I launch &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt; maybe people will know about me and I’ll &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; feel good about myself as a developer. Once I’ve saved enough to buy the home I want, I’ll &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; feel at rest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love to hope. Because hope is awesome. No matter how good or bad the current moment is, hope says the next one will be better. And that’s pretty exciting. But that hope can easily turn into something insatiable in unpleasant forms like greed and workaholism. The key is to embrace the fears and challenges and find joy in them. Find joy in the every day struggle and keep working and find satisfaction in resting and looking back on a day’s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s this reason that I’m super intrigued by Shawn Blanc’s &lt;a href="https://thefocuscourse.com"&gt;Focus Course&lt;/a&gt;. There are a lot of video series/courses/cat videos/minecraft hacks on the internet dedicated to improving yourself, but I have to think Shawn’s is the best. It’s not about making a million bucks before you’re thirty, or how you can hack your body to run 5 marathons a year. It’s simply about how diligence and focus can be learned to do more meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-09:http://www.vox.com/2014/10/31/7137457/broadband-speed-chattanooga-kansas-city-lafayette</id><title>The basic truth about broadband that cable companies want to hide</title><updated>2015-06-09T12:27:24.660Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Vox:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even though we have the technical ability to deliver cheap, super-fast internet and we have the financial ability to finance the construction, we don&amp;#39;t actually have the network. In fact, we&amp;#39;re so in hock to the interests of the broadband incumbents that we don&amp;#39;t even use all the fiber networks we&amp;#39;ve already built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically cable companies are putting their money towards lobbying to shut down possible competition rather than investing in better, faster infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More local governments should look at &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/2014/05/20/technology/innovation/chattanooga-internet/index.html"&gt;Chattanooga&lt;/a&gt; as an example and try to emulate that success. A smallish city building such a fast network for such affordable prices is a huge warning sign that the private internet sector is broken.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-08:http://recode.net/2015/06/02/atts-ralph-de-la-vega-subsidized-phones-are-going-away/</id><title>Smartphone subsidies are going away</title><updated>2015-06-08T12:47:40.494Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;AT&amp;T CEO Ralph de la Vega:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is one of those options that is going to go away slowly…not because we insist on it but because customers will choose it less often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think this is a fairly long way off. I don’t know many people outside the tech-ish bubble who would even consider it. I support the move, as you know exactly what you’re paying for and when you’re paying for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Dan Moren:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-Mobile’s already made this shift, factoring an installment cost of the phone into its plan price. When you pay off the phone, your plan gets cheaper. So if you decide to stick with your current phone for a while, you save money. Likewise, if you bring your own phone, you don’t pay the higher rate. If you want to switch to another provider, just pay off the cost of the phone, and you’re free to go—no pesky contracts mucking things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T does something similar. I moved Lauren and I both off contract by paying the full price of our phones last year (it’s amazing how stunned the reps at the AT&amp;amp;T store were by this). That move dropped our bill by about $15 per line. Just this month I upgraded us to the 10GB data plan and that upped our discount to $25 per line every month. That clever bit of pricing  makes anyone using more than 3GB heavily motivated to move up to the bigger plans. If you use that much data, you can actually save money by paying full price up front and taking advantage of the bigger discount.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-02:http://grantland.com/features/steve-prefontaine-death/</id><title>Steve Prefontaine’s Last Run</title><updated>2015-06-02T19:40:08.901Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great piece on Steve Prefontaine, his running, and the influence he had on amateur and professional sports.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-29:/update/</id><title>Update</title><updated>2015-05-29T19:54:43.576Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href="/a-change/"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about a revamp to the how my site was deployed. Naturally, I’m a tinkerer, and I couldn’t resist making more changes. &lt;a href="http://www.hexo.io"&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice website scaffolding, but there’s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; to it. If I wanted to get in and mess around I had to do a lot of digging. I wanted to have a better understanding of how things were constructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working for a long while on a node based server/generator called Clive that not only generates a site, but gives you an admin interface for editing and publishing files. It also has the ability to queue up posts for automatic posting and generation. I spent some time away from it, and just don’t love it. It’s another thing that just does too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the past week or so I’ve been all over the internet trying to figure out how I want to build this website in a way that makes it easy for my to share and write the way I want to. I finally settled on what I find to be the simplest process; setting up a Gulp build &amp;amp; deploy system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in the near future I’ll open source it (and Clive for that matter). But for now the basics of my setup are this…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All posts and pages and whatever else I might create are written in markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content is stored in two folders, called &lt;code&gt;published&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;drafts&lt;/code&gt; (mostly for ease in combing through and editing files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actual published state is stored via a boolean value in the front matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a couple of tasks which will sort through the markdown files and move any out of place files into their correct directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site is generated with handlebars templates. It’s not great but in order to keep links to previous posts from breaking I’ve set up redirect pages with meta tags which send you to the proper location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Styles are in a single less file that’s compiled to css during the build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next task is to use &lt;a href="http://www.nodegit.org/"&gt;nodegit&lt;/a&gt; to automate deploying to Github pages. I know, I could write more if I spent less time tinkering, but I want to do some of both. I’m hoping I’ll be happy with this as a long term solution…&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-22:http://thesweetsetup.com/chris-brakebills-mac-and-ios-setup/</id><title>My Sweet Setup</title><updated>2015-05-22T13:43:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The folks over at the Sweet Setup have shared my Mac and iOS setup. It’s amazing how much can change in a short period of time. iPhone home screen already looks pretty different and my desk is now located in Tennessee. Thanks to the Sweet Setup for sharing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-07:http://localmilkblog.com/2015/05/earl-grey-waffles-whipped-honey-cream-3-yrs-of-local-milk.html</id><title>3+ years of local milk</title><updated>2015-05-07T22:52:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beth Kirby’s blog might be my favorite thing on the internet. I think I come for the recipes and photography, but I stay because it’s like sitting down with an intimate friend for coffee by a fireplace. It’s not about perfection, but comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-21:http://bleacherreport.com/articles/2394919-what-college-stars-can-learn-from-nfl-players-ditching-millions-to-retire-early</id><title>What College Stars Can Learn From NFL Players Ditching Millions to Retire Early</title><updated>2015-04-21T17:17:56.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Adam Kramer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I have preached the same message to successful products of the NFL’s farm system: Leave as quickly as you can if there’s a living to be made or even if you’re on the cusp of making one. Playing football for the price of a degree is not a worthwhile trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much truth in here. I’ve spent too much time thinking oh this or that guy could have improved their draft stock by staying in school. But it’s crap. Many of these guys are tremendously under compensated for their skills and sacrifice. Once your skills are at all desired in the NFL, I say go and finish that degree later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I’m just glad to see that more players are starting to say no to the millions of dollars to focus on life outside of football. Get what you can get. Quit while you’re ahead. Budget wisely. Don’t destroy the rest of your life for a few more years in the spotlight making millions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-20:http://qz.com/385821/poor-internet-for-poor-people-why-facebooks-internet-org-amounts-to-economic-racism/</id><title>Poor Internet for Poor People</title><updated>2015-04-20T18:19:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Mahesh Murthy:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the scheme works. Facebook approaches a telco—in India’s case, Reliance—and offers to pay them the bandwidth costs of serving Facebook site and a small group of other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when the poor, who in theory can’t afford a net connection come to the Facebook Zero service confusingly called Internet.org, they’re made to believe they’re on the internet while in reality they’re only on Facebook and a few hand-picked sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the sites too are picked in secret under some unknown process. For instance, Facebook chose to offer the distant-second search engine Bing instead of industry-leading Google. Why? Is it rivalry with Google? Or because of Microsoft’s stake in Facebook? And then Facebook’s Zero product features a tiny job site like Babajob instead of the industry-leading Naukri. Why? So that the poor have fewer job options? No one knows. Facebook doesn’t feature YouTube—the largest video site in the world and an immense education resource —but allows its own videos in full. It doesn’t really look like charity any more, does it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While zero services are a more extreme case and don’t fit what you will see in the U.S., they are helpful in illustrating how the seemingly good idea of certain companies’ products not counting towards your data caps is actually bad for the internet. You’re no longer choosing between product X and product Y. It’s now product X, which won’t count towards you cap, and product Y, which may be a superior product but can’t afford to pay off your internet provider. Your cell phone company or ISP shouldn’t get to make this decision. They should simply give you uniform access to sites on the internet and charge you according to that usage, no matter where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-15:/life-sans-iphone/</id><title>Life sans iPhone</title><updated>2015-04-15T11:15:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t know, I’d been looking to trade my iPhone 6+ in for an iPhone 6. I was recently able to sell my 6+ on Glyde. Since my last sale fell through, I decided to wait this time until I had the money before buying a new phone. Some crazy slow shipping times, combined with a seller who didn’t seem to want to part with their iPhone 6 left me without a smartphone for about 3 weeks. I feel like the experience of having a phone which was only for calling has been really informative of my habits. (Okay it could text, but have you tried texting without a full keyboard? It’s horrific).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/oldPhone.jpg" alt="My awesome Alcatel temp phone"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became apparent very quickly how habitual looking at my phone was. I would frequently look at my little candy bar for no reason at all. I needed a fix of stimulation that whatever situation I was currently in just couldn’t give me. Or so it seemed. As time went by, I found myself leaving my phone behind even as I went out to do things. I missed the occasional text or call, but for the most part being disconnected was a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I find interesting now is looking at my apps and thinking about how many of them I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; on my phone. I’m pretty sure I can count on one hand the number of times I really needed an iPhone app for something. (One of those times was when I had to print out Google Maps directions and got lost. It felt like 2002 all over again). Most of the time I looked at my phone out of boredom or being stuck in unpleasant social situations (or both).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most revealing thing has been the past 48 hours of having an iPhone back in my life. I’d been anticipating getting it back for weeks. I think somewhere deep down I thought getting one back would make life so much easier or more pleasant or at least I’ll know the scores of every current SPORTING EVENT. But I’ve become a lot more conscious of my motivations every time I take a peek at it. And I’m finding myself putting it away because I really have nothing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is this experience going to change my life? Probably not. But at the very least it’s got me being a little bit more intentional about how I use my phone. I’m going to pare down the number of apps I keep on it and try to not feel like I need it everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-13:http://www.sunnyskyz.com/blog/766/He-Was-Tired-Of-Looking-At-Boring-Office-Walls-So-He-Bought-9-000-Post-It-Notes-The-Result-Is-Amazing#LlKzFvyFSAjRuQxp.01</id><title>Decorating with Post-It Notes</title><updated>2015-04-13T17:07:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I just got so tired of how sterile and boring our office felt, I thought I should do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic way to bring life to a space affordably and ephemerally.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-09:/outshape/</id><title>Outshape</title><updated>2015-04-09T21:29:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know, I’ve been spending most of my time since I left ESPN working on a game called &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt;. I’m getting super close to being ready to submit to the App Store. I’m just trying to iterate the design and interaction to as close to perfection as I can get it, while I smooth out some functional edges. It’s the most fun I’ve had in years. And I’m delighted to be able to work hard without having to work all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started a &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/blog"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; where I’m going to document the development process of Outshape. From the inspiration, to early mocks, to the stresses of sharing a thing I’m making with the world. I’m sure some of that will come over here, but I’m going to post anything Outshape specific over there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go sign up for the email list if you want to get the details on how Outshape came to be!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-08:http://iain-simpson.org/introvert/</id><title>Introvert</title><updated>2015-04-08T19:28:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Iain Simpson:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts are my thoughts. I share what I choose to, and the rest is mine. Don&amp;#39;t quiz me, demand to know what I&amp;#39;m thinking, tell me I&amp;#39;m meant to share. I have a right to privacy. Don&amp;#39;t assume that because you want to share everything with me, that I should want to share everything with you. Don&amp;#39;t present your view of the world as the only possible option, and that I must be somehow emotionally stunted, wrong, or hiding something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I haven&amp;#39;t told you how I feel about something, it&amp;#39;s probably because I haven&amp;#39;t decided how I feel about it. I can&amp;#39;t make decisions without all the information, and I don&amp;#39;t offer solutions without understanding the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get into the mind of an introvert, this short piece will get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-07:/iphone-sixes/</id><title>iPhone Sixes</title><updated>2015-04-07T16:06:37.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting to read &lt;a href="http://www.512pixels.net/blog/2015/4/well-i-switched-to-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Stephen Hackett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/2015/04/06/life-with-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/04/two-weeks-with-the-iphone-6-plus/"&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; talk about their experiences as regular iPhone 6 users who are experimenting with or switching to the iPhone 6 Plus. Particularly since I’ve been a 6 Plus user who is switching to the regular ol’ iPhone 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to comment on their opinions much, since I don’t have my iPhone 6 yet and I don’t yet know how it works for me. My reason for switching boils down mostly to the fact that the 6 Plus is just too big. I may find that the 6 is too big in day to day usage as well. But I’m most worried about the drop in battery life. I got used to almost never having to think about the battery on my 6 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will definitely follow up with my experiences with the iPhone 6 when I receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-06:http://randsinrepose.com/links/2015/04/02/introverts-as-leaders-briefly/</id><title>Introverts as Leaders</title><updated>2015-04-06T15:20:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;rands:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introverts are professional listeners. Their natural state is to observe and gather data from the world around them as opposed to their extroverts counterparts who enjoying spending their time talking about the state of the world and all the fascinating data in the world… endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All to often, society says that introversion is bad and extroversion is the “proper” or “successful” way to be. This seems to be a more common thought when it comes to leadership. Rands points out that introverts have some pretty huge natural advantages when it comes to good leadership, just as extroverts do. Both most overcome their own weaknesses to make use of their strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>