<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-08T11:28:52.229Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Persona]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/persona"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/07/persona/</id>
    <published>2014-07-07T21:54:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-07T21:54:29.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>When I was younger, it was easy to put people I looked up to on a pedestal. Bosses at work, pastors at church, my favourite bands. That is easy to do from afar, but the closer you get to people, the more you see the real person; the flaws, the hurting, and the mess as much as the good things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great stuff from Chris Bowler. We’re all just messy people.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/persona">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Jonathan Haidt can explain the liberal Hobby Lobby freak out]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.theamericanconservative.com/dreher/jonathan-haidt-can-explain-the-liberal-hobby-lobby-freakout/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/05/hobby-lobby/</id>
    <published>2014-07-06T00:47:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-06T00:48:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot to absorb here, but it’s something that I do feel like resonates with my experiences. Definitely worth a read. The end though is a bit disturbing:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet seeing the grotesque animosity towards people like me from liberals over the small-beer Hobby Lobby decision compels me to face up to the fact that the only political force standing between me, my church, and my community, and a State dominated by people who think we traditional church people are cretins who deserve to be pushed around, is Republicans.</p>
</blockquote>
]]><p><a href="http://www.theamericanconservative.com/dreher/jonathan-haidt-can-explain-the-liberal-hobby-lobby-freakout/">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Gunfighter]]></title>
    <link href="https://vimeo.com/79306807"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/28/the-gunfighter/</id>
    <published>2014-06-28T13:36:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-28T13:36:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great short film. Nick Offerman narrates and is hilarious as usual.</p>
]]><p><a href="https://vimeo.com/79306807">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Universal Studios Interactive Wands]]></title>
    <link href="http://gizmodo.com/live-your-hogwarts-fantasies-with-universal-studios-int-1592078675"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/universal-studios-interactive-wands/</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T19:46:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T19:46:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dang. So cool.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/live-your-hogwarts-fantasies-with-universal-studios-int-1592078675">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Martian: A Novel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00EMXBDMA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00EMXBDMA&linkCode=as2&tag=braonenin-20&linkId=ZIEJGBTQ4ROOEDNR"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/27/the-martian/</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T16:17:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T16:20:14.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just spent a couple of days reading this on vacation. Really fantastic book.</p>
<p>Long story short, an astronaut gets stranded on Mars. He engineers and potato farms to survive while NASA and his fellow astronauts try to figure out how to get him home.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00EMXBDMA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00EMXBDMA&linkCode=as2&tag=braonenin-20&linkId=ZIEJGBTQ4ROOEDNR">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Fighting to Stay Creative]]></title>
    <link href="http://shawnblanc.net/2014/05/fighting-to-stay-creative/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/26/fighting-to-stay-creative/</id>
    <published>2014-06-26T12:02:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-26T12:02:21.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shawn Blanc:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We mustn’t be afraid of failing nor of being rejected, and we must place more value on the act of creating so we can find joy in the journey and develop a lifetime of experience in making things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Shawn has some <strong>great</strong> advice on creativity. I can feel every one of the stiflers of creativity that he mentions getting a foothold in my work. I’m going to try to be more intentional about keeping those things at bay.</p>
<p>Matt Gemmell <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/staying-creative/" target="_blank">adds</a>…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Creative people, in my experience, are plagued with doubt. This is awful! they all think, definitely including myself. It’s a very personal thing, and it’s insidious because you’re the only one who gets to see the first drafts, and the refinements, and whole, messy stop and start and double-back of producing something worthwhile. It’s hard to keep in mind that the first version of everything is garbage, and the final version of everything is still garbage to the person who made it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I absolutely struggle with this every single day.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://shawnblanc.net/2014/05/fighting-to-stay-creative/">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Programming Sucks]]></title>
    <link href="http://stilldrinking.org/programming-sucks"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/25/programming-sucks/</id>
    <published>2014-06-25T19:02:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-25T19:11:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>So no, I’m not required to be able to lift objects weighing up to fifty pounds. I traded that for the opportunity to trim Satan’s pubic hair while he dines out of my open skull so a few bits of the internet will continue to work for a few more days.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hilarious. Depressing. Accurate.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://stilldrinking.org/programming-sucks">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Starting Anew]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20140623211315-269697626-starting-anew"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/starting-anew/</id>
    <published>2014-06-24T15:01:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-24T15:01:03.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>My father used to always say, “Ask questions, don’t make assumptions.” Questions invite conversations, stimulate thinking, break down barriers, create positive energy and show your willingness to understand and learn. Questions show humility, acknowledgement and respect for the past, and give you greater insights into both the business and individuals. And don’t be afraid to ask personal questions or share a few of your personal details. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some great advice that I could follow more often.</p>
]]><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20140623211315-269697626-starting-anew">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[On Losing a Life, Grief, and Honor]]></title>
    <link href="http://apensievenameddesire.com/post/89364387805/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/24/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor/</id>
    <published>2014-06-24T12:41:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-24T12:41:09.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife wrote a wonderful post on <a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/">Emma</a> as well.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://apensievenameddesire.com/post/89364387805/on-losing-a-life-grief-and-honor">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Code as Craft: Opsweekly]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeascraft.com/2014/06/19/opsweekly-measuring-on-call-experience-with-alert-classification/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/23/opsweekly/</id>
    <published>2014-06-23T19:45:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-23T19:45:33.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really cool stuff from Etsy. Quantizing on-call experience and effectiveness is not something you hear about from many companies.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://codeascraft.com/2014/06/19/opsweekly-measuring-on-call-experience-with-alert-classification/">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Miscarriage]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/</id>
    <published>2014-06-21T03:43:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-21T03:43:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had originally planned to call this post “Surprise”, because that’s exactly what it was when Lauren and I found out we were going to have our first child. But as we neared our 6th week, and our first ultrasound, our excitement was turning into fear. Blood was coming when it shouldn’t have been. </p>
<p>A week and three ultrasounds later, our baby was gone.</p>
<p>The emotions of going from “oh crap we’re having a baby” to “I can’t wait to have this child” to “I don’t know what’s happening” and finally to “Your baby isn’t there anymore” are brutal.</p>
<p>When we first found out Lauren was pregnant, we had to allow ourselves some time to grieve. Not to grieve the new life we created, but to grieve the loss of our plans for the next couple of years. This wasn’t supposed to happen yet. I wanted to get a dog first. But that very quickly changed to excitement (and then quickly back and forth between fear and excitement).</p>
<p>The doctors told us that this isn’t uncommon, and happens more than 20% of the time. Usually it happens because of severe genetic defects, and the body stops the pregnancy before it gets going. I have to marvel at the wonder of God’s creation. That He makes our bodies stop these things when He has to, to prevent pain and grief down the road.</p>
<p>Conversely, I have to think about the babies born with various defects and disease. We may question why God would put those babies and families through that. But God keeps those babies going because he knows they are strong enough and their purpose important enough to bring them into this world.</p>
<p>We are so thankful to the close friends and family who were around to love and share this with us. While we’re heartbroken, we’re glad to have the opportunity to talk about something that just isn’t talked about enough, failed pregnancy. </p>
<p>I was driven a bit mad even in the few shorts weeks we had that I couldn’t tell people. I found the idea of waiting until you’re far in and complication free absurd. And now, after this experience, I find it even more ridiculous. You’re denying yourself the support and love of people around you. Is it uncomfortable telling people you lost your baby not long after you told them you were pregnant? Absolutely. But I’d take that every time over dealing with this fear and pain alone. Having to tell my parents, “oh by the way, we were going to have a baby, but we had a miscarriage” was way worse than if they had been there through the whole experience. I’m SO thankful for the people close to us in Orlando who we told and were there to support us through every scary moment.</p>
<p>This child was created in passion, when… certain precautions weren’t taken (ew.. sex.. right?). Before the miscarriage, I’d had a dream that we had a girl, and that’s as good as anything to go on, right? We wanted to memorialize her, so we named her Emma. One of Lauren’s supervisors at school said that she must be a full and passionate woman with God now. That is a thrilling thing to think about. </p>
<p>I can’t wait to meet you one day, Emma.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Game of Thrones Cover]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.vanityfair.com/vf-hollywood/game-of-thrones-dixieland-cover"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/17/game-of-thrones-cover/</id>
    <published>2014-06-17T22:32:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T22:33:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Incredible cover of the Game of Thrones theme.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.vanityfair.com/vf-hollywood/game-of-thrones-dixieland-cover">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[To Teachers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/6/13/to-teachers"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/17/to-teachers/</id>
    <published>2014-06-17T14:39:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T14:39:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes to everything here. My sister is a teacher and I’m incredibly proud of her. Teachers are overworked and underpaid.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/6/13/to-teachers">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Filling a Notebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sanspoint.com/archives/2014/05/19/filling-notebook/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/16/filling-a-notebook/</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T12:55:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T12:55:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been using the <a href="http://bulletjournal.com" target="_blank">Bullet Journal</a> method for managing my tasks and notes. As much as I <strong>want</strong> a digital, cloud based task manager to be my go to, there’s just something about putting a pen to paper that sticks better with me. I suspect it has to do with growing up in a world where I had to write something down to record it.</p>
<p>I’d like to use it more to record thoughts, so that I could write more and better. I often find that the little nugget that was in my head disappears so quickly into an abyss of thoughts and memories.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.sanspoint.com/archives/2014/05/19/filling-notebook/">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Do More of This Stuff]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/wren-lanier/2014-june-14"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/16/do-more-of-this-stuff/</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T12:51:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T12:51:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A good list of things to do more of, and some things to do less of.</p>
]]><p><a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/wren-lanier/2014-june-14">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reading With Intention]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/lectio-divina"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/10/reading-with-intention/</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T12:44:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T15:44:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chris Bowler:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Take time to read, re-read, and meditate on this piece of human thought you’ve chosen to ingest. Truly ingest it; if it resonates with you, allow it to change you. This is what I want to do with Scripture, but also any topic that I enjoy; web design, typography, woodworking … you name it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is great stuff in regards to scripture reading and all other reading.  With both I tend to find myself reading to get it done. I don’t take time and really think about what I’m reading. I just want to quickly absorb the facts. It translates straight into my writing here as well. I see a thing I want to share and I just share it without any thoughtful commentary.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/lectio-divina">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Judge John Hodgman Ep. 161: Cold Case]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.maximumfun.org/judge-john-hodgman/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/10/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case/</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T12:35:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T15:35:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you aren’t listening to John Hodgman’s podcast, you’re really missing out. Basically he acts as judge in an argument between couples, friends, and families. They present their cases and he rules. Hilarious.</p>
<p>In this particularly hilarious episode, a couple debates whether they need to add air conditioning to their apartment in Berlin. We learn about Germans’ fear of drafts and the wonder that is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tropical_Islands_Resort" target="_blank">Tropical Islands Resort</a>.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.maximumfun.org/judge-john-hodgman/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Listen]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/jeff-eaton/2014-may-27"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/listen/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T03:25:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:25:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Defending ourselves is always easier than listening to difficult truths.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Accurate. It’s the natural reaction and it’s so incredibly destructive.</p>
]]><p><a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/jeff-eaton/2014-may-27">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Alton Browncast: Andrew Zimmern]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nerdist.com/pepisode/the-alton-browncast-48-andrew-zimmern/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/the-alton-browncast-andrew-zimmern/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T03:22:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:22:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just an incredible listen. I’ve always loved <a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/bizarre-foods" target="_blank">Bizarre Foods</a>, but I never knew Andrew Zimmern’s story. I can’t remember the exact quote, but he said something like “I’ll never start a business venture without a charitable component”. A fantastic way to do things.</p>
]]><p><a href="http://www.nerdist.com/pepisode/the-alton-browncast-48-andrew-zimmern/">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[John Oliver on 'Preventing Cable Company F&%kery']]></title>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fpbOEoRrHyU&feature=youtu.be"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/04/john-oliver-on-preventing-cable-company-fkery/</id>
    <published>2014-06-04T11:39:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-04T11:39:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brilliant. Hilarious. It would be funnier if it weren’t so true…</p>
]]><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fpbOEoRrHyU&feature=youtu.be">♻</a></p></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
