<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title><description><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast. Sender of Three Things Weekly.]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 14:36:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[2016 Podcasts]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Here&#39;s a dump of the podcasts I&#39;m listening to at the start of 2016. I&#39;m gonna cobble together a list of my favorites next week. Sorry for the lack of links, search the titles in your favorite podcast client/platform and you should find them.</p>
<ul>
<li>5by5 at the Movies</li>
<li>99% Invisible</li>
<li>Accidental Tech Podcast</li>
<li>The Alton Browncast (okay it was inactive for all of 2015, but I&#39;m holding out hope Alton returns...)</li>
<li>Analog(ue)</li>
<li>Back to Work</li>
<li>The Bill Simmons Podcast</li>
<li>Channel 33</li>
<li>Clockwise</li>
<li>Connected</li>
<li>Core Intuition</li>
<li>Cortex</li>
<li>Criminal</li>
<li>Debug</li>
<li>The Distance</li>
<li>Electric Shadow</li>
<li>Exponent</li>
<li>The Flop House</li>
<li>For The Record</li>
<li>Girl on Guy with Aisha Tyler</li>
<li>Harry Potter: The Chapter Titles Were So Good</li>
<li>Hello Internet</li>
<li>Home Work</li>
<li>How Did This Get Made?</li>
<li>Judge John Hodgman</li>
<li>Just The Tip</li>
<li>Liftoff</li>
<li>Lore</li>
<li>The Moment with Brian Koppelman</li>
<li>Myke at the Movies</li>
<li>Quit with After Dark Post-Shows</li>
<li>Reconcilable Differences</li>
<li>Review</li>
<li>Road Work</li>
<li>Roderick on the Line</li>
<li>Serial</li>
<li>Shawn Today</li>
<li>Song Exploder</li>
<li>The Sporkful</li>
<li>Stuff You Missed in History Class</li>
<li>Stuff You Should Know</li>
<li>Style Guide Podcast</li>
<li>Surprisingly Awesome</li>
<li>The Talk Show With John Gruber</li>
<li>The Tim Ferriss Show</li>
<li>Top Four</li>
<li>Top Scallops</li>
<li>The Truth</li>
<li>Under the Radar</li>
<li>Unjustly Maligned</li>
<li>Upgrade</li>
<li>Vector</li>
<li>You Made It Weird with Pete Holmes</li>
</ul>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-podcasts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-podcasts/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 13:05:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2016 Blogroll]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I recently trimmed some fat here, so I think things are a little tighter than last year. But here is a look at the websites I&#39;m reading daily in 2016...</p>
<p><a href="http://andrewalexanderprice.com/blog.php">Andrew Alexander Price</a> - <a href="http://www.andrewalexanderprice.com/blog.rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://thenewsprint.co/">The Newsprint</a> - <a href="http://feed.thenewsprint.co/thenewsprint">RSS</a><br><a href="https://meh.com">meh.com</a> - <a href="https://meh.com/deals.rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com">Mr. Money Mustache</a> - <a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="https://about.gitlab.com/">GitLab</a> - <a href="https://about.gitlab.com/atom.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://bemorewithless.com">Be More with Less</a> - <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BeMoreWithLess">RSS</a><br><a href="http://minimaldesks.com/">Minimal Desks</a> - <a href="http://feedpress.me/minimaldesks">RSS</a><br><a href="https://www.caseyliss.com">Liss is More</a> - <a href="http://www.caseyliss.com/rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.listsofnote.com/">Lists of Note</a> - <a href="http://www.listsofnote.com/feeds/posts/default">RSS</a><br><a href="https://blog.fastmail.com">FastMail Blog</a> - <a href="http://blog.fastmail.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.analogsenses.com/">Analog Senses</a> - <a href="http://www.analogsenses.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/">Letters of Note</a> - <a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/feeds/posts/default">RSS</a><br><a href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/">Sportsgeekonomics</a> - <a href="http://sportsgeekonomics.tumblr.com/rss">RSS</a><br><a href="https://marco.org/">Marco.org</a> - <a href="http://www.marco.org/rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://freshome.com">Freshome</a> - <a href="http://freshome.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.remodelista.com/">Remodelista</a> - <a href="http://www.remodelista.com/contents/index.rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.getrichslowly.org/blog">Get Rich Slowly</a> - <a href="http://www.getrichslowly.org/blog/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://thewirecutter.com">The Wirecutter</a> - <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheWirecutter">RSS</a><br><a href="http://daringfireball.net/">Daring Fireball</a> - <a href="http://daringfireball.net/index.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://toolsandtoys.net">Tools and Toys</a> - <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.manton.org">Manton Reece</a> - <a href="http://www.manton.org/rss.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://inessential.com/">inessential.com</a> - <a href="http://inessential.com/xml/rss.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.rockytoptalk.com/">Rocky Top Talk</a> - <a href="http://www.rockytoptalk.com/rss/current">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.raptitude.com">Raptitude.com</a> - <a href="http://www.raptitude.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.512pixels.net/">512 Pixels</a> - <a href="http://512pixels.net/feed">RSS</a><br><a href="http://randsinrepose.com">Rands in Repose</a> - <a href="http://www.randsinrepose.com/index.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.remodelaholic.com">Remodelaholic</a> - <a href="http://www.remodelaholic.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://localmilkblog.com">Local Milk</a> - <a href="http://localmilkblog.com/feed">RSS</a><br><a href="http://cabinporn.com/">Cabin Porn</a> - <a href="http://cabinporn.com/rss">RSS</a><br><a href="http://sketchnotearmy.com/blog/atom.xml">Sketchnote Army</a> - <a href="http://sketchnotearmy.com/blog/atom.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal">chrisbowler.com</a> - <a href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/feed">RSS</a><br><a href="http://thesweetsetup.com">The Sweet Setup</a> - <a href="http://thesweetsetup.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com">Chris Brakebill</a> - <a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/atom.xml">RSS</a><br><a href="http://pxlnv.com/">Pixel Envy</a> - <a href="http://pxlnv.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.thecramped.com">The Cramped</a> - <a href="http://www.thecramped.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://www.housetweaking.com">House Tweaking</a> - <a href="http://www.housetweaking.com/feed/atom/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://mymorningroutine.com">My Morning Routine</a> - <a href="http://mymorningroutine.com/feed/">RSS</a><br><a href="http://jdbentley.com//journal">Bourbon &amp; Tradition</a> - <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/jdbentley">RSS</a><br><a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a> - <a href="http://unsplash.com/rss">RSS</a>  </p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-blogroll/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-blogroll/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 13:37:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2016 Goals]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Just like last year, I&#39;d like to take a look at some goals for this year. One of the things I&#39;m going to do with these is print them out somehow and post them in my office, by my bed, and maybe even stick a small version in my wallet. </p>
<h3 id="less-watching-more-doing">Less Watching, More Doing</h3>
<p>I <em>love</em> me some TV. And with the huge variety of content available through Netflix, Hulu, HBO, etc., it&#39;s hard not to spend our nights glued to the TV. I&#39;d like to make that less of the default move in our home. I want to do more development. More reading. More writing. More crafts and projects. </p>
<h3 id="settle-my-soul">Settle my soul</h3>
<p>The past 5 years has been a whirlwind, going from Knoxville to Seattle to Orlando, and back to Knoxville. I&#39;ve never really moved in somewhere expecting it to be my home for more than a year. As we scout our next home around Downtown Knoxville, I want to find somewhere we expect to stay for at least a few years. I&#39;ve used not owning my home as a reason for not investing in a place, but I&#39;m going to get out of that mindset. I want to own a home at some point, but I&#39;m going to try hard to really settle myself wherever we end up next and make it <em>home</em> as much as I can.</p>
<h3 id="take-care-of-my-body">Take care of my body</h3>
<p>I didn&#39;t do well at this last year, but I&#39;m hopeful about this year. I&#39;m planning to start a morning routine that involves hitting the YMCA to play some basketball. I want to actually run at least one 5K this year. Lauren and I are both wanting to look more into how we can eat better this year. Less Jet&#39;s Pizza and more veggies.</p>
<h3 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h3>
<p>I know this sounds super wishy washy and vague, but hear me out. I don&#39;t often worry about <em>future Chris</em> as I do stuff around the house. For example, I&#39;m pulling something out of the spice cabinet. I ravage that thing looking for the right spice, and then toss it in, leaving myself open to the need for future ravagings (I&#39;m serious about my spices). I recently organized it a bit and what I&#39;d like to do is keep it easy to find what I&#39;m looking for. When I&#39;m done with my spices, I need to take the extra 10 seconds to put them in their place so <em>future Chris</em> has things easier.</p>
<p>I want to practice a sort of <em>mise en place</em> for all sorts of things in my everyday life. Doing so will help keep the house in order and make me a better worker and just a better me.</p>
<h3 id="grow-my-own-food">Grow my own food</h3>
<p>My mom has a great garden which she pulls basil, peppers, and tomatoes from. She does it all on her deck. It&#39;s time to stop letting being a renter prevent me from investing in a garden. Lauren and I both want to do this so I want to make this the year we start it. Beyond food, I want more plants around the house. We don&#39;t keep many, mostly because we tend to kill them. I want to fix that.</p>
<h3 id="seek-god">Seek God</h3>
<p>Read my bible. Go to church. Pursue Christ-filled relationships with people. I&#39;ve gotten way too passive with my faith and my relationship with Christ in the past few years. 2016 should be a year of action.</p>
<h3 id="release-outshape">Release Outshape</h3>
<p>I know right? When is this guy just going to give up? Never. I used to have this goal of releasing it and having it be super successful and letting me keep working on my own things. I&#39;ve really detached myself from how successful Outshape is. I want to create this thing that I&#39;m proud of and release it. If I can do that, I will feel good about the work I put into it.</p>
<h3 id="start-a-podcast">Start a podcast</h3>
<p>I&#39;m keeping this one because I really want to do this. It&#39;s sort of silly, but I just love podcasts and would love to sit around and talk with some friends about something and share it with others. Not every goal has to be huge.</p>
<h3 id="deepen-relationships">Deepen relationships</h3>
<p>Building a bit on my goal to call people from 2015. More than just calling people, I want to talk to them more. I want to spend more time discussing real stuff and putting myself out there. I want to text less. Conversation is vulnerability. Texting is often just information passing.</p>
<h3 id="take-up-less-space">Take up less space</h3>
<p>This covers several things. Continuing to produce less waste. Compost more and buy more things that are recyclable. Continuing to reduce the amount of clutter in my house. If I don&#39;t keep a gift you give me it&#39;s not because I don&#39;t appreciate it. I absolutely do. But if I don&#39;t use it frequently or find it pleasant to look at, I just can&#39;t keep it. And that&#39;s okay. The use of a gift isn&#39;t what matters. It&#39;s the love and relationship the <em>giving</em> of the gift represents.</p>
<hr>


<p>So there it is. Those are the ten things I really want to focus on in 2016. Looking back at the list, it seems clear that I want to spend more time doing and I want to be a better steward of my time and my resources. Here&#39;s to hoping I can meet my goals in 2016 better than in 2015.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-goals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/2016-goals/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:56:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Look Back at 2015]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of the year I wrote about a <a href="https://chrisbrakebill.com/what-i-want-to-do-better-in-2015/">few things</a> I wanted to improve upon in 2015. I just want to take a look back at those and see how I feel like I did. We did have a baby this year so... this could get ugly.</p>
<h3 id="dental-hygiene">Dental Hygiene</h3>
<p>I would say I&#39;m doing better here but not great. Been having some pain lately so I think it&#39;s time to go to the dentist (okay fine it&#39;s long past time to go). I&#39;ve  been flossing and using mouthwash regularly. I think I&#39;ve set myself up for major improvement here in 2015.</p>
<h3 id="exercise">Exercise</h3>
<p>This is a big bucket of fail. I had some good stretches of consistent running. But it broke down a bit in the summer. Being back in Tennessee is definitely going to make this tougher to improve upon in the winter. Not much tennis and basketball either in 2015. Lauren and I recently joined a program with our insurance that gives us access to many gyms around Knoxville (YMCA&#39;s in particular) so I&#39;m hoping we can get going with this.</p>
<h3 id="journaling">Journaling</h3>
<p>I did a lot of this in the first half of the year, but I dropped off later on. Particularly once the baby came. I&#39;m thinking I might try to pick this up again in 2015. I liked the prompt I did early last year. I might try to find something similar this year.</p>
<h3 id="releasing-outshape">Releasing Outshape</h3>
<p>😞 I&#39;m getting there. I made some great progress while I was between jobs. But it&#39;s hard to help raise a baby, work a full time job, <em>and</em> engage in a side hustle.</p>
<h3 id="minimalism">Minimalism</h3>
<p>This one I&#39;m feeling pretty good about. There&#39;s a lot of room to grow but I&#39;ve gotten fairly ruthless about not keeping stuff I don&#39;t love or need. Now if I could just attack my wife&#39;s 3/4 of the closet...</p>
<h3 id="recycling-waste-reduction">Recycling/Waste Reduction</h3>
<p>Another place I feel like I&#39;ve really improved. Having a local recycling service has been the biggest part. We&#39;re sending more stuff into recycling than we are the trash. I&#39;ve replaced a lot of incandescents with LED bulbs. The phrase &quot;just because I can doesn&#39;t mean I should&quot; has been circling my head lately with respect to the resources I use.</p>
<h3 id="improve-my-relationship-with-lauren">Improve my relationship with Lauren</h3>
<p>I think we&#39;ve made strides here. Having a baby has been an amazing experience as a couple. Challenging for sure. But it&#39;s definitely made us both feel more like a team.</p>
<h3 id="go-to-church">Go to church</h3>
<p>I&#39;m really happy with where we are here. We&#39;ve found a church in Knoxville that we love. We&#39;re in a community group there so we&#39;re getting to know some awesome people there. I hope we can continue to grow there in 2016.</p>
<h3 id="read-my-bible">Read my Bible</h3>
<p>Another fail. I need a new Bible this year.</p>
<h3 id="read-more-in-general">Read more in general</h3>
<p>I think I did more of this but it all kind of runs together. There are a few books I remember loving, I&#39;m just not sure if they were 2015 or 2014. I&#39;m gonna try to do a better job keeping track in Goodreads. It&#39;s hard to find time with a baby (this is a common theme).</p>
<h3 id="fewer-screens">Fewer Screens</h3>
<p>There&#39;s good and bad here. We spend a <em>lot</em> of time still watching TV. But I&#39;ve made some strides in reducing my phone use. I&#39;ve deleted a good number of apps and I&#39;m trying to break that instinctual need to just look at my phone. Just enjoyed a two week break from work for Christmas, and I feel like I barely looked at a computer screen. So hooray for that.</p>
<h3 id="call-people">Call People</h3>
<p>👎 Another place I failed. This one has been on my mind lately and it will definitely be something I hope to improve upon in 2016.</p>
<h3 id="start-a-podcast">Start a podcast</h3>
<p>Nope. I still want to do this. I&#39;m just not sure where I will fit it in. And I need to get my buddies all in on it.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/a-look-back-at-2015/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/a-look-back-at-2015/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 13:20:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bye Twitter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Taking a try at something new over the next week or two. I&#39;m gonna stay off Twitter completely. I&#39;m just wondering whether the time and thought I invest there is wasted.  </p>
<p>I&#39;m also gonna try to leave my phone in my car or out of sight more in social situations. I&#39;ve had a lot on my mind about just how my phone (and digital communication in generally) is impairing me socially.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/bye-twitter/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/bye-twitter/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 22:55:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2015 College Football Playoff]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://chrisbrakebill.com/the-real-college-football-playoff/">Last year</a> I presented my idea for a better playoff. I&#39;ve tweaked it a little this year to add a 14 team option instead of 16 team. Basically it&#39;s 4 rounds, conferences champions all get automatic bids, with a couple of at-large teams.</p>
<h2 id="conference-champions">Conference Champions</h2>
<p>First things first, let’s look at who is getting the automatic bids into our tournament.</p>
<table>
<tr><td>AAC</td><td>Houston</td></tr>
<tr><td>ACC</td><td>Clemson</td></tr>
<tr><td>Big XII</td><td>Oklahoma</td></tr>
<tr><td>Big Ten</td><td>Michigan State</td></tr>
<tr><td>Conference USA</td><td>Western Kentucky</td></tr>
<tr><td>MAC</td><td>Bowling Green</td></tr>
<tr><td>Mountain West</td><td>San Diego State</td></tr>
<tr><td>Pac 12</td><td>Stanford</td></tr>
<tr><td>SEC</td><td>Alabama</td></tr>
<tr><td>Sun Belt</td><td>Arkansas State</td></tr>
</table>

<h2 id="at-large-spots">At Large Spots</h2>
<p>So we’ve got 10 conference champions that leaves us 2 or 4 at large spots, depending on the playoff format.</p>
<p>I&#39;m not even going to bother trying to make my own rankings here. The playoff committee goes deep enough to use <a href="espn.go.com/college-football/rankings/_/poll/21/seasontype/2/year/2015/week/15">their rankings</a> to determine who makes the playoff. Adding a couple of extra teams here so you can see who just misses out on making the playoff.</p>
<ol>
<li>Iowa</li>
<li>Ohio State</li>
<li>Notre Dame</li>
<li>Florida State</li>
<li>North Carolina</li>
<li>TCU</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="ranking-the-field">Ranking the Field</h2>
<p>So that gives us our field of 12 to 14 teams. Mostly based on CFP rankings, and doing it myself for some of the lower seeded teams.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr><th>14 Team</th><th>12 Team</th></tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>1. Clemson</td><td>1. Clemson</td></tr>
<tr><td>2. Alabama</td><td>2. Alabama</td></tr>
<tr><td>3. Michigan State</td><td>3. Michigan State</td></tr>
<tr><td>4. Oklahoma</td><td>4. Oklahoma</td></tr>
<tr><td>5. Iowa</td><td>5. Iowa</td></tr>
<tr><td>6. Stanford</td><td>6. Stanford</td></tr>
<tr><td>7. Ohio State</td><td>7. Ohio State</td></tr>
<tr><td>8. Notre Dame</td><td>8. Houston</td></tr>
<tr><td>9. Florida State</td><td>9. Bowling Green</td></tr>
<tr><td>10. Houston</td><td>10. San Diego State</td></tr>
<tr><td>11. Bowling Green</td><td>11. Western Kentucky</td></tr>
<tr><td>12. San Diego State</td><td>12. Arkansas State</td></tr>
<tr><td>13. Western Kentucky</td><td></td></tr>
<tr><td>14. Arkansas State</td><td></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h2 id="the-brackets">The Brackets</h2>
<p><img src="/images/2015-playoff/14_team.png" alt="14 Team"></p>
<p><img src="/images/2015-playoff/12_team.png" alt="12 Team"></p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015-playoff/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/2015-playoff/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 19:57:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Broke]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Spencer Hall:</p><blockquote>
<p>By rule they are separated from the income they make, and by system they are separated from the university education they were promised. They are neither amateurs nor professionals, and effectively moved as undeclared contraband through the United States tax system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fantastic stuff from Spencer Hall. Every time I hear someone talk about how expensive the new Nike gear is, I get sick to my stomach. The amount of money being generated by college football that&#39;s being funneled to coaches, facilities, and administrators is absurd. Especially with everything we&#39;re learning about CTE. These guys are literally putting their lives on the line for room and board. I&#39;ll let Spencer wrap this up...</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Pay them. Pay them what you owe them. Pay them because the worst American tradition is taking things that aren&#39;t yours and calling it destiny or virtue or principle. Pay them because there is no nobility in keeping someone a dollar poorer than they have to be in exchange for honest work. Pay them because any system that deliberately makes people poorer is one of designed cruelty, even at this relatively small scale. Pay them their goddamn money.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></description><link>http://www.everydayshouldbesaturday.com/2015/9/8/9249681/broke</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.everydayshouldbesaturday.com/2015/9/8/9249681/broke</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 02:08:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Update to my morning routine]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="/morning-routine/">previous post</a> about my morning routine, I said my ability to stick to it when I&#39;m not home varied. I&#39;d like to update that and say that on my trip to Victoria for our <a href="https://opdbrooks.exposure.co/metalab-summit">MetaLab Summer Summit</a> last week my routine completely fell apart. </p>
<p>Fortunately, I don&#39;t think it was a failure of the routine, and more a failure of my own. I just wasn&#39;t intentional about keeping it up and making sure it was important enough to attend to every day. I don&#39;t think I realized just how important that structure was, because without it everything feels completely out of order and I feel so unproductive. So I&#39;m already thinking about how I can handle it better the next time I travel, and it will mostly involve being intentional and having a plan for how to adjust my routine to the new location rather than just playing it by ear.</p>
<p>The next big test or change for my routine comes in about two months when <a href="http://charleston.brakebill.me">Charleston</a> comes into the world. No doubt I&#39;m in for big changes and will have to make some more adjustments for her.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/routine-update/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/routine-update/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 13:44:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Slowing Down]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As you can tell, I&#39;ve slowed my posting down a bit here. I&#39;m reducing my time spent focused on writing for the time being. As I&#39;m ramping up at <a href="http://metalab.co">MetaLab</a>, I have less time to work on <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape">Outshape</a>. I&#39;m trying to focus as much time as I can on getting Outshape out the door, which leaves less time for writing. </p>
<p>Rest assured, I&#39;ll still be posting infrequently and I&#39;ve got some plans to do more microblogging here (and slow myself down when it comes to hot takes on Twitter). </p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/slowing-down/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/slowing-down/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 02:34:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Multiple Workspaces]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Ben Brooks:</p><blockquote>
<p>The often cited rule is that the hardest part of any task is starting. When you move to another work area you do so with a plan of what you are doing. So when you arrive at that workstation you start doing that work. And you’ve now just accomplished the “hardest” part of most tasks.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I haven’t tried out any sit/stand desks, but I have gone back and forth between having a standing and a sitting desk in my office. I’ve found that having only one option is suboptimal. As Lauren and I talk about our future home, one of the things I want in my office is multiple places to work, one standing and one sitting, so I can move back and forth as needed.</p>
]]></description><link>https://brooksreview.net/2015/05/multiple-workspaces/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://brooksreview.net/2015/05/multiple-workspaces/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:56:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Choosing Martyrdom]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">J.D. Bentley:</p><blockquote>
<p>This obsession with immediate happiness—which isn’t happiness at all, but some amalgam of selfishness, laziness, and comfort—is at the root of the modern marriage crisis. Marriage is treated as a loose association between two people to maximize happiness. It is characterized by emotionalism, the concept of the One, and the worship of the fairytale ending. Marriage is not sacramental or sacred, it is not set apart, it is merely another potential means to self-satisfaction. This view has contributed to higher divorce rates, lower marriage rates, and, according to my Facebook feed, a whole host of bastard children being robbed of the love, stability, and order of a two-parent home.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great piece by J.D. Bentley on the value of suffering. I’m glad I had an idea about it heading into marriage, but I’ve learned more and more about it every day. There are days where Lauren and I are so different that it just doesn’t make sense that we chose each other. But we did. And we love each other. And we value the committment we made, even when that committment is hard as shit. There’s no doubt being parents will add a whole new world of challenges. But we’re committed to being martyrs every day for each other and for Charleston (though we will no doubt fail at it many times per day).</p>
]]></description><link>http://jdbentley.com/journal/choosing-martyrdom</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jdbentley.com/journal/choosing-martyrdom</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 03:39:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Morning Routine]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite websites right now is <a href="http://mymorningroutine.com">My Morning Routine</a>, where they ask people questions about, shockingly, their morning routine. I&#39;ve always <em>loved</em> mornings. They are my favorite part of the day. I&#39;ve recently gotten into a much better routine, so I thought I&#39;d share it here using the questions from MMR.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-your-morning-routine-">What is your morning routine?</h2>
<p>I pop up every morning between 6:30 and 7 AM. I&#39;ve been progressively trying to get up a little bit earlier. I leave my phone (and alarm) a few steps away from my bed so I have to actually get up to turn it off. If I didn&#39;t do that I would stay in bed for hours.</p>
<p>I slink out of the bedroom and open up the door to my office to let the cats out. They sleep in there because they are two crazy little monsters who will wreak noisy havoc all night.</p>
<p>My first task of the morning is to get some coffee. To be clear, I&#39;m not one of those people who is like <em>OMG I MUST HAVE COFFEE OR I CANNOT FUNCTION</em>. I function fine without it, but I love drinking a cup in the morning. It&#39;s much more about the joy of making and drinking it than the caffeine. Since it&#39;s summer, we try to keep a pitcher of cold brew in the fridge at all times for iced coffee. Otherwise I&#39;ll fire up the kettle for one of the many hot water coffee devices we have. While I&#39;ll drink just about any coffee, it&#39;s always better from Blue Bottle.</p>
<p>Once I&#39;ve got my coffee I do some reading. Email, RSS feeds, Instapaper, magazines, or books. Could be any or all of these. I&#39;m currently reading Marcus Aurelius&#39; <em>Meditations</em> and a book on teaching kids to be better eaters.</p>
<p>After that my schedule varies by day of the week. On Monday, Wednesday, and Friday, I do some work on my iOS game, <a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape">Outshape</a>. On Tuesday and Thursday, I try to write something to get it up on my blog. I&#39;d really prefer to write every day, but if I want to get Outshape released soon I have to put the time in.</p>
<p>After a little over an hour of writing or working, it&#39;s time to get out and run. I&#39;m trying to get myself back into decent shape, so I&#39;m running a mile every day. I&#39;m just trying to get that mile time somewhere I&#39;m satisfied with before I start upping my distance. </p>
<p>After my run I take a quick cool shower, find some breakfast, and feed the cats. At this point my morning is pretty much done and it&#39;s time to get up into my office to work.</p>
<h2 id="how-long-have-you-stuck-with-this-routine-so-far-">How long have you stuck with this routine so far?</h2>
<p>In it&#39;s current iteration, I&#39;ve been using this routine for about a month. Most of the elements existed beforehand, but they were compressed into a shorter time. I would just wake up when I felt like it. But that was before I started work at MetaLab. Now I don&#39;t have all day to do the work that&#39;s just for me.</p>
<h2 id="what-time-do-you-go-to-sleep-">What time do you go to sleep?</h2>
<p>Usually somewhere between 10:30 and 11:30, depending on when Lauren and I eat dinner and what has captivated us on Netflix.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-do-anything-before-going-to-bed-to-make-your-morning-easier-">Do you do anything before going to bed to make your morning easier?</h2>
<p>The aforementioned leaving the phone across the room is a big thing for me. I will shut that alarm off and go back to sleep if I&#39;m not forced to physically get out of bed.</p>
<p>Early on in my routine I would put a little more work into explicitly planning my next morning and day. I&#39;ve gotten into the groove now and don&#39;t do this quite so strictly.</p>
<p>I also <em>like</em> to clean up the kitchen a bit in the evenings when possible. My morning is a lot more pleasant when there isn&#39;t a mess I&#39;m confronted with. But sometimes we eat late and we&#39;re just too tired to deal with it in the evening.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-use-an-alarm-to-wake-you-up-in-the-morning-and-if-so-do-you-ever-hit-the-snooze-button-">Do you use an alarm to wake you up in the morning, and if so do you ever hit the snooze button?</h2>
<p>Yep I use the standard alarm on my phone. Since I have to get out of bed, it&#39;s <strong>very</strong> rare that I hit the snooze button. I won&#39;t say it never happens, but I love mornings too much once I&#39;m up.</p>
<h2 id="how-soon-after-waking-up-do-you-have-breakfast-and-what-do-you-typically-have-">How soon after waking up do you have breakfast, and what do you typically have?</h2>
<p>Generally it&#39;s a couple of hours. A fun fact about me is I don&#39;t have a functioning thyroid gland. So every morning I have to take synthroid. A side effect of that is I&#39;m not particularly hungry until I&#39;ve taken it, and I&#39;m not hungry until at least an hour after I&#39;ve taken it.</p>
<p>What I eat for breakfast is one aspect of my morning I&#39;m not particularly thrilled with. It&#39;s usually either cereal or oatmeal (old fashioned oats, none of that instant crap). Occasionally I&#39;ll have greek yogurt with granola and honey. I&#39;d really like to get more protein but I&#39;m not a huge fan of eggs nor do I like taking a ton of time to make breakfast. I&#39;m thinking about trying out Soylent for my breakfasts.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-have-a-morning-workout-routine-">Do you have a morning workout routine?</h2>
<p>Just my morning run! I&#39;d like to find a gym with a good basketball court, but they&#39;re surprisingly hard to find. I want a nice court to go shoot in the morning, but most gyms just don&#39;t have the space.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-have-a-morning-meditation-routine-and-if-so-what-kind-of-meditation-do-you-practise-">Do you have a morning meditation routine, and if so what kind of meditation do you practise?</h2>
<p>This is the other big aspect of my morning I&#39;d like to improve. I&#39;d like to spend more time reading the bible and in prayer in the morning. Too often it&#39;s the thing that gets pushed aside for all of the other &quot;more productive&quot; stuff.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-answer-email-first-thing-in-the-morning-or-leave-it-until-later-in-the-day-">Do you answer email first thing in the morning, or leave it until later in the day?</h2>
<p>I get very little email that needs answering. But I try to wait as long as possible before looking at it. I don&#39;t get anything urgent and it can be dealt with later in the day when I have less energy.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-use-any-apps-or-products-to-enhance-your-sleep-or-morning-routine-">Do you use any apps or products to enhance your sleep or morning routine?</h2>
<p>Nothing major. I would say f.lux is the biggest help.
I keep my habits in Omnifocus to make sure I&#39;m knocking them out and reviewing them occasionally.</p>
<h2 id="what-and-when-is-your-first-drink-in-the-morning-">What and when is your first drink in the morning?</h2>
<p>Almost always a coffee. Could be iced, or from the aeropress, french press, or chemex. We have an espresso machine, but it&#39;s been struggling lately. One of my hopes for the next year is to upgrade it, because I love a cappuccino or latte in the morning.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-also-follow-this-routine-on-weekends-or-do-you-change-some-steps-">Do you also follow this routine on weekends, or do you change some steps?</h2>
<p>I follow it, but a little more loosely. I tend to sleep a <em>little</em> longer and I don&#39;t run every day on the weekend. As far as reading, writing, and development goes, I tend to just let my mood lead me. I&#39;ll work on (or not work on) whatever I feel like in the moment.</p>
<h2 id="on-days-you-re-not-settled-in-your-home-are-you-able-to-adapt-your-routine-to-fit-in-with-a-different-environment-">On days you’re not settled in your home, are you able to adapt your routine to fit in with a different environment?</h2>
<p>It sort of depends on the environment. Some changes are more friendly to the routine than others. I at least try to get myself up early and do some reading and writing when I can. I really struggle to get exercise when I&#39;m in a different environment.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-you-do-if-you-fail-to-follow-your-morning-routine-and-how-does-this-influence-the-rest-of-your-day-">What do you do if you fail to follow your morning routine, and how does this influence the rest of your day?</h2>
<p>It&#39;s a little stressful. I feel a bit like I&#39;m not as productive. But I try to just find some time in the day to do the important things; running, reading, and writing.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/morning-routine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/morning-routine/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:37:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pain is a gift]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Drew Magary:</p><blockquote>
<p>Finally, the baby came out and made his first cry. And they brought me over to him, and he was covered in blood and amniotic fluid and had vernix in the creases of his skin, but he looked fucking GREAT. His weight was good. His brain was good. His everything was good. All the selfish, terrible thoughts were sandblasted away. No regrets. Then I looked back to my wife, and she was still alive, beautiful as ever. And I burst into tears. I was wearing a surgical mask during the delivery but it got so gummed up with tears and snot that I was basically wearing a used Kleenex. And I called my mom and my wife&#39;s mom and I said, &quot;THEY&#39;RE ALIVE!&quot; because that was all that mattered. He was alive. She was alive. You can deal with anything in this life, so long as you&#39;re not dead.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Fantastic</em> recounting of the birth of his son, who came seven weeks early. It&#39;s terrifying to think about Lauren having to give birth in just a few weeks, but that&#39;s exactly what this was like. So glad he was okay.</p>
]]></description><link>http://deadspin.com/5900973/pain-is-a-gift-and-other-notes-from-a-terrified-father-during-a-seven-week-premature-birth</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://deadspin.com/5900973/pain-is-a-gift-and-other-notes-from-a-terrified-father-during-a-seven-week-premature-birth</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 22:58:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Am A Conservative]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Fantastic piece from J.D. Bentley on exactly what being a conservative means to him. I particularly love this quote from Yuval Levin:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Conservatives tend to see the human person as an incorrigible mass of contradictions: a fallen and imperfect being created in a divine image, a creature possessed of fundamental dignity and inalienable rights but prone to excess and to sin and ever in need of self-restraint and moral formation.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can really start from there when you&#39;re trying to understand how conservatives approach the world.</p>
]]></description><link>http://jdbentley.com/journal/why-i-am-a-conservative</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jdbentley.com/journal/why-i-am-a-conservative</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 12:15:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[NCAA Basketball 2015-2016 Rules Changes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>There are some good changes in here, particularly as it pertains to pace of play...</p>
<ul>
<li>The shot clock is being dropped from 35 to 30 seconds, which should make games a lot more exciting<sup>1</sup>.</li>
<li>Timeouts without 30 seconds of a scheduled media timeout will become media timeouts.</li>
</ul>
<p>They&#39;re also removing the ban on dunking during pregame and halftime warmups. Because dumb rules are dumb.</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-men/article/2015-06-08/ncaa-changes-shot-clock-30-seconds-makes-other-changes-game</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-men/article/2015-06-08/ncaa-changes-shot-clock-30-seconds-makes-other-changes-game</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 13:12:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tyranny of the chicken finger]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Adam McDowell of the National Post:</p><blockquote>
<p>For a generation, many North American parents have indulged children’s picky eating tendencies by sticking them in an endlessly repeating loop of chicken fingers, burgers, pizza, plain pasta, mac and cheese, and grilled cheese sandwiches. Anyone who has sat down for a meal with youngsters over the past 25 years will recognize this list of typical “kids’ foods.” Pushed out of the picture, to varying degrees for different children, are fruits and vegetables and anything else that might challenge them, from spicy delicacies to unfamiliar proteins. To picture what this might look like to a visitor from almost anywhere else in the world, imagine we just mashed up some bread and cheese and mechanically separated chicken flesh together, called it Kiddy Chow, and bought it by the bag to rip open to feed the tots.</p>
<p>Mealtimes for children were quite different just a few decades ago. Over the past few months, I’ve spoken casually and in formal interviews with dozens of people about food and childhood. As a general rule, people who grew up in North America and are now over the age of 30 recall that when they were children, kids ate what the adults ate. Families usually dined together at the table. There might have been foods you didn’t like; depending on the rules of the house you might have been expected to try them or even finish them. Or you might have been free not to, as long as there weren’t too many foods you were refusing. Either way, it wouldn’t have occurred to you that an adult was going jump up from the table to prepare you something precisely to your liking. And if you didn’t eat, you might have to wait quite a while for the next opportunity: Studies show that North American kids snack more often and consume more calories than they did in the 1970s.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With a baby on the way, this is something that has been on my mind more and more. I want to be intentional about what my child eats, and make sure she doesn’t grow up like her dad. </p>
<p>I grew up eating a metric ton (wait, no, not metric) of bagel bites, lean cuisines, mac and cheese, and grilled cheeses. I <em>always</em> wanted the kids menu at restaurants and as embarrassing as it is, I still frequently do. If my wife isn’t around to make dinner or at least plan it, I will stuff my face with <strong>[BRAND NAME]</strong> mac and cheese. I absolutely believe that teaching good and varied eating habits to kids will turn them into healthier eaters as they grow up.</p>
<p><em>Aside: Mom. I love you. You did a great job raising me. You had to raise four of us at a time and it was a freaking war zone. I chewed on piano keys and carved angry messages into desks. I threw some monster tantrums. I really don’t know how you made it out alive.</em></p>
<p>Some of the strategies outlined here are going to be a good guide for how we want to raise our children to eat. I don’t want my child sucked into seductive kids menus. I’m not going to give her whatever she wants to eat all the time. I want her to try new and strange foods and grow up with that sort of culinary curiosity.</p>
<p>Of course there’s no doubt kids tend to emulate their parents. So if I want my kids to be more adventurous in their diets I’m going to have to do the same. I’m trying to do that right now. I’m saying yes to things with more tomatoes and onions than I’m used to. Often times, it turns out that I like what I’m eating just fine. I’d just refused to accept it because it had something that I didn’t like all that much as a kid. Plus, it wasn’t beige. I thrive on the beige to yellow-ish portion of the menu. But fatherhood changes you, and I think this is just one of many ways I’m going to change.</p>
]]></description><link>http://news.nationalpost.com/the-kids-menu</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://news.nationalpost.com/the-kids-menu</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 13:07:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Teacher]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="link_author">Austin Kleon:</p><blockquote>
<p>This is the way I’ve always tried to approach writing, teaching, or speaking on stage: not as an expert, but as a fellow student. I’m trying to learn in the open. I’m letting others look over my shoulder while I figure things out.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I love this. Too often when I say <em>anything</em> on the internet, I feel like if it’s at all technical I have to be an expert who is never wrong. I want to be more okay with sharing what I’m thinking and learning and not being afraid to be wrong.</p>
]]></description><link>http://austinkleon.com/2015/06/14/to-be-a-teacher-and-remain-a-student/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinkleon.com/2015/06/14/to-be-a-teacher-and-remain-a-student/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:31:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[#1 Dad]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Wonderful piece by Ben Shewry about being a chef and a dad.</p>
]]></description><link>http://luckypeach.com/1-dad/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://luckypeach.com/1-dad/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 22:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Cost of a $15 Minimum Wage]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The minimum wage is one of those things that sounds great in theory and always gets people excited, but has a lot of problems. J.D. Bentley covers some of these issues, including fewer jobs for unskilled workers, fewer opportunities for development, and a climate the pushes more jobs under the table and into the hands of illegal immigrants.</p>
]]></description><link>http://jdbentley.com/journal/the-cost-of-a-15-dollar-minimum-wage</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jdbentley.com/journal/the-cost-of-a-15-dollar-minimum-wage</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 12:33:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Soylent]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Soylent is being talked about more and more, particularly in the tech world. The New York Times <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/25/technology/in-busy-silicon-valley-protein-powder-is-in-demand.html?_r=0">wrote</a> about engineers who are ditching lunch so they can get more work in…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Boom times in Silicon Valley call for hard work, and hard work — at least in technology land — means that coders, engineers and venture capitalists are turning to liquid meals with names like Schmoylent, Soylent, Schmilk and People Chow. The protein-packed products that come in powder form are inexpensive and quick and easy to make — just shake with water, or in the case of Schmilk, milk. While athletes and dieters have been drinking their dinner for years, Silicon Valley’s workers are now increasingly chugging their meals, too, so they can more quickly get back to their computer work. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is just the kind of ridiculous attitude about something that comes from Silicon Valley. Hustle. Grind. Drink lunch at your desk so you can <em>keep on working</em>.  Give me a break.</p>
<p>I find soylent incredibly interesting, but not so I can spend more time at my desk working. Something more like <a href="http://www.insignificant.info/blog-native/2015/5/21/soylent">this</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best meals to replace with Soylent are the meals you aren’t excited about. I’m talking about boring sandwiches, generic lunches near the office, hasty breakfasts, or even “I just need to eat something” dinners. Those aren’t fun eating experiences. They don’t bring delight to your life. They probably cost more than they should, waste time, and are often unhealthy. If you are on a diet, these are the meals where you are likely to cheat and then regret it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I often don’t eat breakfast or I eat crap for lunch because I don’t have the time, energy, or materials to make something proper and decent for me. I see Soylent as a good solution to that. It’s an easily made and balanced meal to replace all that junk. </p>
<p>I also like that I don’t have to worry about the conditions soylent ingredients were raised in. Unlike the bacon and eggs I had for breakfast or the burger I’m having for lunch, the ingredients to soylent don’t require massive slaughterhouses. </p>
<p>I don’t want to stop eating food I enjoy. I can still go out to dinner with family and friends. Or I can have the occasional bacon and eggs in the morning. I just want to replace some of the crap I waste time on with something healthier and easy to make. I think Soylent provides that.</p>
]]></description><link>http://chrisbrakebill.com/soylent/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrisbrakebill.com/soylent/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 12:27:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>