<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-21T03:44:33.814Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Miscarriage]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/20/miscarriage/</id>
    <published>2014-06-21T03:43:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-21T03:43:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had originally planned to call this post “Surprise”, because that’s exactly what it was when Lauren and I found out we were going to have our first child. But as we neared our 6th week, and our first ultrasound, our excitement was turning into fear. Blood was coming when it shouldn’t have been. </p>
<p>A week and three ultrasounds later, our baby was gone.</p>
<p>The emotions of going from “oh crap we’re having a baby” to “I can’t wait to have this child” to “I don’t know what’s happening” and finally to “Your baby isn’t there anymore” are brutal.</p>
<p>When we first found out Lauren was pregnant, we had to allow ourselves some time to grieve. Not to grieve the new life we created, but to grieve the loss of our plans for the next couple of years. This wasn’t supposed to happen yet. I wanted to get a dog first. But that very quickly changed to excitement (and then quickly back and forth between fear and excitement).</p>
<p>The doctors told us that this isn’t uncommon, and happens more than 20% of the time. Usually it happens because of severe genetic defects, and the body stops the pregnancy before it gets going. I have to marvel at the wonder of God’s creation. That He makes our bodies stop these things when He has to, to prevent pain and grief down the road.</p>
<p>Conversely, I have to think about the babies born with various defects and disease. We may question why God would put those babies and families through that. But God keeps those babies going because he knows they are strong enough and their purpose important enough to bring them into this world.</p>
<p>We are so thankful to the close friends and family who were around to love and share this with us. While we’re heartbroken, we’re glad to have the opportunity to talk about something that just isn’t talked about enough, failed pregnancy. </p>
<p>I was driven a bit mad even in the few shorts weeks we had that I couldn’t tell people. I found the idea of waiting until you’re far in and complication free absurd. And now, after this experience, I find it even more ridiculous. You’re denying yourself the support and love of people around you. Is it uncomfortable telling people you lost your baby not long after you told them you were pregnant? Absolutely. But I’d take that every time over dealing with this fear and pain alone. Having to tell my parents, “oh by the way, we were going to have a baby, but we had a miscarriage” was way worse than if they had been there through the whole experience. I’m SO thankful for the people close to us in Orlando who we told and were there to support us through every scary moment.</p>
<p>This child was created in passion, when… certain precautions weren’t taken (ew.. sex.. right?). Before the miscarriage, I’d had a dream that we had a girl, and that’s as good as anything to go on, right? We wanted to memorialize her, so we named her Emma. One of Lauren’s supervisors at school said that she must be a full and passionate woman with God now. That is a thrilling thing to think about. </p>
<p>I can’t wait to meet you one day, Emma.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Game of Thrones Cover]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.vanityfair.com/vf-hollywood/game-of-thrones-dixieland-cover"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/17/game-of-thrones-cover/</id>
    <published>2014-06-17T22:32:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T22:33:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Incredible cover of the Game of Thrones theme.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[To Teachers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/6/13/to-teachers"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/17/to-teachers/</id>
    <published>2014-06-17T14:39:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T14:39:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes to everything here. My sister is a teacher and I’m incredibly proud of her. Teachers are overworked and underpaid.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Filling a Notebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sanspoint.com/archives/2014/05/19/filling-notebook/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/16/filling-a-notebook/</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T12:55:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T12:55:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been using the <a href="http://bulletjournal.com" target="_blank">Bullet Journal</a> method for managing my tasks and notes. As much as I <strong>want</strong> a digital, cloud based task manager to be my go to, there’s just something about putting a pen to paper that sticks better with me. I suspect it has to do with growing up in a world where I had to write something down to record it.</p>
<p>I’d like to use it more to record thoughts, so that I could write more and better. I often find that the little nugget that was in my head disappears so quickly into an abyss of thoughts and memories.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Do More of This Stuff]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/wren-lanier/2014-june-14"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/16/do-more-of-this-stuff/</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T12:51:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T12:51:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A good list of things to do more of, and some things to do less of.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reading With Intention]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/lectio-divina"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/10/reading-with-intention/</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T12:44:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T15:44:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chris Bowler:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Take time to read, re-read, and meditate on this piece of human thought you’ve chosen to ingest. Truly ingest it; if it resonates with you, allow it to change you. This is what I want to do with Scripture, but also any topic that I enjoy; web design, typography, woodworking … you name it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is great stuff in regards to scripture reading and all other reading.  With both I tend to find myself reading to get it done. I don’t take time and really think about what I’m reading. I just want to quickly absorb the facts. It translates straight into my writing here as well. I see a thing I want to share and I just share it without any thoughtful commentary.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Judge John Hodgman Ep. 161: Cold Case]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.maximumfun.org/judge-john-hodgman/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/10/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case/</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T12:35:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T15:35:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you aren’t listening to John Hodgman’s podcast, you’re really missing out. Basically he acts as judge in an argument between couples, friends, and families. They present their cases and he rules. Hilarious.</p>
<p>In this particularly hilarious episode, a couple debates whether they need to add air conditioning to their apartment in Berlin. We learn about Germans’ fear of drafts and the wonder that is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tropical_Islands_Resort" target="_blank">Tropical Islands Resort</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Listen]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/jeff-eaton/2014-may-27"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/listen/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T03:25:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:25:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Defending ourselves is always easier than listening to difficult truths.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Accurate. It’s the natural reaction and it’s so incredibly destructive.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Alton Browncast: Andrew Zimmern]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nerdist.com/pepisode/the-alton-browncast-48-andrew-zimmern/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/the-alton-browncast-andrew-zimmern/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T03:22:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:22:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just an incredible listen. I’ve always loved <a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/bizarre-foods" target="_blank">Bizarre Foods</a>, but I never knew Andrew Zimmern’s story. I can’t remember the exact quote, but he said something like “I’ll never start a business venture without a charitable component”. A fantastic way to do things.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[John Oliver on 'Preventing Cable Company F&%kery']]></title>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fpbOEoRrHyU&feature=youtu.be"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/04/john-oliver-on-preventing-cable-company-fkery/</id>
    <published>2014-06-04T11:39:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-04T11:39:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brilliant. Hilarious. It would be funnier if it weren’t so true…</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Servant Leadership]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/leadership"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/30/servant-leadership/</id>
    <published>2014-05-30T22:22:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-30T22:22:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chris Bowler:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>the truth is, you (and I) can adopt a servant leader mentality no matter what position we’re in. Doing everything you can to ensure your coworkers succeed is the best habit we can all adopt. You may not be setting the vision for your company or assigning work, but you can put energy into making your teammates the best they can be.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some great advice on leadership.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Pastry Box]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/relly-annett-baker/2014-may-24"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/30/write/</id>
    <published>2014-05-30T22:21:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-30T22:21:35.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Whenever I fret and flail (frequently) while trying to create thing, I say to myself “Someone has to be the shittiest writer in the world but while there are people who still get paid to make up horoscopes, it won’t be me.” Then I write. </p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reeder 2 for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.reederapp.com/mac/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/29/reeder-2-for-mac/</id>
    <published>2014-05-29T15:23:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-29T15:23:14.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m tempted to be cheap and whine about having to pay more since I bought Reeder (this is what the App Store economy has done to us). This is the <em>best</em> RSS app for Mac and I use it on a daily basis. Silvio Rizzi has put in the work to create a <em>beautiful</em> application, which is not easy to do on the Mac. He deserves to get paid. Honestly he could charge twice as much and I’d still happily pay for it.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Right Way To Copy]]></title>
    <link href="http://david-smith.org/blog/2014/05/18/the-right-way-to-copy/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/24/the-right-way-to-copy/</id>
    <published>2014-05-24T11:21:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-24T11:21:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David Smith:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good copying learns from another’s innovation and then applies it in a novel way to a new context in a way that doesn’t diminish the source invention.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good stuff. This is something that has been on my mind as I’ve been working on an iOS game in my spare time. It’s inspired by some of my favorite games, but it’s also unique. Sometimes it’s hard not to feel like people will look at it and say he just ripped this or that off another game. He is invalid. David Smith explains how you can take cues without ‘ripping off’.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Chained Wimbledon: The Joys and Perils of Prison Tennis]]></title>
    <link href="http://fittish.deadspin.com/chained-wimbledon-the-joys-and-perils-of-prison-tennis-1576826012"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/21/prison-tennis/</id>
    <published>2014-05-21T12:54:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-21T12:54:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The class perception of tennis is both fascinating and depressing. There are a large number of great athletes that miss out on tennis because of that perception.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[If Internet Providers Ran Public Services]]></title>
    <link href="http://theweek.com/cartoons/index/261623/editorial-cartoon-net-neutrality"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/16/if-internet-providers-ran-public-services/</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T13:54:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T14:52:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Funny and depressing.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Competitive-Balance Argument Against Paying Atheletes is Bullshit]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/the-competitive-balance-argument-against-paying-athlete-1576638830"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/15/the-competitivebalance-argument-against-paying-atheletes-is-bullshit/</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T19:10:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-15T19:10:43.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>As expected, a rigorous statistical analysis confirms what every fan of any powerhouse team already knew: Teams with recruiting success tend to remain successful year after year and teams without much success tend to remain unsuccessful. Fixing the price of a year of a college athlete’s service to be comparable across all schools does not result in anything like competitive balance, and statistically, the level of imbalance has been growing over the last six years. It’s time to stop using that as an excuse why college football should be allowed to collude its way out of paying market rates for talent.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It turns out the powerhouse schools are successful because they spend so much more money on recruiting and facilities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But how would things look under a pay-for-play model? Would the imbalance actually get worse?</p>
<p>Maybe not. If anything, the economics of price competition argue that as you let schools use money directly as a tool in attracting talent, you may empower mid-level schools to splurge on a would-be starter who might otherwise accept an offer at a top-tier school and end up riding the bench. When stars and benchwarmers all get the same compensation package, there’s no way for a smaller school to show they really want a player much more than the big school, which is free to stockpile talent. Both schools can claim they want the player, both can send 700 letters in one day, etc. The best way to show you mean business and that the other school is just engaging in what economists call “cheap talk” is price competition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>More Andy Schwarz being insightful and on point. Remember this stuff next time someone argues that paying players would be unfair or that if players get paid, they all have to get the same stipend.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Johnny Express]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/2014/05/12/johnnyexpress/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/12/johnny-express/</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T21:43:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T21:43:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Short of the Week is one of my new favorite sites. Definitely worth checking out to if you like video shorts (I only subscribe to the <a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/category/style/3d-animation/" target="_blank">3D Animated feed</a>).</p>
<p>This one is hilariously terrifying. I’ve got the worst attention span, so when a video makes me stop checking the time to see when it ends, I know it’s captured me.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How Athletic Departments (And The Media) Fudge The Cost Of Scholarships]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-1570827027"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/09/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-of-scholarships/</id>
    <published>2014-05-10T00:35:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-10T00:35:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The usual brilliance from Andy Schwarz.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA['Authors Should Just Write' - Or, Maybe They Shouldn't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecramped.com/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt-james-shelley/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/08/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt/</id>
    <published>2014-05-08T15:34:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-08T15:34:13.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Patrick Rhone:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A reminder that, in order to be better writers, we must be better observers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is something I need to keep better in the front of my mind. It always feels like my writing is directly correlated with my reading. And my reading tends to be impatient and sometimes thoughtless.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
