<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T15:36:16.376Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[imchrisbrakebill@icloud.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Judge John Hodgman Ep. 161: Cold Case]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.maximumfun.org/judge-john-hodgman/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/10/judge-john-hodgman-ep-161-cold-case/</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T15:35:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T15:35:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you aren’t listening to John Hodgman’s podcast, you’re really missing out. Basically he acts as judge in an argument between couples, friends, and families. They present their cases and he rules. Hilarious.</p>
<p>In this particularly hilarious episode, a couple debates whether they need to add air conditioning to their apartment in Berlin. We learn about Germans’ fear of drafts and the wonder that is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tropical_Islands_Resort" target="_blank">Tropical Islands Resort</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Listen]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/jeff-eaton/2014-may-27"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/listen/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T06:25:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:25:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Defending ourselves is always easier than listening to difficult truths.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Accurate. It’s the natural reaction and it’s so incredibly destructive.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Alton Browncast: Andrew Zimmern]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nerdist.com/pepisode/the-alton-browncast-48-andrew-zimmern/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/05/the-alton-browncast-andrew-zimmern/</id>
    <published>2014-06-06T06:22:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-06T03:22:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just an incredible listen. I’ve always loved <a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/bizarre-foods" target="_blank">Bizarre Foods</a>, but I never knew Andrew Zimmern’s story. I can’t remember the exact quote, but he said something like “I’ll never start a business venture without a charitable component”. A fantastic way to do things.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[John Oliver on 'Preventing Cable Company F&%kery']]></title>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fpbOEoRrHyU&feature=youtu.be"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/06/04/john-oliver-on-preventing-cable-company-fkery/</id>
    <published>2014-06-04T14:39:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-04T11:39:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brilliant. Hilarious. It would be funnier if it weren’t so true…</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Servant Leadership]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/leadership"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/30/servant-leadership/</id>
    <published>2014-05-31T01:22:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-30T22:22:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chris Bowler:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>the truth is, you (and I) can adopt a servant leader mentality no matter what position we’re in. Doing everything you can to ensure your coworkers succeed is the best habit we can all adopt. You may not be setting the vision for your company or assigning work, but you can put energy into making your teammates the best they can be.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some great advice on leadership.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Pastry Box]]></title>
    <link href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/relly-annett-baker/2014-may-24"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/30/write/</id>
    <published>2014-05-31T01:21:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-30T22:21:35.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Whenever I fret and flail (frequently) while trying to create thing, I say to myself “Someone has to be the shittiest writer in the world but while there are people who still get paid to make up horoscopes, it won’t be me.” Then I write. </p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Reeder 2 for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.reederapp.com/mac/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/29/reeder-2-for-mac/</id>
    <published>2014-05-29T18:23:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-29T15:23:14.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m tempted to be cheap and whine about having to pay more since I bought Reeder (this is what the App Store economy has done to us). This is the <em>best</em> RSS app for Mac and I use it on a daily basis. Silvio Rizzi has put in the work to create a <em>beautiful</em> application, which is not easy to do on the Mac. He deserves to get paid. Honestly he could charge twice as much and I’d still happily pay for it.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Right Way To Copy]]></title>
    <link href="http://david-smith.org/blog/2014/05/18/the-right-way-to-copy/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/24/the-right-way-to-copy/</id>
    <published>2014-05-24T14:21:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-24T11:21:57.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David Smith:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good copying learns from another’s innovation and then applies it in a novel way to a new context in a way that doesn’t diminish the source invention.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good stuff. This is something that has been on my mind as I’ve been working on an iOS game in my spare time. It’s inspired by some of my favorite games, but it’s also unique. Sometimes it’s hard not to feel like people will look at it and say he just ripped this or that off another game. He is invalid. David Smith explains how you can take cues without ‘ripping off’.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Chained Wimbledon: The Joys and Perils of Prison Tennis]]></title>
    <link href="http://fittish.deadspin.com/chained-wimbledon-the-joys-and-perils-of-prison-tennis-1576826012"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/21/prison-tennis/</id>
    <published>2014-05-21T15:54:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-21T12:54:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The class perception of tennis is both fascinating and depressing. There are a large number of great athletes that miss out on tennis because of that perception.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[If Internet Providers Ran Public Services]]></title>
    <link href="http://theweek.com/cartoons/index/261623/editorial-cartoon-net-neutrality"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/16/if-internet-providers-ran-public-services/</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T16:54:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T14:52:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Funny and depressing.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Competitive-Balance Argument Against Paying Atheletes is Bullshit]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/the-competitive-balance-argument-against-paying-athlete-1576638830"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/15/the-competitivebalance-argument-against-paying-atheletes-is-bullshit/</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T22:10:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-15T19:10:43.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>As expected, a rigorous statistical analysis confirms what every fan of any powerhouse team already knew: Teams with recruiting success tend to remain successful year after year and teams without much success tend to remain unsuccessful. Fixing the price of a year of a college athlete’s service to be comparable across all schools does not result in anything like competitive balance, and statistically, the level of imbalance has been growing over the last six years. It’s time to stop using that as an excuse why college football should be allowed to collude its way out of paying market rates for talent.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It turns out the powerhouse schools are successful because they spend so much more money on recruiting and facilities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But how would things look under a pay-for-play model? Would the imbalance actually get worse?</p>
<p>Maybe not. If anything, the economics of price competition argue that as you let schools use money directly as a tool in attracting talent, you may empower mid-level schools to splurge on a would-be starter who might otherwise accept an offer at a top-tier school and end up riding the bench. When stars and benchwarmers all get the same compensation package, there’s no way for a smaller school to show they really want a player much more than the big school, which is free to stockpile talent. Both schools can claim they want the player, both can send 700 letters in one day, etc. The best way to show you mean business and that the other school is just engaging in what economists call “cheap talk” is price competition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>More Andy Schwarz being insightful and on point. Remember this stuff next time someone argues that paying players would be unfair or that if players get paid, they all have to get the same stipend.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Johnny Express]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/2014/05/12/johnnyexpress/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/12/johnny-express/</id>
    <published>2014-05-13T00:43:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T21:43:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Short of the Week is one of my new favorite sites. Definitely worth checking out to if you like video shorts (I only subscribe to the <a href="http://www.shortoftheweek.com/category/style/3d-animation/" target="_blank">3D Animated feed</a>).</p>
<p>This one is hilariously terrifying. I’ve got the worst attention span, so when a video makes me stop checking the time to see when it ends, I know it’s captured me.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How Athletic Departments (And The Media) Fudge The Cost Of Scholarships]]></title>
    <link href="http://regressing.deadspin.com/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-1570827027"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/09/how-athletic-departments-and-the-media-fudge-the-cost-of-scholarships/</id>
    <published>2014-05-10T03:35:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-10T00:35:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The usual brilliance from Andy Schwarz.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA['Authors Should Just Write' - Or, Maybe They Shouldn't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecramped.com/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt-james-shelley/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/08/authors-should-just-write-or-maybe-they-shouldnt/</id>
    <published>2014-05-08T18:34:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-08T15:34:13.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Patrick Rhone:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A reminder that, in order to be better writers, we must be better observers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is something I need to keep better in the front of my mind. It always feels like my writing is directly correlated with my reading. And my reading tends to be impatient and sometimes thoughtless.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Kevin Durant Wins NBA MVP]]></title>
    <link href="http://espn.go.com/video/clip?id=10893208&ex_cid=sportscenter"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/07/kevin-durant-wins-nba-mvp/</id>
    <published>2014-05-07T15:21:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-07T12:21:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As if I didn’t already have a huge man crush on Kevin Durant, this MVP speech is unbelievable.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[B.S. Report - Chuck Klosterman 5/1/14]]></title>
    <link href="http://espn.go.com/espnradio/play?id=10870177"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/05/02/bs-report-chuck-klosterman-5114/</id>
    <published>2014-05-02T19:50:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-02T16:50:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really thoughtful conversation between Bill Simmons and Chuck Klosterman. Near the end they really hit on what is SCARY about this situation. The ability for an internet mob to mobilize.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Help Preserve Net Neutrality]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/help-preserve-net-neutrality/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/help-preserve-net-neutrality/</id>
    <published>2014-04-28T03:11:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-28T00:11:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a <a href="https://petitions.whitehouse.gov/petition/maintain-true-net-neutrality-protect-freedom-information-united-states/9sxxdBgy" target="_blank">White House petition</a> and <a href="http://www.savetheinternet.com/sti-home" target="_blank">petition</a> sponsored by the Free Press.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Pen and Paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbowler.com/journal/pen-and-paper"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/27/pen-and-paper/</id>
    <published>2014-04-28T03:08:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-28T00:08:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this post from Chris Bowler. In the past 6-ish months, I’ve found myself in a similar mode. I’ve always wanted my task list to be digital. I’ve wanted it available on all of my various platforms synced through the cloud. For a while, I was an avid <a href="http://culturedcode.com" target="_blank">Things</a> user. I’ve also experimented with <a href="http://trello.com" target="_blank">Trello</a> (I still use it as sort of a long term “issue tracker”).</p>
<p>But late last year, when I discovered the <a href="http://bulletjournal.com" target="_blank">Bullet Journal</a> system, I decided to dive in. There’s just something about picking up a pen and writing physically that connects with my brain more. I more like I know what I have to do, and I feel more accomplished when I can check something off. </p>
<p>I don’t subscribe religiously to every little bit, but I think you have to find what works for you. I’d like to put more notes and events in to log myself. I’ve also been playing a bit with the Omnifocus 2 beta for keeping track of longer term tasks. But for managing my day to day, having a pen and a notebook has been fantastic.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The FCC Continues to Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2014/04/23/fcc-net-neutrality"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/23/the-fcc-continues-to-suck/</id>
    <published>2014-04-24T02:36:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-23T23:36:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The original story is <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/24/technology/fcc-new-net-neutrality-rules.html?_r=1" target="_blank">here</a>. Linking to Gruber because he links to an Obama quote. This was one thing I thought Obama would nail, and this administration has <strong>completely</strong> failed us. The FCC is trying to destroy the internet.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Vox: Why the government should provide internet access]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.vox.com/2014/4/6/5587138/susan-crawford-internet-public-option"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/04/23/vox_why_the_government_should_provide_internet_access/</id>
    <published>2014-04-23T16:58:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-23T13:58:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m far from a supporter of too much government, but the internet is one of those world changing things that requires an exception.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
