<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-23T04:44:52.500Z</updated>
  <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Brakebill]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@brakebill.me]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Here's Why Public WiFi is a Public Health Hazard]]></title>
    <link href="https://medium.com/matter/heres-why-public-wifi-is-a-public-health-hazard-dd5b8dcb55e6"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/22/heres-why-public-wifi-is-a-public-health-hazard/</id>
    <published>2014-10-22T12:42:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T12:42:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Maurits Martijn:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>We visit yet another cafe. My last request to Slotboom is to show me what he would do if he wanted to really harm me. He asks me to go to Live.com (the Microsoft email site) and enter a random username and password. A few seconds later, the information I just typed appears on his screen. “Now I have the login details of your email account,” Slotboom says. “The first thing I would do is change the password of your account and indicate to other services you use that I have forgotten my password. Most people use the same email account for all services. And those new passwords will then be sent to your mailbox, which means I will have them at my disposal as well.” We do the same for Facebook: Slotboom is able to intercept the login name and password I entered with relative ease.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Why you should think twice about connecting to public WiFi. If you’re going to use an untrusted network, you really should use a secured VPN like <a href="https://www.getcloak.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Cloak</a>.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/22/heres-why-public-wifi-is-a-public-health-hazard/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Machine Setup]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/16/machine-setup/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/16/machine-setup/</id>
    <published>2014-10-17T03:34:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-17T03:40:11.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Developers like control. We like things to be just how we like. It tends to take some time to get things that way. This becomes a bit of a problem when you need to do a clean OS install or move to a new machine. How do you restore shell settings? Install node packages? Install your favorite apps?</p>
<p>There are a lot of solutions out there for automating system setups like <a href="https://www.vagrantup.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Vagrant</a> and <a href="https://boxen.github.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Boxen</a> but those seem a little heavy for a personal setup (though I’m open to suggestions otherwise).</p>
<p>In 2012, I had the chance to take a sort of git crash course from Github’s <a href="https://twitter.com/matthewmccull" target="_blank" rel="external">Matthew McCullough</a> and encountered his system setup <a href="https://github.com/matthewmccullough/dotfiles" target="_blank" rel="external">process</a>. I’ve been using the zsh aliases and oh-my-zsh for a long while with some minor tweaks, but after a recent clean install I decided to really make it work.</p>
<p><a href="http://brew.sh" target="_blank" rel="external">Brew</a> is a fantastic tool for installing packages that you want. But the real game changer for me was <a href="http://caskroom.io" target="_blank" rel="external">Cask</a>. It installs Mac applications automatically right from the script. You’re limited to apps that have been added by the community and you can’t install the apps you’ve bought on the Mac App Store, but it’s a great start.</p>
<p>Now when I load up a fresh OS X install all I have to do is install Dropbox and let it sync, go into my dotfiles folder and run </p>
<pre>_setupdotfiles.zsh</pre>

<p>And I’m set. I’m sure I’ll find improvements along the way. But I thought I’d share <a href="https://github.com/braker1nine/dotfiles" target="_blank" rel="external">my setup</a> so it might benefit someone else.</p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Sleeping Without Phones]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/16/sleeping-without-phones/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/10/16/sleeping-without-phones/</id>
    <published>2014-10-16T11:55:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-16T11:55:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back, Dan Benjamin and Merlin Mann discussed how blue light affects our sleep on <a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/160" target="_blank" rel="external">Back to Work</a>. It was a really fantastic discussion and it resonated with my own experiences. I tended to sit up late at night, staring at my phone and wondering why I wasn’t sleepy.</p>
<p>They link <a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-light-affects-our-sleep/#axzz2uMAnScJH" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a> where Mark Sisson dives into the science of why blue light keeps us awake:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blue light regulates our secretion of melatonin, the sleep hormone. Exposed to blue light, we limit the production of melatonin, and we stay alert and awake; in the absence of blue light, melatonin production ramps up, and we get sleepy. This system worked quite well for a long time. Reddish light from fire (our formerly primary source of nighttime illumination) has little to no effect on melatonin production, so sleep wasn’t disrupted when we relied on fire. These days, though, we’re subject to a steady barrage of blue light. During the day, blue light (natural or unnatural) isn’t much of a problem because we’re supposed to be awake, but at night, when we’re “supposed” to be getting ready to sleep, we tend to sit in front of blue light-emanating appliances, and our sleep suffers for it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’m generally a skeptical guy, but this felt anecdotally right to me. I already had <a href="https://justgetflux.com" target="_blank" rel="external">f.lux</a> installed on my MacBook and felt at night as if <em>it was making me</em> tired.</p>
<p>In addition, I moved my phone charger to the office and left it there at night. Not having it next to me has taken away the temptation to look at it. That is a temptation I cannot resist. <strong>IT’S SO CLOSE. I CAN REACH IT INDY.</strong> Since my Fitbit broke, I’ve moved my phone back into the bedroom for alarm purposes, but I keep it across the room. It’s actually fantastic because it keeps me from staring at the phone at night and forces me to get up in the morning to shut it off. The only time I keep my phone on the nightstand anymore is when I’m on call.</p>
<p>I was frequently laying in bed, unable to fall asleep, and then finally getting up to go downstairs and read myself into a coma (Kindle FTW), but I haven’t done that in months it seems. I still have some nights where I struggle to sleep, but that’s usually due to shoulder pain and having another human taking up space in the bed. I like to really spread my elbows out, and they can do damage. <strong>(MARRIAGE TIP: Use separate blankets. Thank me later).</strong></p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Song of the Introvert]]></title>
    <link href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-song-of-the-introvert/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/17/the-song-of-the-introvert/</id>
    <published>2014-09-17T14:35:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-17T14:35:04.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>You are a threat.</p>
<p>It’s a strong word. I don’t mean that you intend pain, injury, or damage. But I’m an introvert and you – as a new unknown human – are a threat to me. I don’t know what you want and you most definitely want something and until I figure that out, you’re a threat.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want to understand me and other introverts better…</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/17/the-song-of-the-introvert/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Shocking Truth About Yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://jdbentley.com/journal/the-shocking-truth-about-yourself"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/03/the-shocking-truth-about-yourself/</id>
    <published>2014-09-04T02:30:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-04T02:30:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The greatest evil is this: pride, avarice, lust, envy, gluttony, anger, and sloth. Avoid those and you’ll arrive at their polar opposites, which are the greatest good: humility, charity, chastity, kindness, temperance, patience, and diligence.</p>
<p>If you lack purpose, if your life is a mess, then you are surely practicing, in some measure, the evils and failing to practice the good. There’s no easy fix for that. There’s no expert for that. There are no “12-steps” or “30-days” that can turn that around for you. It’s a choice made daily and fought for by the minute. It’s exhausting.</p>
<p>But it’s the only thing that works. Anything else is snake oil.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>JD Bentley has one of my favorite websites to read. So many things I read fast and carelessly. But I know when he puts something out there it’s worth the time to slowly take in.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/03/the-shocking-truth-about-yourself/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Pleasing a person who is not in the room]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/08/pleasing-the-person-thats-not-in-the-room.html"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/02/pleasing/</id>
    <published>2014-09-03T02:15:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-03T02:15:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seth Godin:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>It’s the boss’s job to continually ask, “is this the most daring vision of your work?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is how easy it is to prevent stagnation.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/09/02/pleasing/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Fantasy Football Fantasy]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qMor6dL0LfI"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/25/fantasy-football-fantasy/</id>
    <published>2014-08-26T02:35:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-26T02:35:31.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Mannings. Always gold.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/25/fantasy-football-fantasy/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Good at the Beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/05/good-at-the-beginning.html"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/20/good-at-the-beginning/</id>
    <published>2014-08-21T01:06:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-21T01:06:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seth Godin:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Every rejection is a gift. A chance to learn and to do it better next time. An opportunity to figure out how to bounce, not break. Don’t waste them.</p>
</blockquote>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/20/good-at-the-beginning/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Slow Web]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.idonethis.com/the-slow-web-movement/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/20/the-slow-web/</id>
    <published>2014-08-21T00:30:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-21T00:30:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Walter Chen:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>History will probably laugh at our time’s attempt to impose a mentality of industrial production upon creative work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Really love the ‘mantra’ put forth by iDoneThis. If you’re not following their blog you’re missing out.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/20/the-slow-web/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[You're 16. You're a Pedophile. You Don't Want to Hurt Anyone. What Do You Do Now?]]></title>
    <link href="https://medium.com/matter/youre-16-youre-a-pedophile-you-dont-want-to-hurt-anyone-what-do-you-do-now-e11ce4b88bdb"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/15/youre-16-youre-a-pedophile-you-dont-want-to-hurt-anyone-what-do-you-do-now/</id>
    <published>2014-08-15T21:38:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T21:38:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow. It’s hard to do, but it lends a bit of humanity to a group of people we have a hard time seeing as human.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/15/youre-16-youre-a-pedophile-you-dont-want-to-hurt-anyone-what-do-you-do-now/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Lets Build A Traditional City]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewalexanderprice.com/blog20130330.php"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/15/city/</id>
    <published>2014-08-15T13:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T13:39:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An old post that resurfaced this week. I find this really fascinating, particularly the move to a more European style of city construction. Our sprawling cities with wide roads and huge parking lots suck.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/15/city/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Empathy]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattgemmell.com/empathy/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/08/empathy/</id>
    <published>2014-08-08T16:14:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-08T16:14:37.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matt Gemmell:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A friend of mine told me that, when dealing with people, it’s best to assume positive intent. You can view it as a shortcut (since, truthfully, the vast majority of people do have positive intent), but more importantly it’s a conscious choice that makes the world a better place for you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some excellent advice from Matt Gemmell.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/08/empathy/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Why I am leaving the best job I ever had]]></title>
    <link href="http://maxschireson.com/2014/08/05/1137/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/08/why-i-am-leaving-the-best-job-i-ever-had/</id>
    <published>2014-08-08T16:08:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-08T16:08:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Max Schireson:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Friends and colleagues often ask my wife how she balances her job and motherhood. Somehow, the same people don’t ask me.</p>
<p>A few months ago, I decided the only way to balance was by stepping back from my job. MongoDB is a special company. In my nearly 4 years at the company, we have raised $220 million, grown the team 15x and grown sales 30x. We have amazing customers, a great product which gets better with every release, the strongest team I have ever worked with, and incredible momentum in the market. The future is bright and MongoDB deserves a leader who can be “all-in” and make the most of the opportunity.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, I cannot be that leader given the geography of the majority of the company in New York and my family in California.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It says a lot about our society that men aren’t asked these same questions. Fatherhood is <em>important</em>. Kudos to Max Schireson.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/08/why-i-am-leaving-the-best-job-i-ever-had/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[SEC Network: Tennessee]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/07/sec-network-tennessee/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/07/sec-network-tennessee/</id>
    <published>2014-08-07T23:48:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T21:33:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><br></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/NhsEqOdx8Tk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Being Wrong]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/8/1/being-wrong"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/04/being-wrong/</id>
    <published>2014-08-05T01:08:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-05T01:08:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Casey Liss:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>once you accept the beauty and utility of being wrong, “putting something out there” quickly becomes one important step on the path to being right.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So much good here from Casey and <a href="http://inessential.com/2014/07/31/how_to_be_wrong_on_the_internet" target="_blank" rel="external">Brent</a>. I need to think about this more and worry less about being wrong. I think I stay away from technical stuff for fear of being wrong.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/04/being-wrong/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[App Disillusionment]]></title>
    <link href="http://ignorethecode.net/blog/2014/08/01/app_disillusionment/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/04/app-disillusionment/</id>
    <published>2014-08-05T01:07:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-05T01:07:27.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lukas Mathis:</p>]]><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Commoditizing apps and tightly controlling the market for apps on iPhones benefits Apple, and many of its users, in the short run. But in the long run, an unhealthy software ecosystem can’t be good for Apple, for its users, or for the developers who write apps for Apple’s platforms.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Apple obviously doesn’t <em>need</em> to do anything right now. They’re making a lot of money selling iPhones. But their store is flawed. It inhibits a lot of applications and prevents talented developers from being able to make a living selling apps. It may not be hurting now, but it will at some point. The point is Apple could do more to make building great apps a viable business venture, and doing so would directly benefit Apple.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/08/04/app-disillusionment/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Moment: Tim Ferriss]]></title>
    <link href="http://espn.go.com/espnradio/grantland/player?id=11276177"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/31/the-moment-tim-ferriss/</id>
    <published>2014-07-31T22:58:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T21:33:23.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fantastic interview from Brian Koppelman. I’ve been meaning to read the <a href="http://fourhourworkweek.com" target="_blank" rel="external">4-Hour Workweek</a> for years…</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/31/the-moment-tim-ferriss/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[We Really Can't Have Nice Things]]></title>
    <link href="https://brooksreview.net/2014/07/fuck-2/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/31/we-really-cant-have-nice-things/</id>
    <published>2014-07-31T22:57:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-31T22:57:21.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Seriously, Apple launched the App Store with no mechanism for Trials and Upgrades and we all just though “Meh, that’s fine.” Turns out, we screwed over everything by accepting that.</p>
<p>I love iOS and all these apps, but once we lose the good developers, we’ll lose the good apps. And then we’ll lose the platform.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wrote a bunch of crap about this, but didn’t feel like I had a coherent thought. Thankfully Ben Brooks took care of it for me. I’m not convinced the top lists are a positive or a negative. But these other failures are a huge negative.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/31/we-really-cant-have-nice-things/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Insulated Perspectives]]></title>
    <link href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/24/insulated-perspectives/"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/24/insulated-perspectives/</id>
    <published>2014-07-24T17:04:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-24T17:04:38.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David Smith talked on his podcast today about <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threes!/id779157948?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external">Threes!</a> and 2048. In particular he was talking about an acquaintance playing 2048, and how he perceived this acquaintance’s experience. You’ll have to <a href="http://developingperspective.com/2014/07/24/0/" target="_blank" rel="external">listen</a> to hear the nuances of his point, but essentially his deduction was that 2048 made the acquaintance feel smart and that’s why he valued it versus Threes!.</p>
<p>This really missed the mark for me. I think by design Threes! gives users the exact same feeling. It’s more difficult for sure, but it provides the exact same satisfaction. What you take pride in achieving is really based on what your friends achieve. If he feels smart, it’s because he’s doing better than his average friend. While he might take pride in beating 2048, he would take the same pride in getting the 768 block in Threes! if his friends were struggling to. </p>
<p>This user wasn’t playing 2048 because it made him feel smart and Threes! couldn’t. He was playing because 2048 was free. Free games are easier to pick up. You can try them without risking your money. They copied the simple mechanics that made Threes! enjoyable to play and put them out for free. What this story tells me is that this guy, like a lot of App Store consumers, values his $5 (or whatever Threes! costs nowadays).</p>
<p>David’s larger point was to understand what it is your potential customers value, which I think was good. We know that a lot of customers (nay, users; if they don’t pay they aren’t customers) will deal with a lot of crap from a product if it’s gives them some utility they don’t have to pay for. </p>
<p>Certainly developers should be thinking about how they can generate value for customers. 2048 has done that by providing a ton of eyeballs to the customers who pay for ads. The best products, <em>in my opinion</em>, are the ones that can generate enough value to convince users pay for them. Products like David’s own Feed Wrangler/Pod Wrangler and especially apps with delightful and fun experiences like Threes!. </p>
]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[This is Your Brain on Mobile]]></title>
    <link href="https://medium.com/medium-long/15308056cfae"/>
    <id>http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/24/this-is-your-brain-on-mobile/</id>
    <published>2014-07-24T12:40:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-24T12:40:55.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some great thoughts on the effects of being chained to your mobile device, and what you can do to break free. I’ve been doing some similar things myself, which I’m hoping to write about soon.</p>
]]><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://chrisbrakebill.com/2014/07/24/this-is-your-brain-on-mobile/">♻</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
