<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2014-11-26:/20141126155001988</id><title>Chris Brakebill</title><updated>2015-06-08T12:47:54.345Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><generator version="0.4.0" uri="https://github.com/jebrosen/pub-atom">pub-atom</generator><subtitle type="text">Web and mobile developer. Beer and pizza enthusiast. Sender of Three Things Weekly.</subtitle><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-08:smartphone-subsidies</id><title>Smartphone subsidies are going away</title><updated>2015-06-08T12:47:40.494Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;AT&amp;T CEO Ralph de la Vega:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is one of those options that is going to go away slowly…not because we insist on it but because customers will choose it less often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think this is a fairly long way off. I don’t know many people outside the tech-ish bubble who would even consider it. I support the move, as you know exactly what you’re paying for and when you’re paying for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Dan Moren:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-Mobile’s already made this shift, factoring an installment cost of the phone into its plan price. When you pay off the phone, your plan gets cheaper. So if you decide to stick with your current phone for a while, you save money. Likewise, if you bring your own phone, you don’t pay the higher rate. If you want to switch to another provider, just pay off the cost of the phone, and you’re free to go—no pesky contracts mucking things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T does something similar. I moved Lauren and I both off contract by paying the full price of our phones last year (it’s amazing how stunned the reps at the AT&amp;amp;T store were by this). That move dropped our bill by about $15 per line. Just this month I upgraded us to the 10GB data plan and that upped our discount to $25 per line every month. That clever bit of pricing  makes anyone using more than 3GB heavily motivated to move up to the bigger plans. If you use that much data, you can actually save money by paying full price up front and taking advantage of the bigger discount.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-06-02:steves-last-run</id><title>Steve Prefontaine’s Last Run</title><updated>2015-06-02T19:40:08.901Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great piece on Steve Prefontaine, his running, and the influence he had on amateur and professional sports.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-29:update</id><title>Update</title><updated>2015-05-29T19:54:43.576Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href="/a-change/"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about a revamp to the how my site was deployed. Naturally, I’m a tinkerer, and I couldn’t resist making more changes. &lt;a href="http://www.hexo.io"&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice website scaffolding, but there’s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; to it. If I wanted to get in and mess around I had to do a lot of digging. I wanted to have a better understanding of how things were constructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working for a long while on a node based server/generator called Clive that not only generates a site, but gives you an admin interface for editing and publishing files. It also has the ability to queue up posts for automatic posting and generation. I spent some time away from it, and just don’t love it. It’s another thing that just does too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the past week or so I’ve been all over the internet trying to figure out how I want to build this website in a way that makes it easy for my to share and write the way I want to. I finally settled on what I find to be the simplest process; setting up a Gulp build &amp;amp; deploy system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in the near future I’ll open source it (and Clive for that matter). But for now the basics of my setup are this…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All posts and pages and whatever else I might create are written in markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content is stored in two folders, called &lt;code&gt;published&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;drafts&lt;/code&gt; (mostly for ease in combing through and editing files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actual published state is stored via a boolean value in the front matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a couple of tasks which will sort through the markdown files and move any out of place files into their correct directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site is generated with handlebars templates. It’s not great but in order to keep links to previous posts from breaking I’ve set up redirect pages with meta tags which send you to the proper location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Styles are in a single less file that’s compiled to css during the build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next task is to use &lt;a href="http://www.nodegit.org/"&gt;nodegit&lt;/a&gt; to automate deploying to Github pages. I know, I could write more if I spent less time tinkering, but I want to do some of both. I’m hoping I’ll be happy with this as a long term solution…&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-22:My-Sweet-Setup</id><title>My Sweet Setup</title><updated>2015-05-22T13:43:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The folks over at the Sweet Setup have shared my Mac and iOS setup. It’s amazing how much can change in a short period of time. iPhone home screen already looks pretty different and my desk is now located in Tennessee. Thanks to the Sweet Setup for sharing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-05-07:3-years-of-local-milk</id><title>3+ years of local milk</title><updated>2015-05-07T22:52:30.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beth Kirby’s blog might be my favorite thing on the internet. I think I come for the recipes and photography, but I stay because it’s like sitting down with an intimate friend for coffee by a fireplace. It’s not about perfection, but comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-21:college-stars</id><title>What College Stars Can Learn From NFL Players Ditching Millions to Retire Early</title><updated>2015-04-21T17:17:56.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Adam Kramer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I have preached the same message to successful products of the NFL’s farm system: Leave as quickly as you can if there’s a living to be made or even if you’re on the cusp of making one. Playing football for the price of a degree is not a worthwhile trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much truth in here. I’ve spent too much time thinking oh this or that guy could have improved their draft stock by staying in school. But it’s crap. Many of these guys are tremendously under compensated for their skills and sacrifice. Once your skills are at all desired in the NFL, I say go and finish that degree later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I’m just glad to see that more players are starting to say no to the millions of dollars to focus on life outside of football. Get what you can get. Quit while you’re ahead. Budget wisely. Don’t destroy the rest of your life for a few more years in the spotlight making millions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-20:poor-internet-for-poor-people</id><title>Poor Internet for Poor People</title><updated>2015-04-20T18:19:21.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Mahesh Murthy:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the scheme works. Facebook approaches a telco—in India’s case, Reliance—and offers to pay them the bandwidth costs of serving Facebook site and a small group of other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when the poor, who in theory can’t afford a net connection come to the Facebook Zero service confusingly called Internet.org, they’re made to believe they’re on the internet while in reality they’re only on Facebook and a few hand-picked sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the sites too are picked in secret under some unknown process. For instance, Facebook chose to offer the distant-second search engine Bing instead of industry-leading Google. Why? Is it rivalry with Google? Or because of Microsoft’s stake in Facebook? And then Facebook’s Zero product features a tiny job site like Babajob instead of the industry-leading Naukri. Why? So that the poor have fewer job options? No one knows. Facebook doesn’t feature YouTube—the largest video site in the world and an immense education resource —but allows its own videos in full. It doesn’t really look like charity any more, does it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While zero services are a more extreme case and don’t fit what you will see in the U.S., they are helpful in illustrating how the seemingly good idea of certain companies’ products not counting towards your data caps is actually bad for the internet. You’re no longer choosing between product X and product Y. It’s now product X, which won’t count towards you cap, and product Y, which may be a superior product but can’t afford to pay off your internet provider. Your cell phone company or ISP shouldn’t get to make this decision. They should simply give you uniform access to sites on the internet and charge you according to that usage, no matter where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-15:life-sans-iphone</id><title>Life sans iPhone</title><updated>2015-04-15T11:15:26.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t know, I’d been looking to trade my iPhone 6+ in for an iPhone 6. I was recently able to sell my 6+ on Glyde. Since my last sale fell through, I decided to wait this time until I had the money before buying a new phone. Some crazy slow shipping times, combined with a seller who didn’t seem to want to part with their iPhone 6 left me without a smartphone for about 3 weeks. I feel like the experience of having a phone which was only for calling has been really informative of my habits. (Okay it could text, but have you tried texting without a full keyboard? It’s horrific).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/oldPhone.jpg" alt="My awesome Alcatel temp phone"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became apparent very quickly how habitual looking at my phone was. I would frequently look at my little candy bar for no reason at all. I needed a fix of stimulation that whatever situation I was currently in just couldn’t give me. Or so it seemed. As time went by, I found myself leaving my phone behind even as I went out to do things. I missed the occasional text or call, but for the most part being disconnected was a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I find interesting now is looking at my apps and thinking about how many of them I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; on my phone. I’m pretty sure I can count on one hand the number of times I really needed an iPhone app for something. (One of those times was when I had to print out Google Maps directions and got lost. It felt like 2002 all over again). Most of the time I looked at my phone out of boredom or being stuck in unpleasant social situations (or both).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most revealing thing has been the past 48 hours of having an iPhone back in my life. I’d been anticipating getting it back for weeks. I think somewhere deep down I thought getting one back would make life so much easier or more pleasant or at least I’ll know the scores of every current SPORTING EVENT. But I’ve become a lot more conscious of my motivations every time I take a peek at it. And I’m finding myself putting it away because I really have nothing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is this experience going to change my life? Probably not. But at the very least it’s got me being a little bit more intentional about how I use my phone. I’m going to pare down the number of apps I keep on it and try to not feel like I need it everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-13:decorating-with-postit-notes</id><title>Decorating with Post-It Notes</title><updated>2015-04-13T17:07:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I just got so tired of how sterile and boring our office felt, I thought I should do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic way to bring life to a space affordably and ephemerally.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-09:outshape</id><title>Outshape</title><updated>2015-04-09T21:29:17.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know, I’ve been spending most of my time since I left ESPN working on a game called &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape"&gt;Outshape&lt;/a&gt;. I’m getting super close to being ready to submit to the App Store. I’m just trying to iterate the design and interaction to as close to perfection as I can get it, while I smooth out some functional edges. It’s the most fun I’ve had in years. And I’m delighted to be able to work hard without having to work all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started a &lt;a href="http://onehundredten.co/outshape/blog"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; where I’m going to document the development process of Outshape. From the inspiration, to early mocks, to the stresses of sharing a thing I’m making with the world. I’m sure some of that will come over here, but I’m going to post anything Outshape specific over there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go sign up for the email list if you want to get the details on how Outshape came to be!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-08:introvert</id><title>Introvert</title><updated>2015-04-08T19:28:12.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Iain Simpson:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts are my thoughts. I share what I choose to, and the rest is mine. Don&amp;#39;t quiz me, demand to know what I&amp;#39;m thinking, tell me I&amp;#39;m meant to share. I have a right to privacy. Don&amp;#39;t assume that because you want to share everything with me, that I should want to share everything with you. Don&amp;#39;t present your view of the world as the only possible option, and that I must be somehow emotionally stunted, wrong, or hiding something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I haven&amp;#39;t told you how I feel about something, it&amp;#39;s probably because I haven&amp;#39;t decided how I feel about it. I can&amp;#39;t make decisions without all the information, and I don&amp;#39;t offer solutions without understanding the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get into the mind of an introvert, this short piece will get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-07:iphone-sixes</id><title>iPhone Sixes</title><updated>2015-04-07T16:06:37.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting to read &lt;a href="http://www.512pixels.net/blog/2015/4/well-i-switched-to-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Stephen Hackett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/2015/04/06/life-with-the-iphone-6-plus"&gt;Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/04/two-weeks-with-the-iphone-6-plus/"&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; talk about their experiences as regular iPhone 6 users who are experimenting with or switching to the iPhone 6 Plus. Particularly since I’ve been a 6 Plus user who is switching to the regular ol’ iPhone 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to comment on their opinions much, since I don’t have my iPhone 6 yet and I don’t yet know how it works for me. My reason for switching boils down mostly to the fact that the 6 Plus is just too big. I may find that the 6 is too big in day to day usage as well. But I’m most worried about the drop in battery life. I got used to almost never having to think about the battery on my 6 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will definitely follow up with my experiences with the iPhone 6 when I receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-06:introverts-as-leaders</id><title>Introverts as Leaders</title><updated>2015-04-06T15:20:48.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;rands:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introverts are professional listeners. Their natural state is to observe and gather data from the world around them as opposed to their extroverts counterparts who enjoying spending their time talking about the state of the world and all the fascinating data in the world… endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All to often, society says that introversion is bad and extroversion is the “proper” or “successful” way to be. This seems to be a more common thought when it comes to leadership. Rands points out that introverts have some pretty huge natural advantages when it comes to good leadership, just as extroverts do. Both most overcome their own weaknesses to make use of their strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-03:pixar</id><title>Pixar</title><updated>2015-04-03T14:25:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the process of job hunting for life after ESPN, I managed to land some early interviews with Pixar. While technically it would still be under the umbrella of the same company (Disney), Pixar is sort of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company for me. I love everything they do and want badly to be a part of creating beautifully told stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as we were going through that process my wife and I struggled with the fact that going to Pixar meant moving to California. We’ve been planning on moving to Knoxville for quite a while, and we just weren’t sure San Francisco is where we wanted to live. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then things changed. We found out we were going to have our first child. I still badly wanted the job with Pixar, but the decision was no longer a struggle. We want to raise children surrounded by family and friends. We weren’t going to move to San Francisco. It hurt badly and it was one of the hardest things I’ve ever had to do, but I had to tell them I wouldn’t be going any further in the interview process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had friends say I should have kept going through the process, but that just felt wrong to me. Yes it’s good experience, but in my option it’s selfish to waste the time of hard working people when I know I’m not going to take a job offer. I think it would have shown a lack of respect for the people I was interviewing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d be lying if I said I didn’t think about it every day and feel a little sad, but I think a lot more every day about that baby and how excited I am to raise him or her around my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-02:how-to-take-a-day-off</id><title>How to take a day off</title><updated>2015-04-02T15:25:32.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;David Cain:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between that day and a normal weekend day, I realize now, was that I paid little attention to the advance of time. I suspended all aspirations to shaping the future. The only goal was to enjoy the setting and characters of every moment I found myself in, which is refreshingly easy when you’re not trying to get anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is so incredibly true for me. So often I’m busying my self with the advance of time. Always thinking about how I could be using the upcoming time productively. Or getting frustrated because the time has flown by and I haven’t used it “well”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cain provides some great tips on how to take a proper day off. Working some of these into my life will help make me leisure time more enjoyable, and I’m betting will make me a little more fun to be around.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-04-01:pregnant</id><title>Munchkin</title><updated>2015-04-01T14:53:39.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year, when Lauren and I found out we were pregnant I was like 75% scared and 25% excited. We had no plans to have a baby yet. But there we were, expecting one. I’m not sure it’s something you’re ever &lt;em&gt;ready&lt;/em&gt; for. But it’s best to at least be planning for it a little bit. (Apparently I married into a fertile family)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we lost the baby, it was so early in the pregnancy I had a hard time connecting with it. We we’re scared/excited for a couple of weeks. Then just scared shitless for one more. And then just immensely sad. But through all of that, it was hard to feel it was connected to a child. It was more like this roller coaster of expectation changing that Lauren and I went on. One of the most brutal parts about it, was how it affected us differently. How we could be so far apart on the sad to happy spectrum on an hourly basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we were more ready. Not like &lt;em&gt;planning&lt;/em&gt; ready. But it was at least something we had talked about. I think we’d hoped to get settled into Knoxville before Munchkin (that’s what I’m calling him/her) came along, but it wasn’t devastating to have to adjust to new expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here we are, less than six months from bringing a human life into the world. Our future nursery is currently the cats’ bedroom, which basically means a room full of unpacked boxes. I’m unemployed and Lauren is just getting started acquiring clients (If you’re in Knoxville and looking for a counselor or someone to talk to, I &lt;strong&gt;highly&lt;/strong&gt; recommend &lt;a href="http://www.ebenezercounseling.com/Brakebill.html"&gt;her&lt;/a&gt;). And we don’t even have a dog yet. I thought for sure we’d have to get a dog before we could have a baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite all those concerns, I can’t help but feel like we’re way more ready for this than we were a year ago. I’m confident that God will provide the right opportunities for us to support this child. I’m trying hard to not be closed off to the job opportunities my family brings me. And speaking of my family, the idea of raising a child is made a million times easier knowing the support we have here in Knoxville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m saying is my excited to scared ratio is much more balanced this time. So that’s good right?&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-03-31:tennessee-hires-rick-barnes</id><title>Tennessee Hires Rick Barnes</title><updated>2015-03-31T13:33:45.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Chris Dortch:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do if you’re Tennessee athletic director Dave Hart and a coach who has won 70 percent of his career games, has made more NCAA Tournament appearances (22) than the Vols have made in their history (20) and has won everywhere he’s been (George Mason, Providence, Clemson, Texas) drops into your lap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You hire him, that’s what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love Bruce Pearl, but it’s pretty clear that Rick Barnes has had a much better career. How can you argue with a coach who has more NCAA Tournament appearances than your entire program?&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-03-30:no-dickheads</id><title>No Dickheads!</title><updated>2015-03-30T13:13:49.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Rhys Newman:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe there is a straight line between how the studio feels, how we as designers treat each other, and the innovative impact of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some really great nuggets in here for creating an effective creative workplace. No dickheads is obvious. But many of their guidelines are under appreciated in today’s workplace. Eating and cooking together, reading fiction, sharing your family with your coworkers and your coworkers with your family. These things can turn where you work into more than just that place you go to earn your living. They cultivate a place where you experience joy and growth. Where your work feeds your soul and your soul feeds your work. And that’s how you get shit done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-03-23:Two-Years-of-Marriage</id><title>Two Years of Marriage</title><updated>2015-03-23T09:30:25.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/122937125" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot I could say, but I think this video says it well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>tag:chrisbrakebill.com,2015-03-19:Decisions,-Decisions</id><title>Decisions, Decisions</title><updated>2015-03-19T22:33:24.000Z</updated><author><name>Chris Brakebill</name><email>chris@brakebill.me</email></author><content type="html">&lt;p class="link_author"&gt;Anne Gibson:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are our first users — we’re using the workflows and environment that we set up for ourselves to make good decisions on behalf of ourselves, our families, our clients, and our users. We know the consequences of decision fatigue and poor choices better than most. We’re never going to eliminate decision fatigue from our own lives, or from anyone else’s, but by changing our own habits and lessening our own decision fatigue, we can make better choices more consistently throughout the day, which leads to a better experience for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about decision fatigue lately and how it might affect me. I’m trying to get to the more important things as early in the day as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>